<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<weapons>
    <cestus>
        <id>cestus</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Cestus</en>
            <es>Cestus</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These metal knuckle covers give the wearer an edge in fist fights. Most are simple lumps of metal worn
                over the knuckles, but some are ornate designs with hooks, poison jets, and spikes. The spiked ones are
                especially popular among Bannockburn’s professional pugilists. The cestus adds to a characters unarmed
                damage.
            </en>
            <es>Estos nudillos de metal conceden a su portador una ventaja en las peleas a puñetazos. La mayoría de los
                Cestus son simples trozos de metal que se colocan en los nudillos, pero algunos Cestus son diseños
                adornados con ganchos, inyectores de veneno, y pinchos. Los Cestus con pinchos son especialmente
                populares entre los pugilistas profesionales de Bannockburn
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>1</cost>
    </cestus>
    <curvedSword>
        <id>curvedSword</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Curved Sword</en>
            <es>Espada Curva</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A curved sword with either one edge or two, and lighter than a war sword. This could be a scimitar or a
                pirate cutlass. Scimitars are popular among the Kurgan barbarians. These are hacking weapons.
            </en>
            <es>Una espada curva con un filo o dos, y más ligera que una espada de guerra. Esta podría ser una cimitarra
                o un machete pirata. Las cimitarras son populares entre los bárbaros Kurgan. Estas son armas perfectas
                para la piratería.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
    </curvedSword>
    <flail>
        <id>flail</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Flail</en>
            <es>Mayal</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Two long sticks connected by a chain. This could be the standard medieval weapon or the more modern
                nunchaku. Metal flails and morning stars are the business versions of this weapon (DMG 5 for TL2+).
            </en>
            <es>Dos palos largos unidos por una cadena. Esta podría ser el arma medieval estándar o el nunchaku moderno.
                Los Mayales con cuchillas metálicas y las Estrellas de la Mañana son las versiones comerciales de este
                arma (Daño 5 en un NT2+).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>4</cost>
    </flail>
    <pick>
        <id>pick</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Pick</en>
            <es>Pico</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A pickaxe or a spiked club, these are devastating weapons. The weapon’s great momentum and impaling
                spike give it the Hard property for the purpose of armor protection. Picks are unwieldy, however, and
                the wielder receives a –2 goal penalty when used for parrying.
            </en>
            <es>Es una piqueta o una porra con un pincho, estas son armas devastadoras. Un amplio movimiento del arma
                con el fin de ensartar al objetivo concederá al arma la propiedad de Duro a efectos de obviar la
                protección de armadura. Sin embargo los picos son difíciles de manejar y el portador recibe un
                penalizador de -2 al rango de acierto cuando use el arma para bloquear un ataque.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>7</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>5</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
    </pick>
    <saber>
        <id>saber</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Saber</en>
            <es>Sable</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These curved one-handed swords of high precision and quality are very sharp and are made for cutting and
                slicing, instead of hacking. They are of higher quality than common blades, being stronger, sharper,
                more flexible, and better balanced, and also quite expensive. Lightweight and strong, this category
                includes cavalry sabers and the Samurai katana
            </en>
            <es>Estas espadas curvas de una mano de alta precisión y calidad son muy afiladas y se fabrican para cortar
                con precisión, y no para la piratería. Son de mayor calidad que las hojas comunes, siendo más fuertes,
                más afiladas, más flexibles y mejor equilibradas, aunque también bastante más caras. Ligera y fuerte,
                esta categoría incluye sables de caballería y la Katana samurái.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>3</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
    </saber>
    <splinterSword>
        <id>splinterSword</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Splinter Sword</en>
            <es>Espada de Esquirlas</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>This plastic sword shatters on impact, leaving tiny, sharp, and fibrous threads in the victim’s body
                that continue to cut and slice until surgically removed. After the sword has struck, the victim will
                suffer DMG 1 at the beginning of each successive turn moving, or per hour if remaining absolutely still,
                until the threads are removed. This requires a number of VP on a sustained Dexterity + Physick equal to
                the total damage caused by the splinter sword. The problem with splinter swords is that they are
                disposable, breaking apart with each hit (including parrying). A sword can only deliver three hits
                before it is broken beyond use. These weapons were factory manufactured during the Second Republic for
                cheap mass-shipboard defense, and they are no longer produced in the Known Worlds, though they are often
                recovered from Second Republic weapons caches.
            </en>
            <es>Esta espada de plástico se rompe con un solo impacto, soltando pequeñas y afiladas fibras de hilo que se
                adhieren al cuerpo de la víctima y siguen cortando y sajando hasta que se extirpan quirúrgicamente.
                Después de que la espada haya golpeado, la víctima sufrirá Daño 1 al comienzo de cada turno, o por hora,
                si se queda absolutamente quieto, hasta que se eliminen los hilillos. Esto requiere una serie de PV en
                una tirada prolongada de Destreza + Conocimiento del Cuerpo igual al Daño total causado por la Espada de
                Esquirlas. El problema con las Espadas de Esquirlas es que son desechables, porque se rompen con cada
                golpe (incluso al bloquear un ataque). Estas armas se fabricaban masivamente durante la Segunda
                República, con el fin de producir baratas armas de defensa que pudieran ser utilizadas abordo de las
                naves espaciales, pero ya no se siguen produciendo en los Mundos Conocidos, aunque a menudo se suelen
                recuperar muchos ejemplares de los depósitos de armas de la Segunda República.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>50</cost>
        <damage>bleed</damage>
    </splinterSword>
    <staff>
        <id>staff</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Staff</en>
            <es>Báculo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>The ol’ standby for merry men everywhere (DMG 3 for TL1), this could be Little John’s quarterstaff, a
                Japanese monk’s bo staff, or just about any long stick (a short stick is considered a club).
            </en>
            <es>El apoyo físico para hombres de todas partes (Daño 3 en un NT1), este podría ser el bastón de Little
                John, el bastón bo de un monje japonés, o prácticamente cualquier palo que sea largo (un palo corto se
                considera una porra).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>1</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>0.5</cost>
    </staff>
    <suresnakeWhip>
        <id>suresnakeWhip</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Suresnake Whip</en>
            <es>Látigo Serpiente</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>This can be any type of whip, with a special tracking wire threaded throughout its length. The tip of
                the lash holds a nanite think machine that can home in on a chosen target. The tip must first be aimed
                at the target, then "locked down" on that target with a flick of a switch in the handle (to achieve
                this, one VP must be delegated to the tracking rather than to damage effect dice). As long as the target
                does not disappear from the computer’s sight for more than three turns, the attacker gains a +2 goal
                bonus to hit his chosen target. These whips are popular among the Chainers, who use them to keep
                "special" cargo in line.
            </en>
            <es>Este puede ser cualquier tipo de látigo, con un cable enroscado a lo largo de su superficie que le
                permite fijar a un objetivo. La punta del látigo tiene una nanomáquina pensante que puede fijar a un
                objetivo seleccionado. En primer lugar la punta debe señalar en la misma dirección del objetivo, a
                continuación, debe fijar a ese objetivo pulsando un botón en el mango (para conseguirlo, debe invertirse
                un PV para fijar el objetivo en lugar de conseguir un dado de efecto de Daño). Mientras que el objetivo
                no desaparezca de la vista del ordenador durante más de tres turnos, el atacante recibe un bonificador
                de +2 al rango de acierto para golpear a su objetivo seleccionado. Estos látigos son populares entre los
                Esclavistas, que los utilizan para mantener al cargamento "especial" formando una fila.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0/+3</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>100</cost>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>0.01</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedFactions>muster</recommendedFactions>
        </random>
    </suresnakeWhip>
    <twoHandedAxe>
        <id>twoHandedAxe</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Two-Handed Axe</en>
            <es>Hacha a Dos Manos</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A huge battle axe, heavy to lift and unpleasant to suffer (DMG 8 for TL2+). This heavy hacking weapon
                could be any smashhead axe, including heavy woodchoppers and halberds. Very intimidating to face,
                two-handed axes rely on brute force and centrifugal momentum to smash through armor and energy shields.
                The drawback is that these heavy weapons are unwieldy and slow to use, making getting out of the axe’s
                way easier (opponent Dodge goal +2), although parrying these massive weapons is tricky (opponent
                parrying goal –2).
            </en>
            <es>Una enorme hacha de batalla, (Daño 8 en un NT2+). Este arma pesada de piratería podría ser cualquier
                hacha aplasta cabezas, incluyendo las hachas pesadas de los leñadores y las alabardas. Son muy
                intimidantes cuando las tienes delante: las hachas a dos manos se basan en el uso de la fuerza bruta y
                en el impulso que concede la propia inercia para aplastar cualquier cosa, pudiendo atravesar armaduras y
                escudos de energía. El inconveniente es que estas armas pesadas son difíciles de manejar y lentas de
                usar, por lo que es relativamente fácil apartarse de la trayectoria del hacha (el oponente recibe un +2
                al rango de acierto de Esquivar), aunque bloquear un ataque de estas armas tan grandes es complicado (el
                oponente recibe un -2 al rango de acierto al bloquear).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>30</cost>
        <random>
            <recommendedFactions>vuldrok</recommendedFactions>
        </random>
    </twoHandedAxe>
    <twoHandedSword>
        <id>twoHandedSword</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Two-Handed Sword</en>
            <es>Espada a Dos Manos</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>The biggest, baddest sword around (DMG 8 for TL2+), though they require a lot of room to swing with full
                force. This mammoth sword could be any huge blade, but is mainly modeled after the Scottish claymore.
                Two-handed swords are popular among those who do not have the finesse to slide a blade through an energy
                shield’s impact threshold, but who might deliver enough damage to exceed its protection threshold. These
                are primarily hacking weapons.
            </en>
            <es>La espada más letal y más grande (Daño 8 en un NT2+), a pesar de que requieren de una gran cantidad de
                espacio para que el portador pueda matar empleando toda su fuerza. Esta espada descomunal podría ser
                cualquier espada enorme, pero su diseño se basa, sobre todo, en la claymore escocesa. Las Espadas de Dos
                manos son populares entre aquellos que no poseen la delicadeza necesaria para introducir una hoja a
                través del umbral de impacto de un escudo de energía, pero que puede infligir una cantidad de Daño
                suficiente para superar este umbral de protección. Estas armas son principalmente diseñadas para la
                piratería.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>40</cost>
        <random>
            <recommendedFactions>vuldrok</recommendedFactions>
        </random>
    </twoHandedSword>
    <warSword>
        <id>warSword</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>War Sword</en>
            <es>Espada de Guerra</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A heavy sword favored by certain soldiers. This could be a Viking broadsword, a Norman conqueror’s
                sword, or just about any broad, straight sword from history. Advances in steel forging allow for the
                construction of weapons that hold a better edge (DMG 6 for TL2+). These are hacking weapons, and can
                have one or two edges.
            </en>
            <es>Una espada pesada preferida por algunos soldados. Esta podría ser una espada ancha vikinga, una espada
                de conquistadores normandos o casi cualquier espada ancha y recta de toda la historia. Los avances en la
                forja del acero permiten la construcción de armas que tienen un mejor filo (Daño 6 para NT2+). Son armas
                para ataques de corte y pueden tener uno o dos filos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
        <random>
            <recommendedFactions>military</recommendedFactions>
        </random>
    </warSword>
    <whip>
        <id>whip</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Whip</en>
            <es>Látigo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Whips come in all shapes and sizes, from bullwhips to slaver whips to cat-tail whips (DMG 3). Some whips
                are given barbs or hooks for added effect (DMG 4; Cost: +1). High-tech synthetic whips are known at Tech
                Level 6+, and these usually have a base of 4 dice of damage and only require STR 3 to wield.
            </en>
            <es>Los látigos tienen todo tipo de formas y tamaños, desde látigos de una cola hasta látigos de esclavos o
                de múltiples colas (Daño 3). Algunos látigos tienen pinchos o ganchos para aumentar el efecto (Daño 4;
                Coste: +1). Los látigos sintéticos de alta tecnología están disponibles con Nivel de Tecnología 6+;
                estos látigos normalmente tienen una base de cuatro dados de daño y solo requieren 4 de Fuerza para
                empuñarlos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>MELEE</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>–1</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>5</cost>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>0.1</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedFactions>muster</recommendedFactions>
        </random>
    </whip>
    <dart>
        <id>dart</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Dart</en>
            <es>Dardo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A pointed needle with small guiding wings designed for accuracy in throwing (un-winged darts have their
                RNG halved). These are not the common variety darts found in bars, but are larger and more deadly
                versions of the same.
            </en>
            <es>Una aguja en punta con pequeñas alas que le sirven como guía diseñadas para la precisión a la hora de
                lanzar los propios dardos (el alcance de los dardos sin alas se reduce a la mitad). Esta no es la
                variedad común de dardos que se pueden encontrar en los bares, sino que son versiones más grandes y más
                mortales.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>+1</goal>
                <damage>1</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Unfletched</en>
                    <es>Sin alas</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>1</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>3/5</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>2</cost>
    </dart>
    <javelin>
        <id>javelin</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Javelin</en>
            <es>Jabalina</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A thin thrown spear that may include a Roman Verutum, Anglo-Saxon Angon, a Zulu Assegai or even a
                harpoon (DMG 4 for TL1+). Although made for short-range attacks, hunting, or to soften up an enemy
                before melee, most javelins can also be used as stabbing spears in close combat.
            </en>
            <es>Una lanza arrojadiza delgada como puede ser una verutum romana, la Angon anglosajona, la Azagaya zulú o
                incluso un arpón (Daño 4 en un NT1+). Aunque está pensada para los ataques de corto alcance, para cazar,
                o para ablandar a un enemigo antes del cuerpo a cuerpo, la mayoría de las jabalinas también se pueden
                utilizar como lanzas en combate de cortas distancias.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>1</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>2</cost>
    </javelin>
    <rock>
        <id>rock</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Rock</en>
            <es>Piedra</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A good fist-sized rock can be hurled as a deadly weapon at an opponent. The rock’s DMG varies depending
                on size and mass.
            </en>
            <es>una buena piedra del tamaño de un puño puede lanzarse como un arma mortal a un adversario. El Daño de la
                piedra varía en función del tamaño y masa.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Light</en>
                    <es>Ligera</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>1</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageSize>XS</damageSize>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Medium</en>
                    <es>Media</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageSize>S</damageSize>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Heavy</en>
                    <es>Pesada</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageSize>M</damageSize>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Large</en>
                    <es>Grande</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>3/5</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <damageSize>L</damageSize>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Huge</en>
                    <es>Enorme</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>5</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <damageSize>XL</damageSize>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>0</cost>
    </rock>
    <star>
        <id>star</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Star</en>
            <es>Estrella</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A small disk with serrated edges designed to be thrown quickly at targets (DMG 2 for TL2+). This can
                include any variety of shuriken ("throwing stars").
            </en>
            <es>Un pequeño disco con filos dentados diseñado para lanzarse con rapidez a los objetivos (Daño 2 en un
                NT2+). Esta estrella puede incluir cualquier variedad de shuriken (estrellas ninja).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>1</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>2</cost>
    </star>
    <throwingAxe>
        <id>throwingAxe</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Throwing Axe</en>
            <es>Hacha Arrojadiza</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A sleek hand axe balanced for use as a thrown missile weapon, hopefully hitting the target with the
                blade rather than the handle (DMG 3 for TL2+). They can also act as a small axe in melee.
            </en>
            <es>Un hacha de mano elegante a la par que equilibrada, que sirve para usarse como arma arrojadiza, para
                golpear, si hay suerte, al objetivo con la hoja en vez de la empuñadura (Daño 3 En un NT2+). También
                pueden usarse como un pequeño hacha en combates cuerpo a cuerpo.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>5</cost>
    </throwingAxe>
    <throwingKnife>
        <id>throwingKnife</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Throwing Knife</en>
            <es>Cuchillo Arrojadizo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Throwing knives are not like normal kitchen implements; they are usually specially balanced to fly
                through the air and to hit a target with the blade rather than the pommel (DMG 2 for TL2+). They can
                also act as small knives in melee if required.
            </en>
            <es>Los cuchillos arrojadizos no son utensilios de cocina estándar; por lo general son especialmente
                equilibrados para que puedan volar y golpear a un objetivo con la hoja en vez de la empuñadura (Daño 2
                en un NT2+). También pueden usarse como pequeños cuchillos de combate cuerpo a cuerpo si es necesario.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <weaponType>THROWING</weaponType>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <damageTechLevel>2</damageTechLevel>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>3</cost>
    </throwingKnife>
    <heavyFuthangaBow>
        <id>heavyFuthangaBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Heavy Futhanga Bow</en>
            <es>Arco Pesado Futhanga</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 75 kg pull version of the light Futhanga bow (see below), built for warfare and macho prowess.</en>
            <es>Una versión de 75kg de tensión del arco ligero Futhanga (ver más abajo), construido para la guerra y
                para los Vorox más fuertes
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>10</damage>
                <strength>7</strength>
                <range>40/65</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1/2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound Bow</en>
                    <es>Arco Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>10</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>40/65</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1/2</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>30</cost>
        <random>
            <restrictedFactions>vorox</restrictedFactions>
        </random>
    </heavyFuthangaBow>
    <huntingBow>
        <id>huntingBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Hunting Bow</en>
            <es>Arco de Caza</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 30 kg pull bow designed to be drawn and fired quickly (as a deer bolts from the woods or a bird takes
                flight). It is smaller than other bows since it must be carried through thick underbrush. The rarer
                recurve bows have the same traits as a hunting bow, but are designed to be fired from beastback.
            </en>
            <es>Un arco de 30kg de tensión diseñado para hacer disparos rápidos (mientras un ciervo huye del bosque o un
                pájaro emprende el vuelo). Es más pequeño que otros arcos, ya que se debe cargar con él a través de la
                maleza espesa. Los arcos recurvos más raros cuentan con las mismas características que las de un arco de
                caza, pero están diseñados para ser disparados desde una montura.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
                <range>20/30</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>3</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound</en>
                    <es>Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>20/30</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>5</cost>
    </huntingBow>
    <lightFuthangaBow>
        <id>lightFuthangaBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Light Futhanga Bow</en>
            <es>Arco Ligero Futhanga</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 60 kg pull Vorox bow designed to be operated with three limbs, two to hold the bow shaft and one to
                draw the string. Futhanga often have two strings running parallel to one another, each of which can be
                nocked and drawn at the same time, increasing its rate of fire, but requiring all four Vorox limbs to
                use.
            </en>
            <es>Un arco Vorox de 60kg de tensión diseñado para ser utilizado con tres extremidades, dos para sujetar el
                mango del arco y uno para tensar la cuerda. El Futhanga a menudo cuenta con dos cuerdas en paralelo la
                una a la otra, cada una de las cuales pueden colocarse en línea con respecto a la flecha y tensarse a la
                vez, incrementando su ratio de disparo, pero para usar esta característica se precisan las cuatro
                extremidades del Vorox.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>40/60</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1/2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound</en>
                    <es>Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>40/60</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1/2</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
        <random>
            <restrictedFactions>vorox</restrictedFactions>
        </random>
    </lightFuthangaBow>
    <selfBow>
        <id>selfBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Self Bow</en>
            <es>Arco Sencillo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 15 kg pull bow used in primitive societies as both a hunting and battle bow. It is constructed from a
                single piece of wood strung with gut
            </en>
            <es>Un arco de 15kg de tensión utilizado en sociedades primitivas tanto para la caza como para la guerra. Se
                construye a partir de una sola pieza de madera tensada con intestinos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>0</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>3</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound</en>
                    <es>Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>3</cost>
    </selfBow>
    <targetBow>
        <id>targetBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Target Bow</en>
            <es>Arco de Feria</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 22.5 kg pull bow designed for target shooting at tourneys or carnivals rather than for killing. It is
                larger than a hunting bow but not as large as a military bow. The balance gives a +1 bonus to the
                archer’s Shoot goal rolls.
            </en>
            <es>Un arco de 22,5kg de tensión diseñado para apuntar a un objetivo y dispararle en torneos y carnavales y
                no para el asesinato. Es más grande que un arco de caza, pero no tan grande como un arco militar. El
                balance le concede un bonificador de +1 al rango de acierto de las tiradas de Disparar del arquero.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>30/40</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound</en>
                    <es>Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>30/40</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>7</cost>
    </targetBow>
    <warBow>
        <id>warBow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>War Bow</en>
            <es>Arco de Guerra</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 45 kg pull bow designed for warfare, to fling arrows over long distances -usually over battlements or
                onto armies across the field. It is as tall as, or taller than, most people. This is based off the
                English longbow but could just as easily be a Japanese yumi bow.
            </en>
            <es>Un arco de 45kg de tensión diseñado para la guerra, para lanzar flechas a largas distancias, por lo
                general a las almenas o sobre los ejércitos que inundan todo el campo de batalla. Es igual (o más) alto
                que la mayoría de la gente. Esta referencia se basa en el arco largo Inglés, pero fácilmente podría ser
                también el arco japonés yumi.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>1</techLevel>
        <type>BOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
                <range>40/60</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Compound</en>
                    <es>Compuesto</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
                <range>40/60</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>10</cost>
    </warBow>
    <handCrossbow>
        <id>handCrossbow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Hand Crossbow</en>
            <es>Ballesta de Mano</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A small, handheld 15 kg pull crossbow. The bolts are smaller than usual and so must be specially
                manufactured.
            </en>
            <es>Una ballesta de mano pequeña de 15kg de tensión. Los pernos son más pequeños de lo normal de modo que
                deben fabricarse especialmente para estas ballestas.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>CROSSBOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>7</cost>
    </handCrossbow>
    <lightCrossbow>
        <id>lightCrossbow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Light Crossbow</en>
            <es>Ballesta Ligera</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 30 kg pull crossbow used for hunting in many rural areas.</en>
            <es>Una ballesta de 30kg de tensión utilizada para cazar en muchas zonas rurales.</es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>CROSSBOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>6</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </lightCrossbow>
    <heavyCrossbow>
        <id>heavyCrossbow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Heavy Crossbow</en>
            <es>Ballesta Pesada</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 60 kg pull crossbow used for warfare. This monster can pound through shields, but usually takes longer
                to reload than lighter crossbows.
            </en>
            <es>Una ballesta de 60kg de tensión utilizada para la guerra. Este monstruo puede golpear a través de los
                escudos, pero por lo general requiere de un tiempo mayor para recargar que el de las ballestas ligeras.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>CROSSBOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8</damage>
                <strength>8</strength>
                <range>30/40</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>15</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </heavyCrossbow>
    <mediumCrossbow>
        <id>mediumCrossbow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Medium Crossbow</en>
            <es>Ballesta Mediana</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 45 kg pull crossbow that is the standard for most low-tech, but important, guardsmen.</en>
            <es>Una ballesta de 45kg de tensión que es el estándar para la mayoría de los guardias y en entornos con
                bajos niveles de tecnología.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>CROSSBOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>6</strength>
                <range>20/30</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>10</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </mediumCrossbow>
    <wristCrossbow>
        <id>wristCrossbow</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Wrist Crossbow</en>
            <es>Ballesta de Muñeca</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A 7.5 kg pull mini-crossbow, often strapped to the wrist and fired with a flick of the wrist or by
                pulling a thread-trigger (just don’t scratch your nose the wrong way!). This is an easily-concealable
                weapon. The bolts are smaller than usual and so must be specially manufactured (but cost the same).
            </en>
            <es>Una mini-ballesta de 7,5kg de tensión. Generalmente se ata a la muñeca y se dispara con un movimiento de
                muñeca o tirando de un hilo que acciona el gatillo fácilmente (¡no te rasques la nariz con la mano que
                no es!). Esta es un arma que puede esconderse con facilidad. Los pernos son más pequeños de lo normal
                por lo que deben fabricarse especialmente para ellas (pero cuestan lo mismo).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>CROSSBOW</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>archery</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>1</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>2/5</range>
                <shots>Quiver</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>15</cost>
    </wristCrossbow>
    <typicalCaselessRifle>
        <id>typicalCaselessRifle</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Typical Caseless Rifle</en>
            <es>Rifle sin Casquillos Típico</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rifles manufactured to use caseless ammunition (there are very few handguns employing this technology),
                work much the same way as ordinary automatic assault rifles, the technological advance lying primarily
                with the ammunition. Caseless ammunition eliminates the need of a cartridge, containing the primer,
                propellant and bullet as a single unit projectile. The benefit of this is a simpler automatic firing
                mechanism with less chance of failure, as well as smaller and lighter bullets. This allows for larger
                magazine capacity as well as more cost efficient ammunition. Perhaps more important still, the shorter
                bullets mean the autofeed mechanism "travels" a shorter distance to open the chamber for a new bullet,
                which again translatesto a significantly higher rate of fire for caseless ammunition rifles, as well as
                a greater chance of early bullets hitting the target before recoil moves the gun off target. Common
                problems with caseless ammo, which stalled early TL4 attempts at manufacturing these guns, are the
                heat-sensitive ammunition (which tends to self-ignite in hot barrels), sealing the back of the barrel
                with gases produced by the propellant explosion (which in cartridge guns is prevented by the cartridge
                staying behind in the barrel) and finally the fragility of the ammunition not protected by a metal case.
                These weapons were very popular during the Second Republic and were manufactured in large numbers; both
                the Leyland Caseless and the Gleelan MR-C can still be found throughout the Known Worlds. The Karr &amp;
                Meizner Guild on Tethys is currently the only large-scale manufacturer of caseless ammunition rifles in
                the Known Worlds. Their K&amp;M MR12 series, which was launched late in the Emperor Wars, is the only
                model
                series currently produced. The new K&amp;M MR12 version 3 was released in 5002 in an attempt to
                re-launch
                the gun with a superior (but less-profitable) design.
            </en>
            <es>Son rifles fabricados para usar municiones sin casquillo (existen muy pocos revólveres que usen esta
                tecnología), funciona prácticamente igual que la mayoría de los rifles de asalto automáticos comunes, el
                avance tecnológico realmente tiene que ver con la munición. La munición sin casquillos elimina la
                necesidad de un cartucho, que contiene la pólvora, el propelente y la bala como un único proyectil. Lo
                que se consigue con este sistema es un mecanismo de disparo automático más simple y con menos
                posibilidades de fracaso, así como balas más pequeñas y ligeras. Esto permite ampliar la capacidad del
                cargador, así como la fabricación de munición mucho más rentable. Más importante aún que el hecho de que
                las balas sean más cortas, es que el mecanismo de autorecarga "recorre" una distancia menor para abrir
                la recámara para introducir una nueva bala, lo que se traduce de nuevo en un ratio de fuego mayor en el
                caso de los rifles con munición sin casquillos, así como una mayor posibilidad de que las primeras balas
                acierten en el blanco antes de que el retroceso aparte la mira del objetivo. Los problemas más comunes
                que se dan con la munición sin casquillos, que estancaron los primeros intentos de fabricación de estas
                armas de fuego en NT4, son que la munición es sensible al calor (la pólvora tiende a prenderse cuando
                los cañones están sobrecalentados), sellando la parte posterior del cañón con los gases producidos por
                el propelente (lo que en las armas de cartuchos se evita gracias a que el cartucho permanece siempre
                detrás del cañón) y, finalmente, la fragilidad de la munición que no está protegida por un casquillo de
                metal. Estas armas fueron muy populares durante la Segunda República y se fabricaron en gran cantidad;
                el Leyland Caseless y la Gleelan MR-C todavía se pueden encontrar a lo largo de los Mundos Conocidos. El
                Karr &amp; Meizner de Tetis es actualmente el único fabricante a gran escala de los rifles sin
                casquillos de
                los Mundos Conocidos. Su Serie K&amp;M-MR12, que fue lanzada a finales de las Guerras del Emperador, es
                la
                única serie de modelos que actualmente se producen. La nueva versión 3 del K&amp;M-MR12 se lanzó en el
                5002
                en un intento por volver a introducir el arma con un diseño superior, pero menos rentable.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>40/125</range>
                <shots>48</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>800</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
        </others>
    </typicalCaselessRifle>
    <gleelanMRC>
        <id>gleelanMRC</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Gleelan MR-C (4.3mm)</en>
            <es>Gleelan MR-C (4.3mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rifles manufactured to use caseless ammunition (there are very few handguns employing this technology),
                work much the same way as ordinary automatic assault rifles, the technological advance lying primarily
                with the ammunition. Caseless ammunition eliminates the need of a cartridge, containing the primer,
                propellant and bullet as a single unit projectile. The benefit of this is a simpler automatic firing
                mechanism with less chance of failure, as well as smaller and lighter bullets. This allows for larger
                magazine capacity as well as more cost efficient ammunition. Perhaps more important still, the shorter
                bullets mean the autofeed mechanism "travels" a shorter distance to open the chamber for a new bullet,
                which again translatesto a significantly higher rate of fire for caseless ammunition rifles, as well as
                a greater chance of early bullets hitting the target before recoil moves the gun off target. Common
                problems with caseless ammo, which stalled early TL4 attempts at manufacturing these guns, are the
                heat-sensitive ammunition (which tends to self-ignite in hot barrels), sealing the back of the barrel
                with gases produced by the propellant explosion (which in cartridge guns is prevented by the cartridge
                staying behind in the barrel) and finally the fragility of the ammunition not protected by a metal case.
                These weapons were very popular during the Second Republic and were manufactured in large numbers; both
                the Leyland Caseless and the Gleelan MR-C can still be found throughout the Known Worlds. The Karr &amp;
                Meizner Guild on Tethys is currently the only large-scale manufacturer of caseless ammunition rifles in
                the Known Worlds. Their K&amp;M MR12 series, which was launched late in the Emperor Wars, is the only
                model
                series currently produced. The new K&amp;M MR12 version 3 was released in 5002 in an attempt to
                re-launch
                the gun with a superior (but less-profitable) design.
            </en>
            <es>Son rifles fabricados para usar municiones sin casquillo (existen muy pocos revólveres que usen esta
                tecnología), funciona prácticamente igual que la mayoría de los rifles de asalto automáticos comunes, el
                avance tecnológico realmente tiene que ver con la munición. La munición sin casquillos elimina la
                necesidad de un cartucho, que contiene la pólvora, el propelente y la bala como un único proyectil. Lo
                que se consigue con este sistema es un mecanismo de disparo automático más simple y con menos
                posibilidades de fracaso, así como balas más pequeñas y ligeras. Esto permite ampliar la capacidad del
                cargador, así como la fabricación de munición mucho más rentable. Más importante aún que el hecho de que
                las balas sean más cortas, es que el mecanismo de autorecarga "recorre" una distancia menor para abrir
                la recámara para introducir una nueva bala, lo que se traduce de nuevo en un ratio de fuego mayor en el
                caso de los rifles con munición sin casquillos, así como una mayor posibilidad de que las primeras balas
                acierten en el blanco antes de que el retroceso aparte la mira del objetivo. Los problemas más comunes
                que se dan con la munición sin casquillos, que estancaron los primeros intentos de fabricación de estas
                armas de fuego en NT4, son que la munición es sensible al calor (la pólvora tiende a prenderse cuando
                los cañones están sobrecalentados), sellando la parte posterior del cañón con los gases producidos por
                el propelente (lo que en las armas de cartuchos se evita gracias a que el cartucho permanece siempre
                detrás del cañón) y, finalmente, la fragilidad de la munición que no está protegida por un casquillo de
                metal. Estas armas fueron muy populares durante la Segunda República y se fabricaron en gran cantidad;
                el Leyland Caseless y la Gleelan MR-C todavía se pueden encontrar a lo largo de los Mundos Conocidos. El
                Karr &amp; Meizner de Tetis es actualmente el único fabricante a gran escala de los rifles sin
                casquillos de
                los Mundos Conocidos. Su Serie K&amp;M-MR12, que fue lanzada a finales de las Guerras del Emperador, es
                la
                única serie de modelos que actualmente se producen. La nueva versión 3 del K&amp;M-MR12 se lanzó en el
                5002
                en un intento por volver a introducir el arma con un diseño superior, pero menos rentable.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>55/175</range>
                <shots>56</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>1000</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
        </others>
    </gleelanMRC>
    <laylandCaseless>
        <id>laylandCaseless</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Layland Caseless (5mm)</en>
            <es>Layland Caseless (5mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rifles manufactured to use caseless ammunition (there are very few handguns employing this technology),
                work much the same way as ordinary automatic assault rifles, the technological advance lying primarily
                with the ammunition. Caseless ammunition eliminates the need of a cartridge, containing the primer,
                propellant and bullet as a single unit projectile. The benefit of this is a simpler automatic firing
                mechanism with less chance of failure, as well as smaller and lighter bullets. This allows for larger
                magazine capacity as well as more cost efficient ammunition. Perhaps more important still, the shorter
                bullets mean the autofeed mechanism "travels" a shorter distance to open the chamber for a new bullet,
                which again translatesto a significantly higher rate of fire for caseless ammunition rifles, as well as
                a greater chance of early bullets hitting the target before recoil moves the gun off target. Common
                problems with caseless ammo, which stalled early TL4 attempts at manufacturing these guns, are the
                heat-sensitive ammunition (which tends to self-ignite in hot barrels), sealing the back of the barrel
                with gases produced by the propellant explosion (which in cartridge guns is prevented by the cartridge
                staying behind in the barrel) and finally the fragility of the ammunition not protected by a metal case.
                These weapons were very popular during the Second Republic and were manufactured in large numbers; both
                the Leyland Caseless and the Gleelan MR-C can still be found throughout the Known Worlds. The Karr &amp;
                Meizner Guild on Tethys is currently the only large-scale manufacturer of caseless ammunition rifles in
                the Known Worlds. Their K&amp;M MR12 series, which was launched late in the Emperor Wars, is the only
                model
                series currently produced. The new K&amp;M MR12 version 3 was released in 5002 in an attempt to
                re-launch
                the gun with a superior (but less-profitable) design.
            </en>
            <es>Son rifles fabricados para usar municiones sin casquillo (existen muy pocos revólveres que usen esta
                tecnología), funciona prácticamente igual que la mayoría de los rifles de asalto automáticos comunes, el
                avance tecnológico realmente tiene que ver con la munición. La munición sin casquillos elimina la
                necesidad de un cartucho, que contiene la pólvora, el propelente y la bala como un único proyectil. Lo
                que se consigue con este sistema es un mecanismo de disparo automático más simple y con menos
                posibilidades de fracaso, así como balas más pequeñas y ligeras. Esto permite ampliar la capacidad del
                cargador, así como la fabricación de munición mucho más rentable. Más importante aún que el hecho de que
                las balas sean más cortas, es que el mecanismo de autorecarga "recorre" una distancia menor para abrir
                la recámara para introducir una nueva bala, lo que se traduce de nuevo en un ratio de fuego mayor en el
                caso de los rifles con munición sin casquillos, así como una mayor posibilidad de que las primeras balas
                acierten en el blanco antes de que el retroceso aparte la mira del objetivo. Los problemas más comunes
                que se dan con la munición sin casquillos, que estancaron los primeros intentos de fabricación de estas
                armas de fuego en NT4, son que la munición es sensible al calor (la pólvora tiende a prenderse cuando
                los cañones están sobrecalentados), sellando la parte posterior del cañón con los gases producidos por
                el propelente (lo que en las armas de cartuchos se evita gracias a que el cartucho permanece siempre
                detrás del cañón) y, finalmente, la fragilidad de la munición que no está protegida por un casquillo de
                metal. Estas armas fueron muy populares durante la Segunda República y se fabricaron en gran cantidad;
                el Leyland Caseless y la Gleelan MR-C todavía se pueden encontrar a lo largo de los Mundos Conocidos. El
                Karr &amp; Meizner de Tetis es actualmente el único fabricante a gran escala de los rifles sin
                casquillos de
                los Mundos Conocidos. Su Serie K&amp;M-MR12, que fue lanzada a finales de las Guerras del Emperador, es
                la
                única serie de modelos que actualmente se producen. La nueva versión 3 del K&amp;M-MR12 se lanzó en el
                5002
                en un intento por volver a introducir el arma con un diseño superior, pero menos rentable.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>35/110</range>
                <shots>52</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>800</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
        </others>
    </laylandCaseless>
    <kMMR12>
        <id>kMMR12</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>K&amp;M MR12 (5mm)</en>
            <es>K&amp;M MR12 (5mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rifles manufactured to use caseless ammunition (there are very few handguns employing this technology),
                work much the same way as ordinary automatic assault rifles, the technological advance lying primarily
                with the ammunition. Caseless ammunition eliminates the need of a cartridge, containing the primer,
                propellant and bullet as a single unit projectile. The benefit of this is a simpler automatic firing
                mechanism with less chance of failure, as well as smaller and lighter bullets. This allows for larger
                magazine capacity as well as more cost efficient ammunition. Perhaps more important still, the shorter
                bullets mean the autofeed mechanism "travels" a shorter distance to open the chamber for a new bullet,
                which again translatesto a significantly higher rate of fire for caseless ammunition rifles, as well as
                a greater chance of early bullets hitting the target before recoil moves the gun off target. Common
                problems with caseless ammo, which stalled early TL4 attempts at manufacturing these guns, are the
                heat-sensitive ammunition (which tends to self-ignite in hot barrels), sealing the back of the barrel
                with gases produced by the propellant explosion (which in cartridge guns is prevented by the cartridge
                staying behind in the barrel) and finally the fragility of the ammunition not protected by a metal case.
                These weapons were very popular during the Second Republic and were manufactured in large numbers; both
                the Leyland Caseless and the Gleelan MR-C can still be found throughout the Known Worlds. The Karr &amp;
                Meizner Guild on Tethys is currently the only large-scale manufacturer of caseless ammunition rifles in
                the Known Worlds. Their K&amp;M MR12 series, which was launched late in the Emperor Wars, is the only
                model
                series currently produced. The new K&amp;M MR12 version 3 was released in 5002 in an attempt to
                re-launch
                the gun with a superior (but less-profitable) design.
            </en>
            <es>Son rifles fabricados para usar municiones sin casquillo (existen muy pocos revólveres que usen esta
                tecnología), funciona prácticamente igual que la mayoría de los rifles de asalto automáticos comunes, el
                avance tecnológico realmente tiene que ver con la munición. La munición sin casquillos elimina la
                necesidad de un cartucho, que contiene la pólvora, el propelente y la bala como un único proyectil. Lo
                que se consigue con este sistema es un mecanismo de disparo automático más simple y con menos
                posibilidades de fracaso, así como balas más pequeñas y ligeras. Esto permite ampliar la capacidad del
                cargador, así como la fabricación de munición mucho más rentable. Más importante aún que el hecho de que
                las balas sean más cortas, es que el mecanismo de autorecarga "recorre" una distancia menor para abrir
                la recámara para introducir una nueva bala, lo que se traduce de nuevo en un ratio de fuego mayor en el
                caso de los rifles con munición sin casquillos, así como una mayor posibilidad de que las primeras balas
                acierten en el blanco antes de que el retroceso aparte la mira del objetivo. Los problemas más comunes
                que se dan con la munición sin casquillos, que estancaron los primeros intentos de fabricación de estas
                armas de fuego en NT4, son que la munición es sensible al calor (la pólvora tiende a prenderse cuando
                los cañones están sobrecalentados), sellando la parte posterior del cañón con los gases producidos por
                el propelente (lo que en las armas de cartuchos se evita gracias a que el cartucho permanece siempre
                detrás del cañón) y, finalmente, la fragilidad de la munición que no está protegida por un casquillo de
                metal. Estas armas fueron muy populares durante la Segunda República y se fabricaron en gran cantidad;
                el Leyland Caseless y la Gleelan MR-C todavía se pueden encontrar a lo largo de los Mundos Conocidos. El
                Karr &amp; Meizner de Tetis es actualmente el único fabricante a gran escala de los rifles sin
                casquillos de
                los Mundos Conocidos. Su Serie K&amp;M-MR12, que fue lanzada a finales de las Guerras del Emperador, es
                la
                única serie de modelos que actualmente se producen. La nueva versión 3 del K&amp;M-MR12 se lanzó en el
                5002
                en un intento por volver a introducir el arma con un diseño superior, pero menos rentable.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>40/125</range>
                <shots>48</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>800</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
        </others>
    </kMMR12>
    <kMMR12v3>
        <id>kMMR12v3</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>K&amp;M MR12v3 (5mm)</en>
            <es>K&amp;M MR12v3 (5mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rifles manufactured to use caseless ammunition (there are very few handguns employing this technology),
                work much the same way as ordinary automatic assault rifles, the technological advance lying primarily
                with the ammunition. Caseless ammunition eliminates the need of a cartridge, containing the primer,
                propellant and bullet as a single unit projectile. The benefit of this is a simpler automatic firing
                mechanism with less chance of failure, as well as smaller and lighter bullets. This allows for larger
                magazine capacity as well as more cost efficient ammunition. Perhaps more important still, the shorter
                bullets mean the autofeed mechanism "travels" a shorter distance to open the chamber for a new bullet,
                which again translatesto a significantly higher rate of fire for caseless ammunition rifles, as well as
                a greater chance of early bullets hitting the target before recoil moves the gun off target. Common
                problems with caseless ammo, which stalled early TL4 attempts at manufacturing these guns, are the
                heat-sensitive ammunition (which tends to self-ignite in hot barrels), sealing the back of the barrel
                with gases produced by the propellant explosion (which in cartridge guns is prevented by the cartridge
                staying behind in the barrel) and finally the fragility of the ammunition not protected by a metal case.
                These weapons were very popular during the Second Republic and were manufactured in large numbers; both
                the Leyland Caseless and the Gleelan MR-C can still be found throughout the Known Worlds. The Karr &amp;
                Meizner Guild on Tethys is currently the only large-scale manufacturer of caseless ammunition rifles in
                the Known Worlds. Their K&amp;M MR12 series, which was launched late in the Emperor Wars, is the only
                model
                series currently produced. The new K&amp;M MR12 version 3 was released in 5002 in an attempt to
                re-launch
                the gun with a superior (but less-profitable) design.
            </en>
            <es>Son rifles fabricados para usar municiones sin casquillo (existen muy pocos revólveres que usen esta
                tecnología), funciona prácticamente igual que la mayoría de los rifles de asalto automáticos comunes, el
                avance tecnológico realmente tiene que ver con la munición. La munición sin casquillos elimina la
                necesidad de un cartucho, que contiene la pólvora, el propelente y la bala como un único proyectil. Lo
                que se consigue con este sistema es un mecanismo de disparo automático más simple y con menos
                posibilidades de fracaso, así como balas más pequeñas y ligeras. Esto permite ampliar la capacidad del
                cargador, así como la fabricación de munición mucho más rentable. Más importante aún que el hecho de que
                las balas sean más cortas, es que el mecanismo de autorecarga "recorre" una distancia menor para abrir
                la recámara para introducir una nueva bala, lo que se traduce de nuevo en un ratio de fuego mayor en el
                caso de los rifles con munición sin casquillos, así como una mayor posibilidad de que las primeras balas
                acierten en el blanco antes de que el retroceso aparte la mira del objetivo. Los problemas más comunes
                que se dan con la munición sin casquillos, que estancaron los primeros intentos de fabricación de estas
                armas de fuego en NT4, son que la munición es sensible al calor (la pólvora tiende a prenderse cuando
                los cañones están sobrecalentados), sellando la parte posterior del cañón con los gases producidos por
                el propelente (lo que en las armas de cartuchos se evita gracias a que el cartucho permanece siempre
                detrás del cañón) y, finalmente, la fragilidad de la munición que no está protegida por un casquillo de
                metal. Estas armas fueron muy populares durante la Segunda República y se fabricaron en gran cantidad;
                el Leyland Caseless y la Gleelan MR-C todavía se pueden encontrar a lo largo de los Mundos Conocidos. El
                Karr &amp; Meizner de Tetis es actualmente el único fabricante a gran escala de los rifles sin
                casquillos de
                los Mundos Conocidos. Su Serie K&amp;M-MR12, que fue lanzada a finales de las Guerras del Emperador, es
                la
                única serie de modelos que actualmente se producen. La nueva versión 3 del K&amp;M-MR12 se lanzó en el
                5002
                en un intento por volver a introducir el arma con un diseño superior, pero menos rentable.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>40/135</range>
                <shots>52</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>900</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
        </others>
    </kMMR12v3>
    <typicalFirelockPistol>
        <id>typicalFirelockPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Typical Firelock Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistola de Avancarga Típica</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These firearms see little use or manufacturing anymore, although some backwater regions with limited
                technology and resources see local big-men produce such firearms to dominate their fellow man. Also,
                some anachronistic hunters, or hunters on worlds where weapons technologies are severally restricted,
                (Holy Terra), use firelock guns as a hunting tool. Firelock guns are never mass-produced anymore,
                although individual gunsmiths, from private amateurs to master smiths, produce such game for their own
                use or on demand.
            </en>
            <es>Estas armas de fuego se suelen usar poco y se fabrican todavía menos, aunque algunas regiones rurales
                con tecnología y recursos limitados suelen ver cómo los peces gordos locales fabrican estas armas de
                fuego para dominar a sus semejantes. Además, algunos cazadores anacrónicos, o cazadores que provienen de
                mundos donde la tecnología armamentística está restringida con severidad, (Terra Santa), usan las armas
                de avancarga como herramientas de caza. Las armas de avancarga nunca se fabrican en masa, aunque los
                armeros, desde los más aficionados hasta los maestros armeros, fabrican estas armas para su uso personal
                o bajo encargo.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>40</cost>
        <others>
            <other>muzzlefeed</other>
        </others>
    </typicalFirelockPistol>
    <typicalFirelockRifle>
        <id>typicalFirelockRifle</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Typical Firelock Rifle</en>
            <es>Pistola de Avancarga Típica</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These firearms see little use or manufacturing anymore, although some backwater regions with limited
                technology and resources see local big-men produce such firearms to dominate their fellow man. Also,
                some anachronistic hunters, or hunters on worlds where weapons technologies are severally restricted,
                (Holy Terra), use firelock guns as a hunting tool. Firelock guns are never mass-produced anymore,
                although individual gunsmiths, from private amateurs to master smiths, produce such game for their own
                use or on demand.
            </en>
            <es>Estas armas de fuego se suelen usar poco y se fabrican todavía menos, aunque algunas regiones rurales
                con tecnología y recursos limitados suelen ver cómo los peces gordos locales fabrican estas armas de
                fuego para dominar a sus semejantes. Además, algunos cazadores anacrónicos, o cazadores que provienen de
                mundos donde la tecnología armamentística está restringida con severidad, (Terra Santa), usan las armas
                de avancarga como herramientas de caza. Las armas de avancarga nunca se fabrican en masa, aunque los
                armeros, desde los más aficionados hasta los maestros armeros, fabrican estas armas para su uso personal
                o bajo encargo.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>2</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>20/60</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>100</cost>
        <others>
            <other>muzzlefeed</other>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </typicalFirelockRifle>
    <cancanaghDartgunPistol>
        <id>cancanaghDartgunPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Cancanagh Dartgun Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistolas de Dardos Cancanagh</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Occasionally one comes across more unusual handguns in the Known Worlds. Flechette or splinter guns
                (TL6) make up one such category, including such guns as the Reznor Nail Gun (manufactured on Leagueheim
                in limited number by Crafter Orth Reznor of the Engineers Guild), and the Hailstorm (manufactured by the
                Bourriau Guild up until 4993, when the Bourrian family perished during the last days of the Emperor
                Wars. At present, no party holds the production rights to the Hailstrom Flechette pistol). The Cancanagh
                Dartgun, which is muzzle loaded and quite reliable, is one of the most popular handgun sized dartguns in
                the Phoenix Empire (the design is owned by the Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but licensed out extensively
                to weaponsmiths and producers throughout the Empire). It has the same game mechanics effects as a
                syringe arrow. Another strange handgun is the Decados Groin Gun (TL5), dubbed by one observer as "the
                dumbest weapon ever manufactured." This light revolver is made to be concealed somewhere on the wearer’s
                body, and comes with a multi-positioning harness. As its name implies, it is typically hidden in a
                codpiece, but can be adapted for placement into other locations as well. The spring-loaded gun snaps out
                of its hidden compartment at the flick of a switch. The switch is often hidden in a ring, inside a
                pocket, or on a belt, but it can also be fashioned into an electrode attached to a certain muscle and
                turned to activity when the muscle moves. Some Scraver gangsters have been known to modify it as a
                sleeve gun instead.
            </en>
            <es>De vez en cuando uno se encuentra revólveres en los Mundos Conocidos que son más inusuales de lo normal.
                Las armas de Flechette o de dardos (NT6) constituyen una de esas categorías, incluyendo armas como el
                Arma de Clavos Reznor (fabricada en Ligaheim por el artesano Orth Reznor del Gremio de Ingenieros), y el
                Hailstrom (fabricado por el Gremio Bourriau hasta el 4993, cuando la familia Bourrian pereció durante
                los últimos días de las Guerras del Emperador. Actualmente, no hay ningún grupo que tenga los derechosde
                producción de la Pistola de Dardos Hailstrom). El Arma de Dardos Cancanagh, es un arma bastante fiable
                que se recarga por el cañón. Es una de las pistolas de dardos más populares del Imperio del Fénix (el
                diseño es propiedad de la familia Harthoornde Rávena, pero la patente está ampliamente extendida entre
                los armeros y los productores a lo largo de todo el Imperio). Tiene el mismo juego de efectos mecánicos
                que una flecha de punta de jeringa. Otra extraña pistola es la Decados Groin (NT5), tildada por un
                observador militar como "el arma más tonta jamás fabricada". Este revólver ligero está fabricado de modo
                que pueda ocultarse en cualquier parte del cuerpo del portador, e incluye un arnés de
                multiposicionamiento. Como su propio nombre indica (Groin = Ingle en inglés), el arma suele esconderse
                en un taparrabos, pero puede adaptarse para colocarse en otro lugar. La pistola con un sistema de
                recarga con resorte sale de su compartimento oculto accionando un interruptor. Este interruptor suele
                ocultarse en un anillo, en un bolsillo, o en un cinturón, pero bién se puede disimular en un electrodo
                unido a unmúsculo determinado y que se enciende cuando ese músculo se mueva. A algunos gánster de los
                Carroñeros se les conoce por modificar el arma para poder esconderla en la manga.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>3</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>2</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>100</cost>
        <others>
            <other>syringe</other>
            <other>muzzlefeed</other>
        </others>
    </cancanaghDartgunPistol>
    <decadosGroinGun>
        <id>decadosGroinGun</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Decados Groin Gun (.32)</en>
            <es>Pistola Decados Groin (.32)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Occasionally one comes across more unusual handguns in the Known Worlds. Flechette or splinter guns
                (TL6) make up one such category, including such guns as the Reznor Nail Gun (manufactured on Leagueheim
                in limited number by Crafter Orth Reznor of the Engineers Guild), and the Hailstorm (manufactured by the
                Bourriau Guild up until 4993, when the Bourrian family perished during the last days of the Emperor
                Wars. At present, no party holds the production rights to the Hailstrom Flechette pistol). The Cancanagh
                Dartgun, which is muzzle loaded and quite reliable, is one of the most popular handgun sized dartguns in
                the Phoenix Empire (the design is owned by the Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but licensed out extensively
                to weaponsmiths and producers throughout the Empire). It has the same game mechanics effects as a
                syringe arrow. Another strange handgun is the Decados Groin Gun (TL5), dubbed by one observer as "the
                dumbest weapon ever manufactured." This light revolver is made to be concealed somewhere on the wearer’s
                body, and comes with a multi-positioning harness. As its name implies, it is typically hidden in a
                codpiece, but can be adapted for placement into other locations as well. The spring-loaded gun snaps out
                of its hidden compartment at the flick of a switch. The switch is often hidden in a ring, inside a
                pocket, or on a belt, but it can also be fashioned into an electrode attached to a certain muscle and
                turned to activity when the muscle moves. Some Scraver gangsters have been known to modify it as a
                sleeve gun instead.
            </en>
            <es>De vez en cuando uno se encuentra revólveres en los Mundos Conocidos que son más inusuales de lo normal.
                Las armas de Flechette o de dardos (NT6) constituyen una de esas categorías, incluyendo armas como el
                Arma de Clavos Reznor (fabricada en Ligaheim por el artesano Orth Reznor del Gremio de Ingenieros), y el
                Hailstrom (fabricado por el Gremio Bourriau hasta el 4993, cuando la familia Bourrian pereció durante
                los últimos días de las Guerras del Emperador. Actualmente, no hay ningún grupo que tenga los derechosde
                producción de la Pistola de Dardos Hailstrom). El Arma de Dardos Cancanagh, es un arma bastante fiable
                que se recarga por el cañón. Es una de las pistolas de dardos más populares del Imperio del Fénix (el
                diseño es propiedad de la familia Harthoornde Rávena, pero la patente está ampliamente extendida entre
                los armeros y los productores a lo largo de todo el Imperio). Tiene el mismo juego de efectos mecánicos
                que una flecha de punta de jeringa. Otra extraña pistola es la Decados Groin (NT5), tildada por un
                observador militar como "el arma más tonta jamás fabricada". Este revólver ligero está fabricado de modo
                que pueda ocultarse en cualquier parte del cuerpo del portador, e incluye un arnés de
                multiposicionamiento. Como su propio nombre indica (Groin = Ingle en inglés), el arma suele esconderse
                en un taparrabos, pero puede adaptarse para colocarse en otro lugar. La pistola con un sistema de
                recarga con resorte sale de su compartimento oculto accionando un interruptor. Este interruptor suele
                ocultarse en un anillo, en un bolsillo, o en un cinturón, pero bién se puede disimular en un electrodo
                unido a unmúsculo determinado y que se enciende cuando ese músculo se mueva. A algunos gánster de los
                Carroñeros se les conoce por modificar el arma para poder esconderla en la manga.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>6</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>150</cost>
        <others>
            <other>hidden</other>
        </others>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>0.01</probabilityMultiplier>
            <restrictedFactions>decados</restrictedFactions>
        </random>
    </decadosGroinGun>
    <hailstormSplinterPistol>
        <id>hailstormSplinterPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Hailstorm Splinter Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistola de Dardos Hailstorm</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Occasionally one comes across more unusual handguns in the Known Worlds. Flechette or splinter guns
                (TL6) make up one such category, including such guns as the Reznor Nail Gun (manufactured on Leagueheim
                in limited number by Crafter Orth Reznor of the Engineers Guild), and the Hailstorm (manufactured by the
                Bourriau Guild up until 4993, when the Bourrian family perished during the last days of the Emperor
                Wars. At present, no party holds the production rights to the Hailstrom Flechette pistol). The Cancanagh
                Dartgun, which is muzzle loaded and quite reliable, is one of the most popular handgun sized dartguns in
                the Phoenix Empire (the design is owned by the Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but licensed out extensively
                to weaponsmiths and producers throughout the Empire). It has the same game mechanics effects as a
                syringe arrow. Another strange handgun is the Decados Groin Gun (TL5), dubbed by one observer as "the
                dumbest weapon ever manufactured." This light revolver is made to be concealed somewhere on the wearer’s
                body, and comes with a multi-positioning harness. As its name implies, it is typically hidden in a
                codpiece, but can be adapted for placement into other locations as well. The spring-loaded gun snaps out
                of its hidden compartment at the flick of a switch. The switch is often hidden in a ring, inside a
                pocket, or on a belt, but it can also be fashioned into an electrode attached to a certain muscle and
                turned to activity when the muscle moves. Some Scraver gangsters have been known to modify it as a
                sleeve gun instead.
            </en>
            <es>De vez en cuando uno se encuentra revólveres en los Mundos Conocidos que son más inusuales de lo normal.
                Las armas de Flechette o de dardos (NT6) constituyen una de esas categorías, incluyendo armas como el
                Arma de Clavos Reznor (fabricada en Ligaheim por el artesano Orth Reznor del Gremio de Ingenieros), y el
                Hailstrom (fabricado por el Gremio Bourriau hasta el 4993, cuando la familia Bourrian pereció durante
                los últimos días de las Guerras del Emperador. Actualmente, no hay ningún grupo que tenga los derechosde
                producción de la Pistola de Dardos Hailstrom). El Arma de Dardos Cancanagh, es un arma bastante fiable
                que se recarga por el cañón. Es una de las pistolas de dardos más populares del Imperio del Fénix (el
                diseño es propiedad de la familia Harthoornde Rávena, pero la patente está ampliamente extendida entre
                los armeros y los productores a lo largo de todo el Imperio). Tiene el mismo juego de efectos mecánicos
                que una flecha de punta de jeringa. Otra extraña pistola es la Decados Groin (NT5), tildada por un
                observador militar como "el arma más tonta jamás fabricada". Este revólver ligero está fabricado de modo
                que pueda ocultarse en cualquier parte del cuerpo del portador, e incluye un arnés de
                multiposicionamiento. Como su propio nombre indica (Groin = Ingle en inglés), el arma suele esconderse
                en un taparrabos, pero puede adaptarse para colocarse en otro lugar. La pistola con un sistema de
                recarga con resorte sale de su compartimento oculto accionando un interruptor. Este interruptor suele
                ocultarse en un anillo, en un bolsillo, o en un cinturón, pero bién se puede disimular en un electrodo
                unido a unmúsculo determinado y que se enciende cuando ese músculo se mueva. A algunos gánster de los
                Carroñeros se les conoce por modificar el arma para poder esconderla en la manga.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+2/+1/0</goal>
                <damage>4/3/2</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>10/20/×</range>
                <shots>12</shots>
                <rate>3</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>200</cost>
        <others>
            <other>flechette</other>
        </others>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>0.01</probabilityMultiplier>
        </random>
    </hailstormSplinterPistol>
    <reznorNailGun>
        <id>reznorNailGun</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Reznor Nail Gun</en>
            <es>Arma de Clavos Reznor</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Occasionally one comes across more unusual handguns in the Known Worlds. Flechette or splinter guns
                (TL6) make up one such category, including such guns as the Reznor Nail Gun (manufactured on Leagueheim
                in limited number by Crafter Orth Reznor of the Engineers Guild), and the Hailstorm (manufactured by the
                Bourriau Guild up until 4993, when the Bourrian family perished during the last days of the Emperor
                Wars. At present, no party holds the production rights to the Hailstrom Flechette pistol). The Cancanagh
                Dartgun, which is muzzle loaded and quite reliable, is one of the most popular handgun sized dartguns in
                the Phoenix Empire (the design is owned by the Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but licensed out extensively
                to weaponsmiths and producers throughout the Empire). It has the same game mechanics effects as a
                syringe arrow. Another strange handgun is the Decados Groin Gun (TL5), dubbed by one observer as "the
                dumbest weapon ever manufactured." This light revolver is made to be concealed somewhere on the wearer’s
                body, and comes with a multi-positioning harness. As its name implies, it is typically hidden in a
                codpiece, but can be adapted for placement into other locations as well. The spring-loaded gun snaps out
                of its hidden compartment at the flick of a switch. The switch is often hidden in a ring, inside a
                pocket, or on a belt, but it can also be fashioned into an electrode attached to a certain muscle and
                turned to activity when the muscle moves. Some Scraver gangsters have been known to modify it as a
                sleeve gun instead.
            </en>
            <es>De vez en cuando uno se encuentra revólveres en los Mundos Conocidos que son más inusuales de lo normal.
                Las armas de Flechette o de dardos (NT6) constituyen una de esas categorías, incluyendo armas como el
                Arma de Clavos Reznor (fabricada en Ligaheim por el artesano Orth Reznor del Gremio de Ingenieros), y el
                Hailstrom (fabricado por el Gremio Bourriau hasta el 4993, cuando la familia Bourrian pereció durante
                los últimos días de las Guerras del Emperador. Actualmente, no hay ningún grupo que tenga los derechosde
                producción de la Pistola de Dardos Hailstrom). El Arma de Dardos Cancanagh, es un arma bastante fiable
                que se recarga por el cañón. Es una de las pistolas de dardos más populares del Imperio del Fénix (el
                diseño es propiedad de la familia Harthoornde Rávena, pero la patente está ampliamente extendida entre
                los armeros y los productores a lo largo de todo el Imperio). Tiene el mismo juego de efectos mecánicos
                que una flecha de punta de jeringa. Otra extraña pistola es la Decados Groin (NT5), tildada por un
                observador militar como "el arma más tonta jamás fabricada". Este revólver ligero está fabricado de modo
                que pueda ocultarse en cualquier parte del cuerpo del portador, e incluye un arnés de
                multiposicionamiento. Como su propio nombre indica (Groin = Ingle en inglés), el arma suele esconderse
                en un taparrabos, pero puede adaptarse para colocarse en otro lugar. La pistola con un sistema de
                recarga con resorte sale de su compartimento oculto accionando un interruptor. Este interruptor suele
                ocultarse en un anillo, en un bolsillo, o en un cinturón, pero bién se puede disimular en un electrodo
                unido a unmúsculo determinado y que se enciende cuando ese músculo se mueva. A algunos gánster de los
                Carroñeros se les conoce por modificar el arma para poder esconderla en la manga.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1/+1/0</goal>
                <damage>4/3/2</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>10/20/×</range>
                <shots>7</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>300</cost>
        <others>
            <other>autofeed</other>
            <other>flechette</other>
        </others>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>0.01</probabilityMultiplier>
            <restrictedFactionGroups>guild</restrictedFactionGroups>
        </random>
    </reznorNailGun>
    <nailgunPowerTool>
        <id>nailgunPowerTool</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Nailgun Power Tool</en>
            <es>Pistola de Clavos Eléctrica</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Occasionally one comes across more unusual handguns in the Known Worlds. Flechette or splinter guns
                (TL6) make up one such category, including such guns as the Reznor Nail Gun (manufactured on Leagueheim
                in limited number by Crafter Orth Reznor of the Engineers Guild), and the Hailstorm (manufactured by the
                Bourriau Guild up until 4993, when the Bourrian family perished during the last days of the Emperor
                Wars. At present, no party holds the production rights to the Hailstrom Flechette pistol). The Cancanagh
                Dartgun, which is muzzle loaded and quite reliable, is one of the most popular handgun sized dartguns in
                the Phoenix Empire (the design is owned by the Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but licensed out extensively
                to weaponsmiths and producers throughout the Empire). It has the same game mechanics effects as a
                syringe arrow. Another strange handgun is the Decados Groin Gun (TL5), dubbed by one observer as "the
                dumbest weapon ever manufactured." This light revolver is made to be concealed somewhere on the wearer’s
                body, and comes with a multi-positioning harness. As its name implies, it is typically hidden in a
                codpiece, but can be adapted for placement into other locations as well. The spring-loaded gun snaps out
                of its hidden compartment at the flick of a switch. The switch is often hidden in a ring, inside a
                pocket, or on a belt, but it can also be fashioned into an electrode attached to a certain muscle and
                turned to activity when the muscle moves. Some Scraver gangsters have been known to modify it as a
                sleeve gun instead.
            </en>
            <es>De vez en cuando uno se encuentra revólveres en los Mundos Conocidos que son más inusuales de lo normal.
                Las armas de Flechette o de dardos (NT6) constituyen una de esas categorías, incluyendo armas como el
                Arma de Clavos Reznor (fabricada en Ligaheim por el artesano Orth Reznor del Gremio de Ingenieros), y el
                Hailstrom (fabricado por el Gremio Bourriau hasta el 4993, cuando la familia Bourrian pereció durante
                los últimos días de las Guerras del Emperador. Actualmente, no hay ningún grupo que tenga los derechosde
                producción de la Pistola de Dardos Hailstrom). El Arma de Dardos Cancanagh, es un arma bastante fiable
                que se recarga por el cañón. Es una de las pistolas de dardos más populares del Imperio del Fénix (el
                diseño es propiedad de la familia Harthoornde Rávena, pero la patente está ampliamente extendida entre
                los armeros y los productores a lo largo de todo el Imperio). Tiene el mismo juego de efectos mecánicos
                que una flecha de punta de jeringa. Otra extraña pistola es la Decados Groin (NT5), tildada por un
                observador militar como "el arma más tonta jamás fabricada". Este revólver ligero está fabricado de modo
                que pueda ocultarse en cualquier parte del cuerpo del portador, e incluye un arnés de
                multiposicionamiento. Como su propio nombre indica (Groin = Ingle en inglés), el arma suele esconderse
                en un taparrabos, pero puede adaptarse para colocarse en otro lugar. La pistola con un sistema de
                recarga con resorte sale de su compartimento oculto accionando un interruptor. Este interruptor suele
                ocultarse en un anillo, en un bolsillo, o en un cinturón, pero bién se puede disimular en un electrodo
                unido a unmúsculo determinado y que se enciende cuando ese músculo se mueva. A algunos gánster de los
                Carroñeros se les conoce por modificar el arma para poder esconderla en la manga.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>0/1/2/3</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>0/1</range>
                <shots>10</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>melee</skill>
                <goal>-1</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
    </nailgunPowerTool>
    <capekAquaRifle>
        <id>capekAquaRifle</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Capek Aqua Rifle (.47)</en>
            <es>Rifle Acuático Capek</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Just as with handguns, there exist unusual and weird rifles in the Known Worlds and beyond. One example
                is the Reznor Model IX Splinter Carabin, the only flechette rifle currently being manufactured. Like its
                cousin the Reznor Nail gun shard pistol, the shard rifle uses a fusion cell to empower a magnetic field
                to propel metallic shards towards its intended victim. Another interesting flechette rifle is the sabot
                gun, a newly reclaimed Second Republic weapon redeemed by Ahriman Dreskel for the Scravers Guild. The
                sabot gun is useful for operations far from logistical support for long periods of time, such as
                exploration and reclamation jobs. The clunky rifle chops whatever is shoved into the ammo port into
                small splinters with an internal laser array. These splinters can then be fired out of the barrel with a
                burst of compressed air (for non-metallic substances) or magnetics (for metallic materials). 1 kg of
                material usually produce about 20 shots. A fusion cell powers the laser chopper and magnetic barrel for
                up to 50 shots. (DMG: 3 Wood; 4 Ice or Plastic; 5 Stone; 6 Steel). The Cupid Longarm is among the most
                widespread needle-dart rifles around, a boltfeed rifle with great accuracy (the design is owned by the
                Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but is produced on over a dozen worlds throughout the Phoenix Emprie). It
                has the same game mechanics effects as a syringe arrow. The "Newt Gun" is a highly specialized firearm
                constructed by Engineer Povronda Capek exclusively for the Oro’ym. The Capek .40 is an aquatic rifle
                used for underwater hunting, and is designed for the webbed hands of the Oro’ym. The Merchant League
                closely monitors the gun’s trade, and favors some Oro’ym factions (like the Tapol’ym Confederation) over
                others. The gun fires a special kind of ammunition (.40 caliber) designed to work underwater, that is
                rarely available outside of Madoc.
            </en>
            <es>Al igual que con los revólveres, existen rifles inusuales y extraños repartidos por los Mundos Conocidos
                y más allá. Un ejemplo es la Carabina de Dardos Reznor Modelo IX, que es el único rifle de dardos que se
                sigue fabricando. Al igual que su prima la Pistola de Clavos Reznor, este rifle utiliza una pila de
                fusión para alimentar un campomagnético para propulsar los fragmentos metálicos hacia la víctima. Otro
                rifle de dardos interesante es el arma Zueco, un arma de la Segunda República recuperada porAhriman
                Dreskel para el Gremio de los Carroñeros. El Zueco es un arma útil para las operaciones que impliquen la
                ausencia del apoyo logístico por largos periodos de tiempo, tales como los trabajos de exploración y de
                recuperación. Los rifles más toscos destrozan cualquier cosa que se meta en el depósito de munición en
                miles de pequeñas astillas con un dispositivo láser interno. En consecuencia estas astillas pueden salir
                despedidas fuera del cañón con una ráfaga de aire comprimido (en el caso de las sustancias no metálicas)
                o con magnetismo (en el caso de materiales metálicos). 1 kg de material por lo general da para unos 20
                disparos. Una pila de fusión proporciona energía al dispositivo láser y al cañón magnético para un
                máximo de 50 tiros (Daño: 3 Madera; 4 Hielo o Plástico; 5 Piedra; 6 Acero). El Cupid Longarm es uno de
                los rifles de dardos- aguja más extendido, un rifle de cerrojo con gran precisión (el diseño es
                propiedad de la familia Harthoorn en Rávena, pero se fabrica en más de una docena de mundos por todo el
                Imperio del Fénix). Tiene los mismos efectos mecánicos que una punta de flecha de jeringa. El arma
                "Newt" es un arma de fuego altamente especializada, fabricada por el ingeniero Povronda Capek
                exclusivamente para los Oro’ym. El Capek .40 es un rifle acuático utilizado en la caza submarina, y está
                diseñado para las manos palmeadas de los Oro’ym. La Liga Mercantil sigue muy de cerca el comercio de
                este arma, y favorece a ciertas facciones de los Oro’ym (como la Confederación Tapol’ym) entre otras. El
                arma dispara un tipo especial de munición (calibre .40) diseñada para funcionar bajo el agua, lo que en
                extrañas ocasiones está disponible fuera de Madoc.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>7</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>45/140</range>
                <shots>5</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Underwater use</en>
                    <es>Bajo el agua</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>7/6/5</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>30/90/X</range>
                <shots>5</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>800</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>boltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </capekAquaRifle>
    <cupidLongarm>
        <id>cupidLongarm</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Cupid Longarm</en>
            <es>Cupid Longarm</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Just as with handguns, there exist unusual and weird rifles in the Known Worlds and beyond. One example
                is the Reznor Model IX Splinter Carabin, the only flechette rifle currently being manufactured. Like its
                cousin the Reznor Nail gun shard pistol, the shard rifle uses a fusion cell to empower a magnetic field
                to propel metallic shards towards its intended victim. Another interesting flechette rifle is the sabot
                gun, a newly reclaimed Second Republic weapon redeemed by Ahriman Dreskel for the Scravers Guild. The
                sabot gun is useful for operations far from logistical support for long periods of time, such as
                exploration and reclamation jobs. The clunky rifle chops whatever is shoved into the ammo port into
                small splinters with an internal laser array. These splinters can then be fired out of the barrel with a
                burst of compressed air (for non-metallic substances) or magnetics (for metallic materials). 1 kg of
                material usually produce about 20 shots. A fusion cell powers the laser chopper and magnetic barrel for
                up to 50 shots. (DMG: 3 Wood; 4 Ice or Plastic; 5 Stone; 6 Steel). The Cupid Longarm is among the most
                widespread needle-dart rifles around, a boltfeed rifle with great accuracy (the design is owned by the
                Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but is produced on over a dozen worlds throughout the Phoenix Emprie). It
                has the same game mechanics effects as a syringe arrow. The "Newt Gun" is a highly specialized firearm
                constructed by Engineer Povronda Capek exclusively for the Oro’ym. The Capek .40 is an aquatic rifle
                used for underwater hunting, and is designed for the webbed hands of the Oro’ym. The Merchant League
                closely monitors the gun’s trade, and favors some Oro’ym factions (like the Tapol’ym Confederation) over
                others. The gun fires a special kind of ammunition (.40 caliber) designed to work underwater, that is
                rarely available outside of Madoc.
            </en>
            <es>Al igual que con los revólveres, existen rifles inusuales y extraños repartidos por los Mundos Conocidos
                y más allá. Un ejemplo es la Carabina de Dardos Reznor Modelo IX, que es el único rifle de dardos que se
                sigue fabricando. Al igual que su prima la Pistola de Clavos Reznor, este rifle utiliza una pila de
                fusión para alimentar un campomagnético para propulsar los fragmentos metálicos hacia la víctima. Otro
                rifle de dardos interesante es el arma Zueco, un arma de la Segunda República recuperada porAhriman
                Dreskel para el Gremio de los Carroñeros. El Zueco es un arma útil para las operaciones que impliquen la
                ausencia del apoyo logístico por largos periodos de tiempo, tales como los trabajos de exploración y de
                recuperación. Los rifles más toscos destrozan cualquier cosa que se meta en el depósito de munición en
                miles de pequeñas astillas con un dispositivo láser interno. En consecuencia estas astillas pueden salir
                despedidas fuera del cañón con una ráfaga de aire comprimido (en el caso de las sustancias no metálicas)
                o con magnetismo (en el caso de materiales metálicos). 1 kg de material por lo general da para unos 20
                disparos. Una pila de fusión proporciona energía al dispositivo láser y al cañón magnético para un
                máximo de 50 tiros (Daño: 3 Madera; 4 Hielo o Plástico; 5 Piedra; 6 Acero). El Cupid Longarm es uno de
                los rifles de dardos- aguja más extendido, un rifle de cerrojo con gran precisión (el diseño es
                propiedad de la familia Harthoorn en Rávena, pero se fabrica en más de una docena de mundos por todo el
                Imperio del Fénix). Tiene los mismos efectos mecánicos que una punta de flecha de jeringa. El arma
                "Newt" es un arma de fuego altamente especializada, fabricada por el ingeniero Povronda Capek
                exclusivamente para los Oro’ym. El Capek .40 es un rifle acuático utilizado en la caza submarina, y está
                diseñado para las manos palmeadas de los Oro’ym. La Liga Mercantil sigue muy de cerca el comercio de
                este arma, y favorece a ciertas facciones de los Oro’ym (como la Confederación Tapol’ym) entre otras. El
                arma dispara un tipo especial de munición (calibre .40) diseñada para funcionar bajo el agua, lo que en
                extrañas ocasiones está disponible fuera de Madoc.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>3</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>20/60</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>200</cost>
        <others>
            <other>muzzlefeed</other>
            <other>syringe</other>
        </others>
    </cupidLongarm>
    <reznorModelXI>
        <id>reznorModelXI</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Reznor Model IX</en>
            <es>Reznor Modelo IX</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Just as with handguns, there exist unusual and weird rifles in the Known Worlds and beyond. One example
                is the Reznor Model IX Splinter Carabin, the only flechette rifle currently being manufactured. Like its
                cousin the Reznor Nail gun shard pistol, the shard rifle uses a fusion cell to empower a magnetic field
                to propel metallic shards towards its intended victim. Another interesting flechette rifle is the sabot
                gun, a newly reclaimed Second Republic weapon redeemed by Ahriman Dreskel for the Scravers Guild. The
                sabot gun is useful for operations far from logistical support for long periods of time, such as
                exploration and reclamation jobs. The clunky rifle chops whatever is shoved into the ammo port into
                small splinters with an internal laser array. These splinters can then be fired out of the barrel with a
                burst of compressed air (for non-metallic substances) or magnetics (for metallic materials). 1 kg of
                material usually produce about 20 shots. A fusion cell powers the laser chopper and magnetic barrel for
                up to 50 shots. (DMG: 3 Wood; 4 Ice or Plastic; 5 Stone; 6 Steel). The Cupid Longarm is among the most
                widespread needle-dart rifles around, a boltfeed rifle with great accuracy (the design is owned by the
                Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but is produced on over a dozen worlds throughout the Phoenix Emprie). It
                has the same game mechanics effects as a syringe arrow. The "Newt Gun" is a highly specialized firearm
                constructed by Engineer Povronda Capek exclusively for the Oro’ym. The Capek .40 is an aquatic rifle
                used for underwater hunting, and is designed for the webbed hands of the Oro’ym. The Merchant League
                closely monitors the gun’s trade, and favors some Oro’ym factions (like the Tapol’ym Confederation) over
                others. The gun fires a special kind of ammunition (.40 caliber) designed to work underwater, that is
                rarely available outside of Madoc.
            </en>
            <es>Al igual que con los revólveres, existen rifles inusuales y extraños repartidos por los Mundos Conocidos
                y más allá. Un ejemplo es la Carabina de Dardos Reznor Modelo IX, que es el único rifle de dardos que se
                sigue fabricando. Al igual que su prima la Pistola de Clavos Reznor, este rifle utiliza una pila de
                fusión para alimentar un campomagnético para propulsar los fragmentos metálicos hacia la víctima. Otro
                rifle de dardos interesante es el arma Zueco, un arma de la Segunda República recuperada porAhriman
                Dreskel para el Gremio de los Carroñeros. El Zueco es un arma útil para las operaciones que impliquen la
                ausencia del apoyo logístico por largos periodos de tiempo, tales como los trabajos de exploración y de
                recuperación. Los rifles más toscos destrozan cualquier cosa que se meta en el depósito de munición en
                miles de pequeñas astillas con un dispositivo láser interno. En consecuencia estas astillas pueden salir
                despedidas fuera del cañón con una ráfaga de aire comprimido (en el caso de las sustancias no metálicas)
                o con magnetismo (en el caso de materiales metálicos). 1 kg de material por lo general da para unos 20
                disparos. Una pila de fusión proporciona energía al dispositivo láser y al cañón magnético para un
                máximo de 50 tiros (Daño: 3 Madera; 4 Hielo o Plástico; 5 Piedra; 6 Acero). El Cupid Longarm es uno de
                los rifles de dardos- aguja más extendido, un rifle de cerrojo con gran precisión (el diseño es
                propiedad de la familia Harthoorn en Rávena, pero se fabrica en más de una docena de mundos por todo el
                Imperio del Fénix). Tiene los mismos efectos mecánicos que una punta de flecha de jeringa. El arma
                "Newt" es un arma de fuego altamente especializada, fabricada por el ingeniero Povronda Capek
                exclusivamente para los Oro’ym. El Capek .40 es un rifle acuático utilizado en la caza submarina, y está
                diseñado para las manos palmeadas de los Oro’ym. La Liga Mercantil sigue muy de cerca el comercio de
                este arma, y favorece a ciertas facciones de los Oro’ym (como la Confederación Tapol’ym) entre otras. El
                arma dispara un tipo especial de munición (calibre .40) diseñada para funcionar bajo el agua, lo que en
                extrañas ocasiones está disponible fuera de Madoc.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+2</goal>
                <damage>5/4/3</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>20/60/x</range>
                <shots>13</shots>
                <rate>2(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <others>
            <other>muzzlefeed</other>
            <other>syringe</other>
        </others>
    </reznorModelXI>
    <sabotGun>
        <id>sabotGun</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Sabot Gun</en>
            <es>Arma de Zanco</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Just as with handguns, there exist unusual and weird rifles in the Known Worlds and beyond. One example
                is the Reznor Model IX Splinter Carabin, the only flechette rifle currently being manufactured. Like its
                cousin the Reznor Nail gun shard pistol, the shard rifle uses a fusion cell to empower a magnetic field
                to propel metallic shards towards its intended victim. Another interesting flechette rifle is the sabot
                gun, a newly reclaimed Second Republic weapon redeemed by Ahriman Dreskel for the Scravers Guild. The
                sabot gun is useful for operations far from logistical support for long periods of time, such as
                exploration and reclamation jobs. The clunky rifle chops whatever is shoved into the ammo port into
                small splinters with an internal laser array. These splinters can then be fired out of the barrel with a
                burst of compressed air (for non-metallic substances) or magnetics (for metallic materials). 1 kg of
                material usually produce about 20 shots. A fusion cell powers the laser chopper and magnetic barrel for
                up to 50 shots. (DMG: 3 Wood; 4 Ice or Plastic; 5 Stone; 6 Steel). The Cupid Longarm is among the most
                widespread needle-dart rifles around, a boltfeed rifle with great accuracy (the design is owned by the
                Harthoorn family on Ravenna, but is produced on over a dozen worlds throughout the Phoenix Emprie). It
                has the same game mechanics effects as a syringe arrow. The "Newt Gun" is a highly specialized firearm
                constructed by Engineer Povronda Capek exclusively for the Oro’ym. The Capek .40 is an aquatic rifle
                used for underwater hunting, and is designed for the webbed hands of the Oro’ym. The Merchant League
                closely monitors the gun’s trade, and favors some Oro’ym factions (like the Tapol’ym Confederation) over
                others. The gun fires a special kind of ammunition (.40 caliber) designed to work underwater, that is
                rarely available outside of Madoc.
            </en>
            <es>Al igual que con los revólveres, existen rifles inusuales y extraños repartidos por los Mundos Conocidos
                y más allá. Un ejemplo es la Carabina de Dardos Reznor Modelo IX, que es el único rifle de dardos que se
                sigue fabricando. Al igual que su prima la Pistola de Clavos Reznor, este rifle utiliza una pila de
                fusión para alimentar un campomagnético para propulsar los fragmentos metálicos hacia la víctima. Otro
                rifle de dardos interesante es el arma Zueco, un arma de la Segunda República recuperada porAhriman
                Dreskel para el Gremio de los Carroñeros. El Zueco es un arma útil para las operaciones que impliquen la
                ausencia del apoyo logístico por largos periodos de tiempo, tales como los trabajos de exploración y de
                recuperación. Los rifles más toscos destrozan cualquier cosa que se meta en el depósito de munición en
                miles de pequeñas astillas con un dispositivo láser interno. En consecuencia estas astillas pueden salir
                despedidas fuera del cañón con una ráfaga de aire comprimido (en el caso de las sustancias no metálicas)
                o con magnetismo (en el caso de materiales metálicos). 1 kg de material por lo general da para unos 20
                disparos. Una pila de fusión proporciona energía al dispositivo láser y al cañón magnético para un
                máximo de 50 tiros (Daño: 3 Madera; 4 Hielo o Plástico; 5 Piedra; 6 Acero). El Cupid Longarm es uno de
                los rifles de dardos- aguja más extendido, un rifle de cerrojo con gran precisión (el diseño es
                propiedad de la familia Harthoorn en Rávena, pero se fabrica en más de una docena de mundos por todo el
                Imperio del Fénix). Tiene los mismos efectos mecánicos que una punta de flecha de jeringa. El arma
                "Newt" es un arma de fuego altamente especializada, fabricada por el ingeniero Povronda Capek
                exclusivamente para los Oro’ym. El Capek .40 es un rifle acuático utilizado en la caza submarina, y está
                diseñado para las manos palmeadas de los Oro’ym. La Liga Mercantil sigue muy de cerca el comercio de
                este arma, y favorece a ciertas facciones de los Oro’ym (como la Confederación Tapol’ym) entre otras. El
                arma dispara un tipo especial de munición (calibre .40) diseñada para funcionar bajo el agua, lo que en
                extrañas ocasiones está disponible fuera de Madoc.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>SLUG</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1/0/-1</goal>
                <damage>6/5/4</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>15/60/X</range>
                <shots>20</shots>
                <rate>2(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Stone/Iron</en>
                    <es>Piedra/Hierro</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1/0/-1</goal>
                <damage>5/4/3</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>15/60/X</range>
                <shots>20</shots>
                <rate>2(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Plastic/Glass</en>
                    <es>Plástico/Cristal</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1/0/-1</goal>
                <damage>6/5/4</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>4/3/2</range>
                <shots>20</shots>
                <rate>2(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Wood/Ice</en>
                    <es>Madera/Hielo</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1/0/-1</goal>
                <damage>3/2/1</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>15/60/X</range>
                <shots>20</shots>
                <rate>2(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>2000</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>autofeed</other>
            <other>compressedAir</other>
        </others>
    </sabotGun>
    <martechMidgetPalmLaser>
        <id>martechMidgetPalmLaser</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Martech Midget Palm Laser</en>
            <es>Láser de Mano Martech Midget</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A derringer-sized laser, used for selfdefense when it is not possible to carry a larger gun. The Martech
                Midget is the most popular model, manufactured by Martech, a sub-guild of the Engineers. Like all
                lasers, this gun suffers a –2 penalty to its damage effect dice when shooting through thick fog or
                smoke, or anything which could scatter or defuse the coherent beam.
            </en>
            <es>Un láser del tamaño de un Derringer, utilizado para la autodefensa cuando no es posible llevar un arma
                más grande. El Martech Enano es el modelo más popular, fabricado por los Martech, un subclan de los
                Ingenieros. Al igual que todos los láseres, este arma sufre un penalizador de -2 a sus dados de efecto
                de daño cuando se dispara a través de la espesa niebla o del humo, o de cualquier cosa que pudiere
                dispersar o desactivar el haz de luz.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>LASER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3*</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>7</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Ring Laser</en>
                    <es>Anillo Láser</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3*</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>5/10</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
                <extraCost>400</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>200</cost>
        <damageType>laser</damageType>
    </martechMidgetPalmLaser>
    <bannerCabalXaserPistol>
        <id>bannerCabalXaserPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Banner Cabal Xaser Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistola Camarilla del Estandarte Xáser</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>About the size of a medium autofeed slug gun, the Martech Gold (so called because it emits a yellow
                beam) is the standard laser handgun of the Known Worlds. The Martech Amber is a variant (its beam a warm
                orange), tuned to sacrifice damage for a higher ammo capacity. Lasers suffer a –2 penalty to their
                damage effect dice when shooting through thick fog/smoke or anything which could scatter or defuse the
                coherent beam. The Banner Cabal xaser pistol is weaker than a standard laser pistol, but armor offers
                less protection against its shorter wavelength beam (ignore 4 successful armor penetration effect dice
                regardless of the type of armor or its properties). Similarly, the Banner Cabal graser pistol is equally
                powerful to the Martech Gold laser pistol, but completely ignores all physical armors, including bunker
                walls and tank hulls! Energy shields protect against grasers and xasers exactly as they do against
                lasers, however, and the neither weapon suffers from smoke or fog penalties.
            </en>
            <es>Más o menos del tamaño de un arma de fuego de autorecarga mediana, el Martech Oro (llamado así porque
                emite un rayo amarillo) es el arma láser estándar de los Mundos Conocidos. El Martech Ámbar es una
                variante (su haz es de un naranja intenso), enfocado a sacrificar daño a cambio de una capacidad de
                munición superior. Los láseres sufren un penalizador de -2 a sus dados de efecto de daño cuando se
                disparan a través de niebla / humo espesos o a través de cualquier cosa que pudiere dispersar o
                desactivar el haz de luz. La pistola xáser de la camarilla del Estandarte es más débil que una pistola
                láser estándar, pero una armadura ofrece menos protección contra la longitud de onda más corta de su haz
                (ignora 4 éxitos de los dados de efecto de penetración de armadura, sin importar el tipo de armadura o
                sus propiedades). Del mismo modo, la pistola gráser de la camarilla del Estandarte es igual de poderosa
                que la pistola láser Martech Oro, pero ignora completamente todas las armaduras físicas, ¡incluyendo los
                muros de un bunker y el blindaje de un tanque! Sin embargo los escudos de energía protegen contra los
                grásers y xásers del mismo modo que protegen contra los láseres; este arma no sufre penalizadores por el
                humo o la niebla.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>LASER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>10</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <damageType>xaser</damageType>
    </bannerCabalXaserPistol>
    <bannerCabalGraserPistol>
        <id>bannerCabalGraserPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Banner Cabal Graser Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistola Camarilla del Estandarte Graser</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>About the size of a medium autofeed slug gun, the Martech Gold (so called because it emits a yellow
                beam) is the standard laser handgun of the Known Worlds. The Martech Amber is a variant (its beam a warm
                orange), tuned to sacrifice damage for a higher ammo capacity. Lasers suffer a –2 penalty to their
                damage effect dice when shooting through thick fog/smoke or anything which could scatter or defuse the
                coherent beam. The Banner Cabal xaser pistol is weaker than a standard laser pistol, but armor offers
                less protection against its shorter wavelength beam (ignore 4 successful armor penetration effect dice
                regardless of the type of armor or its properties). Similarly, the Banner Cabal graser pistol is equally
                powerful to the Martech Gold laser pistol, but completely ignores all physical armors, including bunker
                walls and tank hulls! Energy shields protect against grasers and xasers exactly as they do against
                lasers, however, and the neither weapon suffers from smoke or fog penalties.
            </en>
            <es>Más o menos del tamaño de un arma de fuego de autorecarga mediana, el Martech Oro (llamado así porque
                emite un rayo amarillo) es el arma láser estándar de los Mundos Conocidos. El Martech Ámbar es una
                variante (su haz es de un naranja intenso), enfocado a sacrificar daño a cambio de una capacidad de
                munición superior. Los láseres sufren un penalizador de -2 a sus dados de efecto de daño cuando se
                disparan a través de niebla / humo espesos o a través de cualquier cosa que pudiere dispersar o
                desactivar el haz de luz. La pistola xáser de la camarilla del Estandarte es más débil que una pistola
                láser estándar, pero una armadura ofrece menos protección contra la longitud de onda más corta de su haz
                (ignora 4 éxitos de los dados de efecto de penetración de armadura, sin importar el tipo de armadura o
                sus propiedades). Del mismo modo, la pistola gráser de la camarilla del Estandarte es igual de poderosa
                que la pistola láser Martech Oro, pero ignora completamente todas las armaduras físicas, ¡incluyendo los
                muros de un bunker y el blindaje de un tanque! Sin embargo los escudos de energía protegen contra los
                grásers y xásers del mismo modo que protegen contra los láseres; este arma no sufre penalizadores por el
                humo o la niebla.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>LASER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>5</shots>
                <rate>3</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>900</cost>
        <damageType>graser</damageType>
    </bannerCabalGraserPistol>
    <bannerCabalXaserRifle>
        <id>bannerCabalXaserRifle</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Banner Cabal Xaser Rifle</en>
            <es>Rifle Camarilla del Estandarte Xáser</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>The Martech Indigo is the most popular laser rifle model, about the size of a sniper rifle. The Martech
                Safire sniper laser is a variant of the Indigo, tuned to sacrifice capacity and rate of fire for an
                extended range. Lasers suffer a –2 penalty to their damage effect dice when shooting through thick fog
                or smoke, or anything which could scatter or defuse the coherent beam. Banner Cabal Xaser Rifles are
                considerably weaker than common laser rifles, but penetrate armor quite efficiently just like its xaser
                pistol cousin (ignore 4 armor protection effect dice successes). Banner Cabal Graser Rifles are only
                slightly weaker then laser rifles, but completely ignore all physical protection! Energy shields protect
                against grasers and xasers, exactly as they do against lasers however, and neither weapon suffers from
                smoke or fog penalties.
            </en>
            <es>El Martech Indigo es el modelo de rifle láser más popular, aproximadamente es del tamaño de un rifle de
                francotirador. El láser de francotirador Martech Safire es una variante del Indigo, centrado en
                sacrificar la capacidad y el ratio de disparo para poder tener un mayor alcance. Los láseres sufren un
                penalizador de -2 a sus dados de efecto de daño cuando se disparan a través de la niebla o humo espesos,
                o a través de cualquier cosa que pudiere dispersaro desactivar el haz de luz. Los rifles xáser de la
                camarilla del Estandarte son considerablemente más débiles que los rifles lásermás comunes, pero son
                capaces de penetrar cualquier armadura con mayor efectividad, al igual que su prima la pistola xáser
                (ignora 4 éxitos de los dados de efectode protección de armadura). Los rifles gráser de la camarilla del
                Estandarte son ligeramente más débiles que los rifles láser, ¡pero ignoran completamente toda protección
                física! Los escudos de energía protegen contra grásers y xásers, exactamente como lo hacen contra los
                láseres, y el arma tampoco sufre los penalizadores por humo o niebla. Láser de Asalto: la carabina
                Varsten Blacklight compite con el Martech Rojo de renombre como el arma láser del soldado. Las carabinas
                Varsten las fabrica la Casa Decados y eso no le gusta al gremio Martech, sobre todo desde que ciertas
                tropas de la aristocracia parece que prefieren los láseres Varsten. El Varsten Blacklight viene con un
                enchufe eléctrico para conectar el arma a un microgenerador de fusión eterno, lo que le proporciona
                munición ilimitada cuando el arma está estacionada. Los láseres sufren un penalizador de -2 a sus dados
                de efecto de daño cuando se disparan a través de niebla/humo espesos o a través de cualquier cosa que
                pudiere dispersar o desactivar el haz de luz.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>LASER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>30/40</range>
                <shots>15</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>1000</cost>
        <damageType>xaser</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </bannerCabalXaserRifle>
    <bannerCabalGraserRifle>
        <id>bannerCabalGraserRifle</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Banner Cabal Graser Rifle</en>
            <es>Rifle Camarilla del Estandarte Gráser</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>The Martech Indigo is the most popular laser rifle model, about the size of a sniper rifle. The Martech
                Safire sniper laser is a variant of the Indigo, tuned to sacrifice capacity and rate of fire for an
                extended range. Lasers suffer a –2 penalty to their damage effect dice when shooting through thick fog
                or smoke, or anything which could scatter or defuse the coherent beam. Banner Cabal Xaser Rifles are
                considerably weaker than common laser rifles, but penetrate armor quite efficiently just like its xaser
                pistol cousin (ignore 4 armor protection effect dice successes). Banner Cabal Graser Rifles are only
                slightly weaker then laser rifles, but completely ignore all physical protection! Energy shields protect
                against grasers and xasers, exactly as they do against lasers however, and neither weapon suffers from
                smoke or fog penalties.
            </en>
            <es>El Martech Indigo es el modelo de rifle láser más popular, aproximadamente es del tamaño de un rifle de
                francotirador. El láser de francotirador Martech Safire es una variante del Indigo, centrado en
                sacrificar la capacidad y el ratio de disparo para poder tener un mayor alcance. Los láseres sufren un
                penalizador de -2 a sus dados de efecto de daño cuando se disparan a través de la niebla o humo espesos,
                o a través de cualquier cosa que pudiere dispersaro desactivar el haz de luz. Los rifles xáser de la
                camarilla del Estandarte son considerablemente más débiles que los rifles lásermás comunes, pero son
                capaces de penetrar cualquier armadura con mayor efectividad, al igual que su prima la pistola xáser
                (ignora 4 éxitos de los dados de efectode protección de armadura). Los rifles gráser de la camarilla del
                Estandarte son ligeramente más débiles que los rifles láser, ¡pero ignoran completamente toda protección
                física! Los escudos de energía protegen contra grásers y xásers, exactamente como lo hacen contra los
                láseres, y el arma tampoco sufre los penalizadores por humo o niebla.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>LASER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>35/45</range>
                <shots>8</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>2000</cost>
        <damageType>graser</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </bannerCabalGraserRifle>
    <sOEHowler>
        <id>sOEHowler</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>SOE Howler</en>
            <es>SOE Howler</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A sonic gun, emitting a concussive force and a high-pitched squeal that damages hearing and cause
                internal injuries in the target. Screechers ignore all forms of armor (including Energy Shields),
                although hearing protection halves the wounds caused (characters with their hands over their ears also
                get this benefit). Various models are known, including the SOE Howler and its smaller but more
                user-friendly Zenic Pacifier.
            </en>
            <es>Un arma sónica que emite un chillido agudo conmocionante que daña la audición y causa lesiones internas
                en el objetivo. Los altavoces sónicos ignoran todas las clases de armadura (incluyendo los Escudos de
                Energía), aunque la protección auditiva reduce a la mitad las heridas que causa el altavoz (los
                personajes que se cubran los oídos con las manos también obtendrán este beneficio). Se conocen varios
                modelos, incluyendo el SOE Howler y su versión más pequeña pero más fácil de usar el Pacificador Zenic.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SCREECHER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>15</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>300</cost>
        <damageType>sonic</damageType>
    </sOEHowler>
    <zenicPacifier>
        <id>zenicPacifier</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Zenic Pacifier</en>
            <es>Pacificador Zenic</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A sonic gun, emitting a concussive force and a high-pitched squeal that damages hearing and cause
                internal injuries in the target. Screechers ignore all forms of armor (including Energy Shields),
                although hearing protection halves the wounds caused (characters with their hands over their ears also
                get this benefit). Various models are known, including the SOE Howler and its smaller but more
                user-friendly Zenic Pacifier.
            </en>
            <es>Un arma sónica que emite un chillido agudo conmocionante que daña la audición y causa lesiones internas
                en el objetivo. Los altavoces sónicos ignoran todas las clases de armadura (incluyendo los Escudos de
                Energía), aunque la protección auditiva reduce a la mitad las heridas que causa el altavoz (los
                personajes que se cubran los oídos con las manos también obtendrán este beneficio). Se conocen varios
                modelos, incluyendo el SOE Howler y su versión más pequeña pero más fácil de usar el Pacificador Zenic.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>SCREECHER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>8/15</range>
                <shots>12</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XS</size>
        <cost>300</cost>
        <damageType>sonic</damageType>
    </zenicPacifier>
    <sOETesla16B50002>
        <id>sOETesla16B50002</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>SOE Tesla 16B50002</en>
            <es>SOE Tesla 16B50002</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Stunners emit a concussive force field which causes nervous system shock, effectively stunning a target
                or knocking her unconscious. If a target takes any damage from a stunner, she must roll Endurance +
                Vigor. If successful, there is no further effect, but if the roll fails, she is stunned for a number of
                turns equal to the damage rolled (although no actual wounds are suffered). A Critical Failure means the
                character falls unconscious for a number of minutes equal to the damage rolled. Stunner damage heals
                naturally after one span (mark stunner damage with an “S” rather than a checkmark on the character’s
                Vitality levels). However, this system shock damage is cumulative with other damage taken. Should a
                stunnedcharacter suffer other damage which takes her below zero Vitality, she dies. These were Second
                Republic riot police weapons. Due to the constant lawsuits brought against police by stunner victims, it
                became illegal to manufacture stunners with too much power. It is rumored that the Engineers have
                developed a more powerful version called SOE Tesla 16B5002, although the Guild refuse to confirm or deny
                whether or not the weapon is theirs. The most popular regular stunner is the Arbogast Sleeper.
            </en>
            <es>Los aturdidores emiten un campo de fuerza de conmoción, lo que provoca una descarga del sistema
                nervioso, que conmociona a un objetivo o lo deja inconsciente. Si un objetivo recibe cualquier tipo de
                daño de un Aturdidor, debe realizar una tirada de Fortaleza + Vigor. Si tiene éxito, no hay efecto, pero
                si la tirada falla, el personaje estará aturdido durante un número de turnos igual al daño que se sacó
                en la tirada (aunque no se sufren heridas realmente). Un fallo crítico significa que el personaje cae
                inconsciente por un número de minutos igual al daño obtenido en la tirada. El daño de un aturdidor se
                sana de forma natural después de una escena (señala el daño de conmoción con una “C” en lugar de marcar
                con una “X” los puntos de vitalidad perdidos). Ahora bien, este daño se acumula con cualquier otro tipo
                de daño recibido. Si un personaje aturdido sufre otros daños que lo lleven a estar por debajo de cero en
                Vitalidad, el personaje muere. Estas fueron las armas de la policía antidisturbios durante la Segunda
                República. Debido a las constantes demandas interpuestas contra la policía por las víctimas de los
                aturdidores, se hizo ilegal fabricar aturdidores con demasiada potencia. Se rumorea que los ingenieros
                han desarrollado una versión más potente llamada SOE Tesla 16B5002, aunque el Gremio se niega a
                confirmar o negar si el arma es de ellos. El aturdidor regular más popular es el Arbogast Sleeper.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>STUNNER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>1</goal>
                <damage>6 (KO)</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>8/15</range>
                <shots>6</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>600</cost>
    </sOETesla16B50002>
    <varsotechModel331>
        <id>varsotechModel331</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Varsotech Model 331</en>
            <es>Varsotech Model 331</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These small palm guns fire a nearly invisible and slightly erratic stream of energy which causes
                destruction to nerve cells and brain matter. If damage exceeds Endurance (or Psi, whichever is higher),
                the target falls unconscious. If damage exceeds the Vitality track, the target is dead. Armor does not
                protect against this damage (although a Psi cloak does). Psychics may defend against neural disrupter
                attacks. To deflect the energy stream, roll Psi + Self Control contested against the attacker’s
                successes. The Neural Disrupter had only just begun production as a prototype when the Fall of the
                Second Republic came to pass. Very few of these weapons are known to exist. The best known examples of
                Neural Disruptors are, the heavy-pistol-sized Varsotech Model 331, and the clunky shotgunsized
                Cunningham Demeantor (Cost: 3700 fb).
            </en>
            <es>Estas pequeñas armas de un palmo de tamaño disparan un flujo de energía casi invisible y ligeramente
                errático que causa la destrucción de las células nerviosas y de la materia cerebral. Si el daño excede
                la puntuación de Fortaleza (o de Psique, la que sea mayor), el objetivo cae inconsciente. Si el daño
                excede la puntuación actual de Vitalidad, el objetivo está muerto. La armadura no protege contra esta
                clase de daños (aunque un Manto de Psique sí que protege contra este artefacto). Los psíquicos pueden
                tratar de defenderse de los ataques de un disruptor neuronal. Para desviar el flujo de la energía,
                realiza una tirada de Psique + Autocontrol enfrentada a los éxitos del atacante. Tan solo se empezó a
                fabricar el Disruptor Neuronal a modo de prototipo cuando aconteció la Caída de la Segunda República. Se
                tiene muy poca constancia de la existencia de estas armas. Los ejemplos más conocidos de Disruptores
                Neuronales son, la pistola de tamaño pesada Modelo 331 Varsotech y la pistola del tamaño de una robusta
                escopeta conocida como la Dementor Cunningham (Coste: 3.700 fénix)
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>8</techLevel>
        <type>ARTIFACT_ENERGY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>–3</goal>
                <damage>5</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>6</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>3000</cost>
        <damageType>neural</damageType>
    </varsotechModel331>
    <cunninghamDemeantor>
        <id>cunninghamDemeantor</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Cunningham Demeantor</en>
            <es>Dementor Cunningham</es>
        </name>
        <techLevel>8</techLevel>
        <type>ARTIFACT_ENERGY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>4</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/40</range>
                <shots>10</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>L</size>
        <cost>3700</cost>
        <damageType>neural</damageType>
        <description>
            <en>These small palm guns fire a nearly invisible and slightly erratic stream of energy which causes
                destruction to nerve cells and brain matter. If damage exceeds Endurance (or Psi, whichever is higher),
                the target falls unconscious. If damage exceeds the Vitality track, the target is dead. Armor does not
                protect against this damage (although a Psi cloak does). Psychics may defend against neural disrupter
                attacks. To deflect the energy stream, roll Psi + Self Control contested against the attacker’s
                successes. The Neural Disrupter had only just begun production as a prototype when the Fall of the
                Second Republic came to pass. Very few of these weapons are known to exist. The best known examples of
                Neural Disruptors are, the heavy-pistol-sized Varsotech Model 331, and the clunky shotgunsized
                Cunningham Demeantor (Cost: 3700 fb).
            </en>
            <es>Estas pequeñas armas de un palmo de tamaño disparan un flujo de energía casi invisible y ligeramente
                errático que causa la destrucción de las células nerviosas y de la materia cerebral. Si el daño excede
                la puntuación de Fortaleza (o de Psique, la que sea mayor), el objetivo cae inconsciente. Si el daño
                excede la puntuación actual de Vitalidad, el objetivo está muerto. La armadura no protege contra esta
                clase de daños (aunque un Manto de Psique sí que protege contra este artefacto). Los psíquicos pueden
                tratar de defenderse de los ataques de un disruptor neuronal. Para desviar el flujo de la energía,
                realiza una tirada de Psique + Autocontrol enfrentada a los éxitos del atacante. Tan solo se empezó a
                fabricar el Disruptor Neuronal a modo de prototipo cuando aconteció la Caída de la Segunda República. Se
                tiene muy poca constancia de la existencia de estas armas. Los ejemplos más conocidos de Disruptores
                Neuronales son, la pistola de tamaño pesada Modelo 331 Varsotech y la pistola del tamaño de una robusta
                escopeta conocida como la Dementor Cunningham (Coste: 3.700 fénix)
            </es>
        </description>
    </cunninghamDemeantor>
    <typicalLtMg>
        <id>typicalLtMg</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Typical Lt. Mg (10mm)</en>
            <es>Ametralladora Ligera Típica (10mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Machineguns come in many sizes, although a few types have come to be established as standard models. The
                Jahnisak 0.40 machinegun, manufactured by the Jahnisak weaponsmiths, is one of the more common support
                weapons currently available, and had users on all sides of the Emperor Wars. Although small and not
                particularly effective, the Jahnisak 0.40 does continue the Jahnisak reputation for ruggedness and
                reliability. Its larger cousin, the Jahnisak 0.51 machinegun, however, has failed to attract the same
                attention and fame. This is partially due to its poorer automatic fire mechanics, which led the
                Jahnisaks to quickly halt marketing the gun. The Jahnisak 16mm Autocannon is a low-tech favorite weapon
                for tanks and other mechanized cavalry. The Furystorm Chaingun is the most widely recognized heavy
                machinegun, built to suppress both personnel and light vehicles from dug-in positions. It barely
                qualifies as a heavy weapon, and is more commonly used as a stationed machinegun in gun-boxes or on
                vehicles.
            </en>
            <es>Existen muchos tamaños de ametralladoras, aunque unos cuantos tipos han llegado a establecerse como
                modelos estándar. La Jahnisak 0.40 es una ametralladora, fabricada por los armeros Jahnisak y es una de
                las armas de apoyo más comunes actualmente disponibles, y la usaron todos los bandos de las Guerras del
                Emperador. Aunque es pequeña y no es particularmente eficaz, la Jahnisak 0.40 mantiene la reputación de
                los Jahnisak como fabricantes de armas robustas y fiables. Su prima más grande, laametralladora Jahnisak
                del 0.51, sin embargo, no ha logrado atraer la misma atención y fama. En parte se debe a su pobre
                mecánica de fuego automática, que llevó a los Jahnisaks a detener a toda prisa la comercialización del
                arma. El Cañón Automático de los Jahnisak de 16mm es el arma de baja tecnología preferida contra tanques
                y contra la caballería mecanizada en general. La Furystorm Chaingun es la ametralladora pesada más
                reconocida universalmente, construida para propinar fuego de supresión contra vehículos personales y
                ligeros desde posiciones de trinchera. Pocas veces se la considera como un arma pesada, y normalmente se
                suele usar más como una ametralladora estacionada en cajas de armas o en los vehículos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>7</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>50/150</range>
                <shots>∞</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>750</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>bipod</other>
            <other>beltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </typicalLtMg>
    <jahnisak040MG>
        <id>jahnisak040MG</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Jahnisak 0.40 MG</en>
            <es>Jahnisak 0.40 MG</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Machineguns come in many sizes, although a few types have come to be established as standard models. The
                Jahnisak 0.40 machinegun, manufactured by the Jahnisak weaponsmiths, is one of the more common support
                weapons currently available, and had users on all sides of the Emperor Wars. Although small and not
                particularly effective, the Jahnisak 0.40 does continue the Jahnisak reputation for ruggedness and
                reliability. Its larger cousin, the Jahnisak 0.51 machinegun, however, has failed to attract the same
                attention and fame. This is partially due to its poorer automatic fire mechanics, which led the
                Jahnisaks to quickly halt marketing the gun. The Jahnisak 16mm Autocannon is a low-tech favorite weapon
                for tanks and other mechanized cavalry. The Furystorm Chaingun is the most widely recognized heavy
                machinegun, built to suppress both personnel and light vehicles from dug-in positions. It barely
                qualifies as a heavy weapon, and is more commonly used as a stationed machinegun in gun-boxes or on
                vehicles.
            </en>
            <es>Existen muchos tamaños de ametralladoras, aunque unos cuantos tipos han llegado a establecerse como
                modelos estándar. La Jahnisak 0.40 es una ametralladora, fabricada por los armeros Jahnisak y es una de
                las armas de apoyo más comunes actualmente disponibles, y la usaron todos los bandos de las Guerras del
                Emperador. Aunque es pequeña y no es particularmente eficaz, la Jahnisak 0.40 mantiene la reputación de
                los Jahnisak como fabricantes de armas robustas y fiables. Su prima más grande, laametralladora Jahnisak
                del 0.51, sin embargo, no ha logrado atraer la misma atención y fama. En parte se debe a su pobre
                mecánica de fuego automática, que llevó a los Jahnisaks a detener a toda prisa la comercialización del
                arma. El Cañón Automático de los Jahnisak de 16mm es el arma de baja tecnología preferida contra tanques
                y contra la caballería mecanizada en general. La Furystorm Chaingun es la ametralladora pesada más
                reconocida universalmente, construida para propinar fuego de supresión contra vehículos personales y
                ligeros desde posiciones de trinchera. Pocas veces se la considera como un arma pesada, y normalmente se
                suele usar más como una ametralladora estacionada en cajas de armas o en los vehículos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>40/120</range>
                <shots>50/∞</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>700</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>bipod</other>
            <other>beltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </jahnisak040MG>
    <jahnisak051MG>
        <id>jahnisak051MG</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Jahnisak 0.51 MG</en>
            <es>Jahnisak 0.51 MG</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Machineguns come in many sizes, although a few types have come to be established as standard models. The
                Jahnisak 0.40 machinegun, manufactured by the Jahnisak weaponsmiths, is one of the more common support
                weapons currently available, and had users on all sides of the Emperor Wars. Although small and not
                particularly effective, the Jahnisak 0.40 does continue the Jahnisak reputation for ruggedness and
                reliability. Its larger cousin, the Jahnisak 0.51 machinegun, however, has failed to attract the same
                attention and fame. This is partially due to its poorer automatic fire mechanics, which led the
                Jahnisaks to quickly halt marketing the gun. The Jahnisak 16mm Autocannon is a low-tech favorite weapon
                for tanks and other mechanized cavalry. The Furystorm Chaingun is the most widely recognized heavy
                machinegun, built to suppress both personnel and light vehicles from dug-in positions. It barely
                qualifies as a heavy weapon, and is more commonly used as a stationed machinegun in gun-boxes or on
                vehicles.
            </en>
            <es>Existen muchos tamaños de ametralladoras, aunque unos cuantos tipos han llegado a establecerse como
                modelos estándar. La Jahnisak 0.40 es una ametralladora, fabricada por los armeros Jahnisak y es una de
                las armas de apoyo más comunes actualmente disponibles, y la usaron todos los bandos de las Guerras del
                Emperador. Aunque es pequeña y no es particularmente eficaz, la Jahnisak 0.40 mantiene la reputación de
                los Jahnisak como fabricantes de armas robustas y fiables. Su prima más grande, laametralladora Jahnisak
                del 0.51, sin embargo, no ha logrado atraer la misma atención y fama. En parte se debe a su pobre
                mecánica de fuego automática, que llevó a los Jahnisaks a detener a toda prisa la comercialización del
                arma. El Cañón Automático de los Jahnisak de 16mm es el arma de baja tecnología preferida contra tanques
                y contra la caballería mecanizada en general. La Furystorm Chaingun es la ametralladora pesada más
                reconocida universalmente, construida para propinar fuego de supresión contra vehículos personales y
                ligeros desde posiciones de trinchera. Pocas veces se la considera como un arma pesada, y normalmente se
                suele usar más como una ametralladora estacionada en cajas de armas o en los vehículos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>7</damage>
                <strength>3</strength>
                <range>50/150</range>
                <shots>∞</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>900</cost>
        <others>
            <other>tripod</other>
            <other>beltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </jahnisak051MG>
    <jahniAutocannon>
        <id>jahniAutocannon</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Jahnisak Autocannon (16mm)</en>
            <es>Auto cañón Jahnisak (16mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Machineguns come in many sizes, although a few types have come to be established as standard models. The
                Jahnisak 0.40 machinegun, manufactured by the Jahnisak weaponsmiths, is one of the more common support
                weapons currently available, and had users on all sides of the Emperor Wars. Although small and not
                particularly effective, the Jahnisak 0.40 does continue the Jahnisak reputation for ruggedness and
                reliability. Its larger cousin, the Jahnisak 0.51 machinegun, however, has failed to attract the same
                attention and fame. This is partially due to its poorer automatic fire mechanics, which led the
                Jahnisaks to quickly halt marketing the gun. The Jahnisak 16mm Autocannon is a low-tech favorite weapon
                for tanks and other mechanized cavalry. The Furystorm Chaingun is the most widely recognized heavy
                machinegun, built to suppress both personnel and light vehicles from dug-in positions. It barely
                qualifies as a heavy weapon, and is more commonly used as a stationed machinegun in gun-boxes or on
                vehicles.
            </en>
            <es>Existen muchos tamaños de ametralladoras, aunque unos cuantos tipos han llegado a establecerse como
                modelos estándar. La Jahnisak 0.40 es una ametralladora, fabricada por los armeros Jahnisak y es una de
                las armas de apoyo más comunes actualmente disponibles, y la usaron todos los bandos de las Guerras del
                Emperador. Aunque es pequeña y no es particularmente eficaz, la Jahnisak 0.40 mantiene la reputación de
                los Jahnisak como fabricantes de armas robustas y fiables. Su prima más grande, laametralladora Jahnisak
                del 0.51, sin embargo, no ha logrado atraer la misma atención y fama. En parte se debe a su pobre
                mecánica de fuego automática, que llevó a los Jahnisaks a detener a toda prisa la comercialización del
                arma. El Cañón Automático de los Jahnisak de 16mm es el arma de baja tecnología preferida contra tanques
                y contra la caballería mecanizada en general. La Furystorm Chaingun es la ametralladora pesada más
                reconocida universalmente, construida para propinar fuego de supresión contra vehículos personales y
                ligeros desde posiciones de trinchera. Pocas veces se la considera como un arma pesada, y normalmente se
                suele usar más como una ametralladora estacionada en cajas de armas o en los vehículos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>9</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>60/175</range>
                <shots>∞</shots>
                <rate>3(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>1200</cost>
        <others>
            <other>tripod</other>
            <other>beltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </jahniAutocannon>
    <furystormChaingun>
        <id>furystormChaingun</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Furystorm Chaingun (20mm)</en>
            <es>Furystorm Chaingun (20mm)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Machineguns come in many sizes, although a few types have come to be established as standard models. The
                Jahnisak 0.40 machinegun, manufactured by the Jahnisak weaponsmiths, is one of the more common support
                weapons currently available, and had users on all sides of the Emperor Wars. Although small and not
                particularly effective, the Jahnisak 0.40 does continue the Jahnisak reputation for ruggedness and
                reliability. Its larger cousin, the Jahnisak 0.51 machinegun, however, has failed to attract the same
                attention and fame. This is partially due to its poorer automatic fire mechanics, which led the
                Jahnisaks to quickly halt marketing the gun. The Jahnisak 16mm Autocannon is a low-tech favorite weapon
                for tanks and other mechanized cavalry. The Furystorm Chaingun is the most widely recognized heavy
                machinegun, built to suppress both personnel and light vehicles from dug-in positions. It barely
                qualifies as a heavy weapon, and is more commonly used as a stationed machinegun in gun-boxes or on
                vehicles.
            </en>
            <es>Existen muchos tamaños de ametralladoras, aunque unos cuantos tipos han llegado a establecerse como
                modelos estándar. La Jahnisak 0.40 es una ametralladora, fabricada por los armeros Jahnisak y es una de
                las armas de apoyo más comunes actualmente disponibles, y la usaron todos los bandos de las Guerras del
                Emperador. Aunque es pequeña y no es particularmente eficaz, la Jahnisak 0.40 mantiene la reputación de
                los Jahnisak como fabricantes de armas robustas y fiables. Su prima más grande, laametralladora Jahnisak
                del 0.51, sin embargo, no ha logrado atraer la misma atención y fama. En parte se debe a su pobre
                mecánica de fuego automática, que llevó a los Jahnisaks a detener a toda prisa la comercialización del
                arma. El Cañón Automático de los Jahnisak de 16mm es el arma de baja tecnología preferida contra tanques
                y contra la caballería mecanizada en general. La Furystorm Chaingun es la ametralladora pesada más
                reconocida universalmente, construida para propinar fuego de supresión contra vehículos personales y
                ligeros desde posiciones de trinchera. Pocas veces se la considera como un arma pesada, y normalmente se
                suele usar más como una ametralladora estacionada en cajas de armas o en los vehículos.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>11</damage>
                <strength>8</strength>
                <range>75/200</range>
                <shots>∞</shots>
                <rate>(A)</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XXL</size>
        <cost>1500</cost>
        <others>
            <other>beltfeed</other>
        </others>
    </furystormChaingun>
    <deamasineTerrakin>
        <id>deamasineTerrakin</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Deamasine Terrakin (Borer)</en>
            <es>Deamasine Terrakin (Perforante)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Weapons designed specifically to defeat battle armored vehicles are rare in the Phoenix Empire, although
                they do exist. The Terrakin Borer is a single-shot anti-tank “can-opener” sniper rifle, classified as a
                heavy weapon. The Deamasine weaponsmith family of Midian specializes in these high-velocity, largebore
                firearms. Designed to punch through thick armor, these weapons are ideally used against foes in cover,
                heavy armor, or in vehicles. Its ammo (16mm) is a specially designed ultra-hard bullet, coated to punch
                through metal and ceramsteel. The Bosark Cannoneer is a Second Republic weapon that was intended for
                large game hunting, however it continues to serve adequately to this day and is frequently used as an
                anti-armor weapon. It has seen considerable use on Stigmata where it is used to bring down the larger
                Symbiot creatures.
            </en>
            <es>Armas diseñadas específicamente para derrotar a los vehículos de batalla blindados que rara vez podrás
                encontrar en el Imperio del Fénix, a pesar de que existan. El Terrakin Borer es un rifle de
                francotirador antitanque “abrelatas” de un solo disparo, clasificado como arma pesada. La familia de
                armeros Deamasine de Madián está especializada en estas armas de fuego de gran calibre y de alta
                velocidad. Diseñadas para atravesar una armadura gruesa, estas armas suelen emplearse contra los
                enemigos bajo cobertura, contra armaduras pesadas, o contra vehículos. Su munición (16 mm) es un diseño
                especial de bala ultra dura, revestida para atravesar el metal y la acerámica. El Cañonero Bosark es un
                arma de la Segunda República que se diseñó para la caza mayor, sin embargo, continúa siendo utilizada a
                día de hoy, y suele emplearse como un arma anti-armadura. Se usó bastante en Estigmata, donde se empleó
                para derrotar a las criaturas simbiontes más grandes.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>10</damage>
                <strength>7</strength>
                <range>60/175</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>1000</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>bipod</other>
            <other>sight2</other>
        </others>
    </deamasineTerrakin>
    <bosarkCannoneer>
        <id>bosarkCannoneer</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Bosark Cannoneer (Borer)</en>
            <es>Cañonero Bosark (Perforante)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Weapons designed specifically to defeat battle armored vehicles are rare in the Phoenix Empire, although
                they do exist. The Terrakin Borer is a single-shot anti-tank “can-opener” sniper rifle, classified as a
                heavy weapon. The Deamasine weaponsmith family of Midian specializes in these high-velocity, largebore
                firearms. Designed to punch through thick armor, these weapons are ideally used against foes in cover,
                heavy armor, or in vehicles. Its ammo (16mm) is a specially designed ultra-hard bullet, coated to punch
                through metal and ceramsteel. The Bosark Cannoneer is a Second Republic weapon that was intended for
                large game hunting, however it continues to serve adequately to this day and is frequently used as an
                anti-armor weapon. It has seen considerable use on Stigmata where it is used to bring down the larger
                Symbiot creatures.
            </en>
            <es>Armas diseñadas específicamente para derrotar a los vehículos de batalla blindados que rara vez podrás
                encontrar en el Imperio del Fénix, a pesar de que existan. El Terrakin Borer es un rifle de
                francotirador antitanque “abrelatas” de un solo disparo, clasificado como arma pesada. La familia de
                armeros Deamasine de Madián está especializada en estas armas de fuego de gran calibre y de alta
                velocidad. Diseñadas para atravesar una armadura gruesa, estas armas suelen emplearse contra los
                enemigos bajo cobertura, contra armaduras pesadas, o contra vehículos. Su munición (16 mm) es un diseño
                especial de bala ultra dura, revestida para atravesar el metal y la acerámica. El Cañonero Bosark es un
                arma de la Segunda República que se diseñó para la caza mayor, sin embargo, continúa siendo utilizada a
                día de hoy, y suele emplearse como un arma anti-armadura. Se usó bastante en Estigmata, donde se empleó
                para derrotar a las criaturas simbiontes más grandes.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1</goal>
                <damage>10</damage>
                <strength>7</strength>
                <range>75/200</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>2000</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>bipod</other>
            <other>sight4</other>
        </others>
    </bosarkCannoneer>
    <goboLobberJetPistol>
        <id>goboLobberJetPistol</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol</en>
            <es>Pistola a Chorro Gobo Lobber</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rocketeer weapons fire either guided (missile launchers) or unguided explosive rockets; most are little
                more than tubes with a firing mechanism. The Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol fires jet-propelled Blast Pellets,
                and is manufactured by the Gobo weaponsmiths guild of Bannockburn. While this bulky pistol is not very
                concealable, its small size makes it a favorite of mercenaries who like to destroy things. The Gobo
                Garbage Chucker Cluster Gun, a rifle-sized version of the Jet Pistol, spray a cluster of five Blast
                Pellets over a 2-meter area, causing massive damage and suppressing anyone in the vicinity. It Is a
                single-fire rocketeer, emptying it’s entire ammo storage with a single pull on the trigger. This weapon
                is favored by those who need to clean out an area quickly without regard for making a mess. The
                Nightstorm is a handheld rocket launcher about twice the size of a common shotgun, is the most famous
                rocketeer weapon. It is manufactured by the Muster Guild, who are quite fond of this model, as it won
                them the decisive victory during the Emperor Wars at the Battle of Barga Gully on Sutek. Another popular
                model is the Model Hazat R–25 missile launcher, a reliable personal artillery weapon employed in large
                numbers on the Hira front. Typically, this weapon is manned by two soldiers, one being the shooter and
                the other acting as a spotter and loader, although a single firer can operate the weapon if necessary
                (it just takes longer to reload and the R–25 is quite heavy to lug around on your own). Another two-team
                missile launcher is the Dreskel Bazooka, a multi-purpose missile launcher that has proven effective
                against, land, sea, and air vehicles, fortifications, starships, and infantry alike.
            </en>
            <es>Incluyen tanto las de misiles guiados (lanzamisiles) como las de misiles no guiados; la mayoría son poco
                más que unos simples tubos con un mecanismo de disparo. La pistola a chorro Gobo Lobber dispara
                perdigones explosivos a chorro, y la fabrica el gremio de armeros de Gobo en Bannockburn. Aunque esta
                voluminosa pistola no pueda ocultarse así como así, su pequeño tamaño hace que sea una de las armas
                favoritas de los mercenarios a los que les guste destruir cosas. El arma de racimo Gobo Garbage Chucker,
                es una versión de la pistola a chorro con tamaño de rifle, que esparce un racimo de cinco perdigones
                explosivos sobre un área de 2 metros, causando daño masivo y también ofrece fuego de supresión sobre
                cualquiera que esté cerca. Es un arma de cohetes de un solo disparo, vaciando todo su cargador con tan
                solo apretar el gatillo. Este arma es la idónea para aquellos que necesitan limpiar un área rápidamente
                sin preocuparse de hacer un destrozo. El Nightstorm es un lanzacohetes portátil aproximadamente con el
                doble del tamaño de una escopeta común; es el arma de cohetes más famosa. La fabrica el gremio de la
                Asamblea, que son muy aficionados a este modelo, dado que les consiguió la victoria decisiva durante las
                Guerras del Emperador en la batalla de Barga Gully en Sutek. Otro modelo popular es el lanzamisiles
                modelo Hazat R-25, un arma de artillería personal fiable, muy utilizada en el frente de Hira. Por lo
                general, este arma la manejan dos soldados, uno es el tirador y el otro es un observador y el que
                recarga el arma, aunque un solo tirador se las puede apañar con el arma si es necesario (sólo se
                necesitará más tiempo para recargar y el R-25 es bastante pesado como para cargarlo por tu cuenta). Otro
                lanzamisiles de dos soldados es el Bazooka Dreskel, un lanzamisiles multiuso que ha demostrado su
                eficacia contra vehículos de tierra, mar y aire, fortificaciones, naves espaciales, y contra la
                infantería por igual.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>ROCKETEER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>6 (1m)</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>2</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>300</cost>
        <damageType>plasma</damageType>
    </goboLobberJetPistol>
    <goboGarbageChucker>
        <id>goboGarbageChucker</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Gobo Garbage Chucker</en>
            <es>Gobo Garbage Chucker</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rocketeer weapons fire either guided (missile launchers) or unguided explosive rockets; most are little
                more than tubes with a firing mechanism. The Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol fires jet-propelled Blast Pellets,
                and is manufactured by the Gobo weaponsmiths guild of Bannockburn. While this bulky pistol is not very
                concealable, its small size makes it a favorite of mercenaries who like to destroy things. The Gobo
                Garbage Chucker Cluster Gun, a rifle-sized version of the Jet Pistol, spray a cluster of five Blast
                Pellets over a 2-meter area, causing massive damage and suppressing anyone in the vicinity. It Is a
                single-fire rocketeer, emptying it’s entire ammo storage with a single pull on the trigger. This weapon
                is favored by those who need to clean out an area quickly without regard for making a mess. The
                Nightstorm is a handheld rocket launcher about twice the size of a common shotgun, is the most famous
                rocketeer weapon. It is manufactured by the Muster Guild, who are quite fond of this model, as it won
                them the decisive victory during the Emperor Wars at the Battle of Barga Gully on Sutek. Another popular
                model is the Model Hazat R–25 missile launcher, a reliable personal artillery weapon employed in large
                numbers on the Hira front. Typically, this weapon is manned by two soldiers, one being the shooter and
                the other acting as a spotter and loader, although a single firer can operate the weapon if necessary
                (it just takes longer to reload and the R–25 is quite heavy to lug around on your own). Another two-team
                missile launcher is the Dreskel Bazooka, a multi-purpose missile launcher that has proven effective
                against, land, sea, and air vehicles, fortifications, starships, and infantry alike.
            </en>
            <es>Incluyen tanto las de misiles guiados (lanzamisiles) como las de misiles no guiados; la mayoría son poco
                más que unos simples tubos con un mecanismo de disparo. La pistola a chorro Gobo Lobber dispara
                perdigones explosivos a chorro, y la fabrica el gremio de armeros de Gobo en Bannockburn. Aunque esta
                voluminosa pistola no pueda ocultarse así como así, su pequeño tamaño hace que sea una de las armas
                favoritas de los mercenarios a los que les guste destruir cosas. El arma de racimo Gobo Garbage Chucker,
                es una versión de la pistola a chorro con tamaño de rifle, que esparce un racimo de cinco perdigones
                explosivos sobre un área de 2 metros, causando daño masivo y también ofrece fuego de supresión sobre
                cualquiera que esté cerca. Es un arma de cohetes de un solo disparo, vaciando todo su cargador con tan
                solo apretar el gatillo. Este arma es la idónea para aquellos que necesitan limpiar un área rápidamente
                sin preocuparse de hacer un destrozo. El Nightstorm es un lanzacohetes portátil aproximadamente con el
                doble del tamaño de una escopeta común; es el arma de cohetes más famosa. La fabrica el gremio de la
                Asamblea, que son muy aficionados a este modelo, dado que les consiguió la victoria decisiva durante las
                Guerras del Emperador en la batalla de Barga Gully en Sutek. Otro modelo popular es el lanzamisiles
                modelo Hazat R-25, un arma de artillería personal fiable, muy utilizada en el frente de Hira. Por lo
                general, este arma la manejan dos soldados, uno es el tirador y el otro es un observador y el que
                recarga el arma, aunque un solo tirador se las puede apañar con el arma si es necesario (sólo se
                necesitará más tiempo para recargar y el R-25 es bastante pesado como para cargarlo por tu cuenta). Otro
                lanzamisiles de dos soldados es el Bazooka Dreskel, un lanzamisiles multiuso que ha demostrado su
                eficacia contra vehículos de tierra, mar y aire, fortificaciones, naves espaciales, y contra la
                infantería por igual.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>ROCKETEER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>6 (2m)</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>5</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <damageType>plasma</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </goboGarbageChucker>
    <musterNightstorm>
        <id>musterNightstorm</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Muster Nightstorm</en>
            <es>Nightstorm de la Asamblea</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rocketeer weapons fire either guided (missile launchers) or unguided explosive rockets; most are little
                more than tubes with a firing mechanism. The Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol fires jet-propelled Blast Pellets,
                and is manufactured by the Gobo weaponsmiths guild of Bannockburn. While this bulky pistol is not very
                concealable, its small size makes it a favorite of mercenaries who like to destroy things. The Gobo
                Garbage Chucker Cluster Gun, a rifle-sized version of the Jet Pistol, spray a cluster of five Blast
                Pellets over a 2-meter area, causing massive damage and suppressing anyone in the vicinity. It Is a
                single-fire rocketeer, emptying it’s entire ammo storage with a single pull on the trigger. This weapon
                is favored by those who need to clean out an area quickly without regard for making a mess. The
                Nightstorm is a handheld rocket launcher about twice the size of a common shotgun, is the most famous
                rocketeer weapon. It is manufactured by the Muster Guild, who are quite fond of this model, as it won
                them the decisive victory during the Emperor Wars at the Battle of Barga Gully on Sutek. Another popular
                model is the Model Hazat R–25 missile launcher, a reliable personal artillery weapon employed in large
                numbers on the Hira front. Typically, this weapon is manned by two soldiers, one being the shooter and
                the other acting as a spotter and loader, although a single firer can operate the weapon if necessary
                (it just takes longer to reload and the R–25 is quite heavy to lug around on your own). Another two-team
                missile launcher is the Dreskel Bazooka, a multi-purpose missile launcher that has proven effective
                against, land, sea, and air vehicles, fortifications, starships, and infantry alike.
            </en>
            <es>Incluyen tanto las de misiles guiados (lanzamisiles) como las de misiles no guiados; la mayoría son poco
                más que unos simples tubos con un mecanismo de disparo. La pistola a chorro Gobo Lobber dispara
                perdigones explosivos a chorro, y la fabrica el gremio de armeros de Gobo en Bannockburn. Aunque esta
                voluminosa pistola no pueda ocultarse así como así, su pequeño tamaño hace que sea una de las armas
                favoritas de los mercenarios a los que les guste destruir cosas. El arma de racimo Gobo Garbage Chucker,
                es una versión de la pistola a chorro con tamaño de rifle, que esparce un racimo de cinco perdigones
                explosivos sobre un área de 2 metros, causando daño masivo y también ofrece fuego de supresión sobre
                cualquiera que esté cerca. Es un arma de cohetes de un solo disparo, vaciando todo su cargador con tan
                solo apretar el gatillo. Este arma es la idónea para aquellos que necesitan limpiar un área rápidamente
                sin preocuparse de hacer un destrozo. El Nightstorm es un lanzacohetes portátil aproximadamente con el
                doble del tamaño de una escopeta común; es el arma de cohetes más famosa. La fabrica el gremio de la
                Asamblea, que son muy aficionados a este modelo, dado que les consiguió la victoria decisiva durante las
                Guerras del Emperador en la batalla de Barga Gully en Sutek. Otro modelo popular es el lanzamisiles
                modelo Hazat R-25, un arma de artillería personal fiable, muy utilizada en el frente de Hira. Por lo
                general, este arma la manejan dos soldados, uno es el tirador y el otro es un observador y el que
                recarga el arma, aunque un solo tirador se las puede apañar con el arma si es necesario (sólo se
                necesitará más tiempo para recargar y el R-25 es bastante pesado como para cargarlo por tu cuenta). Otro
                lanzamisiles de dos soldados es el Bazooka Dreskel, un lanzamisiles multiuso que ha demostrado su
                eficacia contra vehículos de tierra, mar y aire, fortificaciones, naves espaciales, y contra la
                infantería por igual.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>ROCKETEER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>9 (3m)</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>20/30</range>
                <shots>5</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
        <random>
            <restrictedFactions>muster</restrictedFactions>
        </random>
    </musterNightstorm>
    <modelHazatR25>
        <id>modelHazatR25</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Model Hazat R-25 (HEAT)</en>
            <es>Modelo Hazat R-25 (CALOR)</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rocketeer weapons fire either guided (missile launchers) or unguided explosive rockets; most are little
                more than tubes with a firing mechanism. The Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol fires jet-propelled Blast Pellets,
                and is manufactured by the Gobo weaponsmiths guild of Bannockburn. While this bulky pistol is not very
                concealable, its small size makes it a favorite of mercenaries who like to destroy things. The Gobo
                Garbage Chucker Cluster Gun, a rifle-sized version of the Jet Pistol, spray a cluster of five Blast
                Pellets over a 2-meter area, causing massive damage and suppressing anyone in the vicinity. It Is a
                single-fire rocketeer, emptying it’s entire ammo storage with a single pull on the trigger. This weapon
                is favored by those who need to clean out an area quickly without regard for making a mess. The
                Nightstorm is a handheld rocket launcher about twice the size of a common shotgun, is the most famous
                rocketeer weapon. It is manufactured by the Muster Guild, who are quite fond of this model, as it won
                them the decisive victory during the Emperor Wars at the Battle of Barga Gully on Sutek. Another popular
                model is the Model Hazat R–25 missile launcher, a reliable personal artillery weapon employed in large
                numbers on the Hira front. Typically, this weapon is manned by two soldiers, one being the shooter and
                the other acting as a spotter and loader, although a single firer can operate the weapon if necessary
                (it just takes longer to reload and the R–25 is quite heavy to lug around on your own). Another two-team
                missile launcher is the Dreskel Bazooka, a multi-purpose missile launcher that has proven effective
                against, land, sea, and air vehicles, fortifications, starships, and infantry alike.
            </en>
            <es>Incluyen tanto las de misiles guiados (lanzamisiles) como las de misiles no guiados; la mayoría son poco
                más que unos simples tubos con un mecanismo de disparo. La pistola a chorro Gobo Lobber dispara
                perdigones explosivos a chorro, y la fabrica el gremio de armeros de Gobo en Bannockburn. Aunque esta
                voluminosa pistola no pueda ocultarse así como así, su pequeño tamaño hace que sea una de las armas
                favoritas de los mercenarios a los que les guste destruir cosas. El arma de racimo Gobo Garbage Chucker,
                es una versión de la pistola a chorro con tamaño de rifle, que esparce un racimo de cinco perdigones
                explosivos sobre un área de 2 metros, causando daño masivo y también ofrece fuego de supresión sobre
                cualquiera que esté cerca. Es un arma de cohetes de un solo disparo, vaciando todo su cargador con tan
                solo apretar el gatillo. Este arma es la idónea para aquellos que necesitan limpiar un área rápidamente
                sin preocuparse de hacer un destrozo. El Nightstorm es un lanzacohetes portátil aproximadamente con el
                doble del tamaño de una escopeta común; es el arma de cohetes más famosa. La fabrica el gremio de la
                Asamblea, que son muy aficionados a este modelo, dado que les consiguió la victoria decisiva durante las
                Guerras del Emperador en la batalla de Barga Gully en Sutek. Otro modelo popular es el lanzamisiles
                modelo Hazat R-25, un arma de artillería personal fiable, muy utilizada en el frente de Hira. Por lo
                general, este arma la manejan dos soldados, uno es el tirador y el otro es un observador y el que
                recarga el arma, aunque un solo tirador se las puede apañar con el arma si es necesario (sólo se
                necesitará más tiempo para recargar y el R-25 es bastante pesado como para cargarlo por tu cuenta). Otro
                lanzamisiles de dos soldados es el Bazooka Dreskel, un lanzamisiles multiuso que ha demostrado su
                eficacia contra vehículos de tierra, mar y aire, fortificaciones, naves espaciales, y contra la
                infantería por igual.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>ROCKETEER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>18(3)</damage>
                <strength>4</strength>
                <range>75/200</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>800</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
        <random>
            <restrictedFactions>hazat</restrictedFactions>
        </random>
    </modelHazatR25>
    <dreskelBazooka>
        <id>dreskelBazooka</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Dreskel Bazooka</en>
            <es>Bazooka Dreskel</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Rocketeer weapons fire either guided (missile launchers) or unguided explosive rockets; most are little
                more than tubes with a firing mechanism. The Gobo Lobber Jet Pistol fires jet-propelled Blast Pellets,
                and is manufactured by the Gobo weaponsmiths guild of Bannockburn. While this bulky pistol is not very
                concealable, its small size makes it a favorite of mercenaries who like to destroy things. The Gobo
                Garbage Chucker Cluster Gun, a rifle-sized version of the Jet Pistol, spray a cluster of five Blast
                Pellets over a 2-meter area, causing massive damage and suppressing anyone in the vicinity. It Is a
                single-fire rocketeer, emptying it’s entire ammo storage with a single pull on the trigger. This weapon
                is favored by those who need to clean out an area quickly without regard for making a mess. The
                Nightstorm is a handheld rocket launcher about twice the size of a common shotgun, is the most famous
                rocketeer weapon. It is manufactured by the Muster Guild, who are quite fond of this model, as it won
                them the decisive victory during the Emperor Wars at the Battle of Barga Gully on Sutek. Another popular
                model is the Model Hazat R–25 missile launcher, a reliable personal artillery weapon employed in large
                numbers on the Hira front. Typically, this weapon is manned by two soldiers, one being the shooter and
                the other acting as a spotter and loader, although a single firer can operate the weapon if necessary
                (it just takes longer to reload and the R–25 is quite heavy to lug around on your own). Another two-team
                missile launcher is the Dreskel Bazooka, a multi-purpose missile launcher that has proven effective
                against, land, sea, and air vehicles, fortifications, starships, and infantry alike.
            </en>
            <es>Incluyen tanto las de misiles guiados (lanzamisiles) como las de misiles no guiados; la mayoría son poco
                más que unos simples tubos con un mecanismo de disparo. La pistola a chorro Gobo Lobber dispara
                perdigones explosivos a chorro, y la fabrica el gremio de armeros de Gobo en Bannockburn. Aunque esta
                voluminosa pistola no pueda ocultarse así como así, su pequeño tamaño hace que sea una de las armas
                favoritas de los mercenarios a los que les guste destruir cosas. El arma de racimo Gobo Garbage Chucker,
                es una versión de la pistola a chorro con tamaño de rifle, que esparce un racimo de cinco perdigones
                explosivos sobre un área de 2 metros, causando daño masivo y también ofrece fuego de supresión sobre
                cualquiera que esté cerca. Es un arma de cohetes de un solo disparo, vaciando todo su cargador con tan
                solo apretar el gatillo. Este arma es la idónea para aquellos que necesitan limpiar un área rápidamente
                sin preocuparse de hacer un destrozo. El Nightstorm es un lanzacohetes portátil aproximadamente con el
                doble del tamaño de una escopeta común; es el arma de cohetes más famosa. La fabrica el gremio de la
                Asamblea, que son muy aficionados a este modelo, dado que les consiguió la victoria decisiva durante las
                Guerras del Emperador en la batalla de Barga Gully en Sutek. Otro modelo popular es el lanzamisiles
                modelo Hazat R-25, un arma de artillería personal fiable, muy utilizada en el frente de Hira. Por lo
                general, este arma la manejan dos soldados, uno es el tirador y el otro es un observador y el que
                recarga el arma, aunque un solo tirador se las puede apañar con el arma si es necesario (sólo se
                necesitará más tiempo para recargar y el R-25 es bastante pesado como para cargarlo por tu cuenta). Otro
                lanzamisiles de dos soldados es el Bazooka Dreskel, un lanzamisiles multiuso que ha demostrado su
                eficacia contra vehículos de tierra, mar y aire, fortificaciones, naves espaciales, y contra la
                infantería por igual.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>ROCKETEER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>18 (3)</damage>
                <strength>5</strength>
                <range>65/175</range>
                <shots>1</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>750</cost>
        <damageType>hard</damageType>
    </dreskelBazooka>
    <dreskelBombardier>
        <id>dreskelBombardier</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Dreskel Bombardier</en>
            <es>Dreskel Bombardier</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Most slug rifles of the 51st century can be fitted with a grenade launcher below the barrel. This gives
                the shooter the choice of weapon to use without needing to switch between his armaments. The Masseri
                Devastator is a cheap and popular model, although the Hawkwood family model Lion Roar is more reliable
                and accurate.The Dreskel Bombardier is a singular weapon (i.e. not attacked to a rifle). It has a large
                revolving drum magazine giving it a great ammo capacity, although the bulky construction makes the
                Bombardier somewhat inaccurate.
            </en>
            <es>La mayoría de los rifles del Siglo 51 pueden equiparse con un lanzagranadas por debajo del cañón. Esto
                le da al tirador la posibilidad de usar otro arma sin necesidad de cambiar de arma. El Masseri
                Devastator es un modelo barato y popular, aunque el modelo de la familia Hawkwood “Rugido de León” es
                más fiable y preciso. El Dreskel Bombardier es un arma singular (es decir, no se acopla a un rifle).
                Tiene un gran cargador de tambor giratorio que le da una enorme capacidad de munición, pero su aparatoso
                diseño hace que el Bombardier sea algo impreciso.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE_LAUNCHER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>Grenade</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>7</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>revolver</other>
        </others>
    </dreskelBombardier>
    <hawkwoodLionRoar>
        <id>hawkwoodLionRoar</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Hawkwood Lion Roar</en>
            <es>Hawkwood "Rugido de León"</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Most slug rifles of the 51st century can be fitted with a grenade launcher below the barrel. This gives
                the shooter the choice of weapon to use without needing to switch between his armaments. The Masseri
                Devastator is a cheap and popular model, although the Hawkwood family model Lion Roar is more reliable
                and accurate.The Dreskel Bombardier is a singular weapon (i.e. not attacked to a rifle). It has a large
                revolving drum magazine giving it a great ammo capacity, although the bulky construction makes the
                Bombardier somewhat inaccurate.
            </en>
            <es>La mayoría de los rifles del Siglo 51 pueden equiparse con un lanzagranadas por debajo del cañón. Esto
                le da al tirador la posibilidad de usar otro arma sin necesidad de cambiar de arma. El Masseri
                Devastator es un modelo barato y popular, aunque el modelo de la familia Hawkwood “Rugido de León” es
                más fiable y preciso. El Dreskel Bombardier es un arma singular (es decir, no se acopla a un rifle).
                Tiene un gran cargador de tambor giratorio que le da una enorme capacidad de munición, pero su aparatoso
                diseño hace que el Bombardier sea algo impreciso.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE_LAUNCHER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>–1</goal>
                <damage>Grenade</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>4</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>500</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>pumpfeed</other>
        </others>
    </hawkwoodLionRoar>
    <masseriDevastator>
        <id>masseriDevastator</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Masseri Devastator</en>
            <es>Masseri Devastator</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Most slug rifles of the 51st century can be fitted with a grenade launcher below the barrel. This gives
                the shooter the choice of weapon to use without needing to switch between his armaments. The Masseri
                Devastator is a cheap and popular model, although the Hawkwood family model Lion Roar is more reliable
                and accurate.The Dreskel Bombardier is a singular weapon (i.e. not attacked to a rifle). It has a large
                revolving drum magazine giving it a great ammo capacity, although the bulky construction makes the
                Bombardier somewhat inaccurate.
            </en>
            <es>La mayoría de los rifles del Siglo 51 pueden equiparse con un lanzagranadas por debajo del cañón. Esto
                le da al tirador la posibilidad de usar otro arma sin necesidad de cambiar de arma. El Masseri
                Devastator es un modelo barato y popular, aunque el modelo de la familia Hawkwood “Rugido de León” es
                más fiable y preciso. El Dreskel Bombardier es un arma singular (es decir, no se acopla a un rifle).
                Tiene un gran cargador de tambor giratorio que le da una enorme capacidad de munición, pero su aparatoso
                diseño hace que el Bombardier sea algo impreciso.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE_LAUNCHER</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>slugGuns</skill>
                <goal>-2</goal>
                <damage>Grenade</damage>
                <strength>2</strength>
                <range>15/25</range>
                <shots>4</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>M</size>
        <cost>450</cost>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
            <other>pumpfeed</other>
        </others>
    </masseriDevastator>
    <gatlingLaser>
        <id>gatlingLaser</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Gatling Laser</en>
            <es>Láser Gatling</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Essentially five laser rifles linked together, this is the most prevalent energy support weapon In the
                Known Worlds (but that doesn’t make it common). Up to shots are fired as a single action (one goal
                roll), at the same target (DMG is rolled separately for each shot). When fired at energy shields, there
                is a chance the force field burns out, similar to long bursts hitting energy shields (p. 320). The
                weapon is loaded with 5 fusion cells.
            </en>
            <es>Esencialmente son cinco rifles láser dispuestos en conjunto, lo que hace de este arma el arma de energía
                de apoyo más prevalente en los Mundos Conocidos (pero eso no la hace más común). El arma dispara cinco
                veces en una sola acción (una tirada de acierto), al mismo objetivo (el daño se lanza por separado por
                cada disparo). Cuando se dispara contra escudos de energía, existe la posibilidad de que el campo de
                fuerza se sobrecaliente, similar a una ráfaga larga que impacta contra los escudos de energía (página
                266). El arma se carga con 5 pilas de fusión.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>+1</goal>
                <damage>7</damage>
                <strength>0</strength>
                <range>30/80</range>
                <shots>115</shots>
                <rate>2*</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XL</size>
        <cost>2500</cost>
        <damageType>laser</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </gatlingLaser>
    <blasterCannon>
        <id>blasterCannon</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Blaster Cannon</en>
            <es>Cañón Blaster</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Blaster Cannons are antitank guns, too big to be carried. Usually they are mounted on armored vehicles
                or set up on powerful tripod feet. They use custom fusion cells (Cost: 25) and fire shells that are
                basically enormous blast capsules, giving these artillery weapons both the Plasma and Hard weapon
                properties.
            </en>
            <es>Son armas antitanque, demasiado grandes para poder transportarlas a mano. Por lo general se montan en
                vehículos blindados o se montan sobre un poderoso trípode. Utilizan pilas de fusión personalizadas
                (Coste: 25) y disparan balas que son, básicamente, enormes cápsulas explosivas, lo que le concede a
                estas armas de artillería las propiedades de arma tanto de Plasma como de Duro.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>7</techLevel>
        <type>HEAVY</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>energyGuns</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>15</damage>
                <strength>7</strength>
                <range>30/100</range>
                <shots>20</shots>
                <rate>1</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>XXL</size>
        <cost>5000</cost>
        <damageType>plasma, hard</damageType>
        <others>
            <other>stock</other>
        </others>
    </blasterCannon>
    <blastPellet>
        <id>blastPellet</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Blast Pellet</en>
            <es>Perdigón Explosivo</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A mini plasma pellet that explode upon impact. Blast pellets come in various sizes, from marble
                ball-sized (3 dice damage) to tennisball- sized (6 dice damage), with a 1 meter blast radius. As with
                most plasma weapons, blast pellets can leak through energy shields (on a damage dice roll of 1 or 2).
            </en>
            <es>Un mini perdigón de plasma que explota tras impactar. Existen varios tamaños de perdigones explosivos,
                desde perdigones de mármol con forma de bola (3 dados de daño), con forma de pelota de tenis (6 dados de
                daño), con un radio de explosión de 1 metro. Al igual que la mayoría de las armas de plasma, los
                perdigones explosivos pueden atravesar escudos de energía (obteniendo un 1 o un 2 en la tirada de los
                dados de daño).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>3</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <damageName>
                    <en>Heavy</en>
                    <es>Pesado</es>
                </damageName>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6 (3 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <extraCost>10</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>20</cost>
        <damageType>plasma</damageType>
    </blastPellet>
    <concussionGrenade>
        <id>concussionGrenade</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Concussion Grenade</en>
            <es>Granada de Confusión</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A grenade with a small explosive charge designed to cause a concussion wave in the blast area; usually
                about 4 meter blast radius. If struck in the blast of a Concussion Grenade, the character suffer a
                Knockout attack. Armor does not protect against concussion grenades, except for full-body suits, in
                which case the shock wave is deflected as normal. Energy Shields protect as normal.
            </en>
            <es>Una granada con una pequeña carga explosiva diseñada para provocar una onda de conmoción cerebral en el
                área de la explosión; generalmente se trata de un radio de explosión de unos 4 metros. Si te alcanza la
                explosión de una granada de conmoción cerebral, el personaje sufre un ataque de Noqueo usando 8 dados de
                daño. La armadura no protege contra las granadas de confusión, a excepción de los trajes de cuerpo
                entero, en cuyo caso la onda de choque es desviada. Los Escudos de Energía protegen con normalidad.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>KO</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>50</cost>
    </concussionGrenade>
    <fragGrenades>
        <id>fragGrenades</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Frag Grenades</en>
            <es>Granada de Fragmentación</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>These come in all sizes and shapes, but their common feature is that they damage people and things in a
                wide area from where they explode. Each grenade is rated for the number of meters its radius encompasses
                and the damage it delivers at ground zero. The standard radius for a hand grenade is 5 meters, but this
                can increase with Tech Levels above 4. Standard damage is 12 effect dice (this can also increase at
                higher Tech Levels). A character tossing a grenade does not get to add his Victory Points to the
                damage—the grenade does all the work; all the character has to do is get it to its destination. However,
                anyone standing in the radius will suffer the damage rolled (after subtracting armor). One point is
                subtracted from the grenade’s damage for each meter away from its point of explosion.
            </en>
            <es>Existen de todos los tamaños y formas, pero su característica común es que dañan a las personas y a
                todas las cosas dentro de un amplio rango de expansión a partir de la zona donde explotan. Cada granada
                está clasificada en función de la distancia en metros que su radio puede abarcar y en función del daño
                que inflige a esa zona de impacto. El radio estándar de una granada de mano es de 5 metros, pero esto
                puede incrementarse en niveles de tecnología que estén por encima de 4. El daño estándar son 12 dados de
                efecto (también puede incrementarse en los niveles de tecnología más altos). Un personaje que lance una
                granada no añade sus Puntos de Victoria al daño, puesto que la granada hace todo el trabajo; todo lo que
                el personaje tiene que hacer es encargarse de que la granada llegue a su destino. Sin embargo, cualquier
                persona de pie dentro del adio sufrirá el daño de la tirada (después de restar la armadura). Se resta un
                punto al daño de la granada por cada metro que se aleje del centro de la explosión.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>12 (5 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>50</cost>
    </fragGrenades>
    <pipeBomb>
        <id>pipeBomb</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Pipe Bomb</en>
            <es>Bomba Casera</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>This category covers all types of ‘home made’ bombs and explosives, for use as primitive thrown grenades
                or for demolition purposes. They require a Tech + Demolition to manufacture, and cannot be constructed
                at a TL higher than the creator’s Tech Characteristic (roll once for the entire batch). A Critical
                Failure results in one or more of the bombs blowing up prematurely, possibly setting off a chain
                reaction if stored together with other Pipe Bombs. Every Pipe Bomb has a blast radius of 1 meter, but
                the strength of the explosion depends on the materials and know-how that goes into its construction; DMG
                is equal to TL+1 per ‘stick’. Several Pipe Bombs can be huddled together to form a larger bomb. A stick
                of dynamite is treated as a special (professionally made) pipe bomb, costing twice as much, but doing
                twice the DMG within a 2 meter blast radius, and it doesn’t explode on a Critical Failure (unless it was
                made with poor workmanship).
            </en>
            <es>Esta categoría abarca todos los tipos de bombas y explosivos ‘hecho en casa’, para su uso como granada
                primitiva o con fines de demolición. A fin de fabricarlas se requiere de una tirada de Tecnología +
                Demolición; no pueden fabricarse granadas con un nivel de tecnología mayor que la puntuación de la
                característica de Tecnología del personaje, (realiza una sola tirada para todo el lote). Un resultado de
                Fallo Crítico supone que una o más de las bombas exploten antes de tiempo, lo que posiblemente puede
                llegar a desencadenar una reacción en cadena si almacena todas las bombas caseras juntas. Cada bomba
                casera cuenta con un radio de explosión de 1 metro, pero la fuerza de la explosión depende de los
                materiales y del saber cómo construirla; el Daño es igual a NT+1 por unidad. Pueden amontonarse varias
                bombas caseras para crear una bomba más grande. Un cartucho de dinamita a efectos de reglas se considera
                como una bomba casera (de creación profesional), que cuesta el doble, pero inflige el doble de daño en
                un radio de explosión de 2 metros, y que no explota con un fallo crítico (a menos que lo fabricara una
                mala mano de obra).
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>3</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>4 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>5 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageTechLevel>4</damageTechLevel>
                <extraCost>10</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>6 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageTechLevel>5</damageTechLevel>
                <extraCost>20</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>7 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageTechLevel>6</damageTechLevel>
                <extraCost>30</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>8 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageTechLevel>7</damageTechLevel>
                <extraCost>40</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <techLevelSpecial>true</techLevelSpecial>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>9 (1 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
                <damageTechLevel>8</damageTechLevel>
                <extraCost>50</extraCost>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>30</cost>
    </pipeBomb>
    <plasmaGrenade>
        <id>plasmaGrenade</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Plasma Grenade</en>
            <es>Granada de Plasma</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A plasma grenade, larger than a blast pellet. These devastating weapons do 18 effect dice of damage,
                which can leak through energy shields (on a damage dice roll of 1 or 2). The blast radius is 6 meters.
            </en>
            <es>Una granada de plasma, más grande que un perdigón explosivo. Estas armas devastadoras infligen 18 dados
                de efecto de daño, que pueden atravesar los escudos de energía (con resultados de 1 o 2 en la tirada de
                daño). El radio de explosión es de 6 metros.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>6</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>18 (6 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>100</cost>
        <damageType>plasma</damageType>
    </plasmaGrenade>
    <flashBangGrenade>
        <id>flashBangGrenade</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Flash-Bang Grenade</en>
            <es>Granada Aturdidora</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Upon detonation, these grenades explode with a blinding flash and a deafening thunderclap. Anyone caught
                in the 4 meter blast radius is left disoriented and suffering a –8 penalty to all actions until they can
                shake off the effect with a successful Will + Self-Control goal roll. Armor does not protect against
                flash bangs, except for full-body suits with dark visors or fully insulated helmets, in which case the
                flash bang effect can be ignored.
            </en>
            <es>Tras la detonación, éstas granadas estallan con un destello cegador y un estruendo ensordecedor.
                Cualquiera que sea sorprendido dentro de un rango de unos 4 metros de la explosión quedará desorientado
                y sufrirá un penalizador de -8 a todas las acciones hasta que supere los efectos superando una tirada de
                Voluntad + Autocontrol. La armadura no protege contra las granadas aturdidoras, a excepción de los
                trajes de cuerpo completo con viseras oscuras o de los cascos totalmente aislados, en cuyo caso el
                efecto de la explosión del flash puede ser ignorado.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>4</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>*(4m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>50</cost>
    </flashBangGrenade>
    <wireGrenade>
        <id>wireGrenade</id>
        <type>weapon</type>
        <official>false</official>
        <name>
            <en>Wire Grenade</en>
            <es>Granada Eléctrica</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>A grenade that unspools a monofilament wire in all directions. The damage is the same as a regular
                grenade (12d), but the armor defense effect dice of anyone in the radius is halved. Radius is 3 meters.
            </en>
            <es>Una granada que esparce un cable basado en monofilamentos por todas partes. El daño es el mismo que el
                de una granada normal (12d), pero los dados de efecto de armadura de cualquier persona dentro del radio
                quedan reducidos a la mitad. El radio de explosión es de 3 metros.
            </es>
        </description>
        <techLevel>5</techLevel>
        <type>GRENADE</type>
        <damageList>
            <weaponDamage>
                <characteristic>dexterity</characteristic>
                <skill>throwing</skill>
                <goal>0</goal>
                <damage>12 (3 m)</damage>
                <strength>1</strength>
                <range>10/20</range>
                <shots>handful</shots>
                <rate>2</rate>
            </weaponDamage>
        </damageList>
        <size>S</size>
        <cost>80</cost>
        <damageType>halveArmour</damageType>
    </wireGrenade>
</weapons>
