<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<callings>
    <calling>
        <id>servant</id>
        <name>
            <en>Servant</en>
            <es>Sirviente</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Often beneath notice, and frequently beneath contempt, the servitor class that undergirds the noble class is a broad grouping of people who know not only their own role, but the greater eco-system that pervades and surrounds the powerful. Those of the servitor class serve not only the nobility but paying members of the guilds and even (to a lesser extent) Church interestás. While most servants come to their calling through conventional means, some enter the servant class as spies or as a cover. No few nobles, or other important personages, have been forced into secret servitude to escape the dissolution of their house or to hide from enemies. In so doing, they gain new insights and the "common touch" that comes with the calling's peasant perks.
                Patron Saints: Orieth the Faithful — A simple and unassuming servant, little is known of this woman who is obliquely mentioned throughout the Omega Gospels. Orieth served the Prophet with honestá piety all her life and died with him during his pilgrimage to the vau. Balazim the Clever — Nobles rule over society, priests speak for the cosmos, and the guilds invent, but serfs and servants know who really keeps everything going. Balazim was cleverer by far than any of his "superiors," and the benign trickster always managed to get his feckless másters out of trouble (usually of their own making), while also benefiting himself and others who served below the salt. Balazim is a subversive, folkloric figure, not always venerated on every planet in the Known Worlds — though most of his tales involve bailing out his bumbling máster, Lord Cylus Chauki of Sutek. Regardless, he remains popular among serfs, and especially among long-suffering servants who toil under half-witted másters.</en>
            <es>A menudo ignorada, y con frecuencia despreciada, la clase servil que sostiene a la clase noble es un amplio grupo de personas que conocen no solo su propio papel, sino el ecosistema mayor que impregna y rodea a los poderosos. Los de la clase servil sirven no solo a la nobleza, sino también a miembros de pago de los gremios e incluso (en menor medida) a los intereses de la Iglesia. Aunque la mayoría de los sirvientes llega a su vocación por medios convencionales, algunos entran en la clase servil como espías o como tapadera. No pocos nobles, u otros personajes importantes, se han visto forzados a una servidumbre secreta para escapar de la disolución de su casa o para esconderse de sus enemigos. Al hacerlo, obtienen nuevas perspectivas y el "toque popular" que acompaña a los perks campesinos de la vocación.
                Santos Patronos: Orieth la Fiel — Una sirvienta sencilla y modestá, poco se sabe de está mujer mencionada de forma indirecta a lo largo de los Evangelios Omega. Orieth sirvió al Profeta con piedad sincera toda su vida y murió con él durante su peregrinacion a los vau. Balazim el Astuto — Los nobles gobiernan la sociedad, los sacerdotes hablan por el cosmos y los gremios inventan, pero los siervos y sirvientes saben quién mantiene realmente todo en marcha. Balazim era con mucho más astuto que cualquiera de sus "superiores," y el benigno embaucador siempre lograba sacar de apuros a sus inútiles amos (normalmente provocados por ellos mismos), beneficiándose a la vez a sí mismo y a otros que servían por debajo de la sal. Balazim es una figura subversiva y folclórica, no siempre venerada en todos los planetas de los Mundos Conocidos, aunque la mayoría de sus relatos consisten en sacar las castañas del fuego a su torpe amo, el Señor Cylus Chauki de Sutek. En cualquier caso, sigue siendo popular entre los siervos, y especialmente entre los sufridos sirvientes que se afanan bajo amos de pocas luces.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>cathedralCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>commonsCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>courtCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <group>knowledgeLore</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>craftsLore</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>scienceLore</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>medicalLore</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>transport</group>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>endurance</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>faith</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>will</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>perception</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>presence</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>wits</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>catBurglarsEye</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>counterfeit</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>householder</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>keepingSecrets</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>peasantHero</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>rabbleRouse</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>charm</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>crafts</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>drive</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>knavery</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>observe</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>remedy</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>sleightOfHand</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>sneak</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <restrictions>
            <upbringings>
                <upbringing>merchant</upbringing>
                <upbringing>yeoman</upbringing>
            </upbringings>
        </restrictions>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>SOCIAL</preference>
                <preference>STEALTH</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
    <calling>
        <id>starMarine</id>
        <name>
            <en>Star Marine</en>
            <es>Infante Estelar</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Star Marines are elite soldiers found in many space armadas, from Brother Battle to every noble fleet, and among the Charioteers and Muster mercenary groups. Trained to operate in a wide array of environments, they are most frequently deployed in ship-to-ship boarding and combat. In this arena, they are unparalleled in the complex process of breaching an enemy ship's hull while taking fire, and then fighting through the enemy ship to take its bridge. Regardless of their dependence on high technology, those who retain space marine forces are sure to carve out holy exceptions for them under the Doctrine of the Privilege of Martyrs, though this lasts only for as long as the marine is in good standing with the greater military body.
                Patron Saints: Damik the Marksman — Damik was a renowned al-Malik commander who battled against the ukar during their war against Criticorum. With a surprise attack from a hidden mothership, the ukar destároyed much of the local fleet (Damik's was one of the few still battleworthy), leaving the planet defenseless as they launched wave after wave of spaceborne attacks. When the ukari offered mercy to the thousands of civilians under Damik's protection if he would stand down, the noble reluctantly agreed. The ukari, however, reneged as Damik's force withdrew, starting a new wave of bombings over the planet. Enraged at this betrayal, he spotted a jumpgate-shaped opening in an interstellar cloud, which he took as a vision from the Prophet. Ordering his ship through the misty gate, he discovered the hidden mothership. Boarding the ukari command vessel, he and his men disrupted ukari command and control until the arrival of al-Malik reinforcements, ending the invasíon and saving the planet. Damik's thousand-to-one shot is still celebrated on Criticorum, or wherever soldiers face seemingly hopeless odds. Sgt. Gronn — As much a tactically adaptable artillery battery as an individual soldier, this cigar-chomping vorox space marine was well known during the early Symbiot War in his battle armor with twin-wielded mini-guns. Sgt. Gronn displayed a nearly preternatural ability to adapt to the bizarre symbiot-infestéd planets on which he battled, often fooling the creatures on their own turf. His greatestá victory, however, occurred when the menace came closer to home. Rather than endangering the planet below, Sgt. Gronn and his men steered the ship into the sun. A somber monument to the vorox and his men still draws pilgrims to the windblown planet, and his memory is revered by those who battle in space.</en>
            <es>Los Infantes Estelares son soldados de elite presentes en muchas armadas espaciales, desde Hermano de Batalla hasta todas las flotas nobles, y entre los grupos mercenarios de los Carromateros y la Leva. Entrenados para operar en una amplia variedad de entornos, se despliegan con mayor frecuencia en abordajes y combate de nave a nave. En ese terreno, no tienen rival en el complejo proceso de penetrar el casco de una nave enemiga bajo fuego para luego abrirse paso por ella y tomar su puente. Pese a su dependencia de la alta tecnología, quienes mantienen fuerzas de infanteria espacial se aseguran de labrarles excepciones sagradas bajo la Doctrina del Privilegio de los Martires, aunque estáo solo dura mientras el infante esté en buena posición ante el cuerpo militar mayor.
                Santos Patronos: Damik el Tirador — Damik fue un renombrado comandante al-Malik que combatio contra los ukar durante su guerra contra Criticorum. Con un ataque sorpresa desde una nave nodriza oculta, los ukar destáruyeron gran parte de la flota local (la de Damik era una de las pocas aun aptas para el combate), dejando el planeta indefenso mientras lanzaban oleada tras oleada de ataques desde el espacio. Cuando los ukari ofrecieron clemencia a los miles de civiles bajo la proteccion de Damik si se rendia, el noble accedio a reganadientes. Sin embargo, los ukari incumplieron su palabra cuando la fuerza de Damik se retiraba, iniciando una nueva oleada de bombardeos sobre el planeta. Enfurecido por está traicion, avisto una abertura con forma de puerta de salto en una nube interestélar, que tomo por una vision del Profeta. Ordenando que su nave atravesara la brumosa puerta, descubrio la nave nodriza oculta. Abordando la nave de mando ukari, el y sus hombres interrumpieron el mando y control ukari hasta la llegada de refuerzos al-Malik, poniendo fin a la invasíon y salvando el planeta. El disparo de mil a uno de Damik aun se celebra en Criticorum, o dondequiera que los soldados afronten situaciónes aparentemente desesperadas. Sgt. Gronn — Tanto una bateria de artilleria tácticamente adaptable como un soldado individual, esté infante espacial vorox que máscaba puros fue muy conocido durante los inicios de la Guerra Simbionte con su armadura de combate y dos mini-canones empunados. El Sgt. Gronn mostro una capacidad casí sobrenatural para adaptarse a los extraños planetas infestádos de simbiontes en los que combatia, enganando a menudo a las criaturas en su propio terreno. Su mayor victoria, sin embargo, ocurrio cuando la amenaza se acerco a casa. En lugar de poner en peligro el planeta de abajo, el Sgt. Gronn y sus hombres dirigieron la nave hacia el sol. Un sombrio monumento al vorox y sus hombres aun atrae peregrinos al ventoso planeta, y su memoria es venerada por quienes combaten en el espacio.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>warArmor</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>slugGuns</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>energyGuns</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>shipboardOperations</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>dexterity</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>endurance</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>strength</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>armedToTheTeeth</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>boardingAction</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>canOpener</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <group>marksmanship</group>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <group>militaryRank</group>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>spotter</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>fight</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>intrusion</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>melee</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>observe</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>shoot</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>techRedemption</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>vigor</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>COMBAT</preference>
                <preference>MILITARY</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
    <calling>
        <id>starSailor</id>
        <name>
            <en>Star Sailor</en>
            <es>Marinero Estelar</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Charioteer captains and others travel space in almost every form of vessel, but they do not do so alone. Star sailors are the men, women and aliens who do the hard work of maintaining the craft, tending its engines, or maintaining its hull integrity, air recycling systems, navigation, or servicing/manning its weaponry. Sailors may come from backgrounds as disparate as the ships they serve, which may be modern or primitive, pristine or in need of constant repair. Ships in need of sailors include: tugs or salvagers, solar-sailed barges, sleek cutters, research stations, and more. Star sailors are also needed on space stations and airless moon bases. Sailors on these vessels may be noble, Church, guild, or from a panoply of other backgrounds. Robed monks may be think-machine experts or stellar cartographers on Church vessels, while such unexpected types as Carnivalers and Courtesans may pick up these guild-duties while entertaining on a luxury liner (or other ships where their services are required). While most advanced shipboard jobs go to Charioteers or Engineers, the only prerequisite for this calling is to have served on a ship long enough to have learned the ropes. While spacecraft inspire awe in those who behold them, few think of the demanding tasks involved in keeping most ships running. Gourmands Guild chefs serve crew and passengers food, while chaplains and members of the Oubliette Guild help keep people grounded while sailing through space for months at a time in groaning metal tubes. Sewage and other waste removal are most often carried out by members of the Purgers Guild, who have adapted to ship life.
                Patron Saints: Olav the Engineer — A valuable slave on a Decados war vessel after the Fall, Olav resented his captors but loved the ship on which he served. Both a skilled engineer and faithful follower of the Prophet, he served his másters well in many conflicts, while also praying for freedom for himself and his fellow slaves. When his ship encountered a seemingly derelict vau ship near the Cadiz jumpgate, his captain boarded the vessel in search of advanced technology. Finding surviving vau, the captain foolishly ordered their execution, a decision that might easíly have resulted in war and (possibly) the extinction of House Decados. Interdicting his captain's orders by stranding him on a shuttlecraft, Olav's act of mutiny was unknowingly well-timed as a vau warship arrived just in time to have monitored the entire affair. The resulting diplomatic incident, later known as the Vril-Ya Imbroglio, allowed for the release of Olav and his fellow slaves, as well as thousands of others, at vau insistence. Makeshift shrines to Olav can often be encountered on ships and space stations. Po-Pi — Famed for fighting to the finish, this sailor of the stellar seas worked on every form of spaceship, from the most primitive tramp vessels to the largestá dreadnoughts. During the Kurgan conflict, the Hazat command ship on which Po-Pi served was crítically damaged. Donning a spacesuit, Po-Pi worked feverishly outside the ship, bringing systems on line, thus saving the ship and allowing for victory over the Kurgans. Upon returning to his comrades, Po-Pi immediately died, but it was discovered that his suit was torn and he had really run out of air many hours earlier. Though some claim his survival was only attributable to his imbibing of advanced Agricorp oxy-green, the miracle of the torn spacesuit is still celebrated, and the suit itself a venerated object on Vera Cruz.</en>
            <es>Los capitanes Carromateros y otros viajan por el espacio en casí cualquier tipo de nave, pero no lo hacen solos. Los marineros estelares son los hombres, mujeres y alienigenas que realizan el duro trabajo de mantener la nave, atender sus motores o conservar la integridad de su casco, los sistemas de reciclaje de aire, la navegacion, o el servicio y manejo de su armamento. Los marineros pueden proceder de origenes tan dispares como las naves a las que sirven, que pueden ser modernas o primitivas, impecables o necesitadas de constante reparacion. Entre las naves que necesitan marineros están: remolcadores o rescatadores, barcazas de vela solar, elegantes cuteres, estáciones de investigación y más. También se necesitan marineros estelares en estáciones espaciales y bases lunares sin aire. Los marineros de estás naves pueden ser nobles, de la Iglesia, de gremios o de un sinfin de otros origenes. Monjes con tunica pueden ser expertos en maquinas pensantes o cartografos estelares en naves de la Iglesia, mientras que tipos tan inesperados como Carnavaleros y Cortesanas pueden asumir estás táreas gremiales mientras entretienen en un crucero de lujo (u otras naves donde se requieran sus servicios). Aunque la mayoría de los trabajos avanzados de a bordo recaen en Carromateros o Ingenieros, el unico requisito para está vocación es haber servido en una nave el tiempo suficiente para aprender el oficio. Aunque las naves espaciales inspiran asombro en quienes las contemplan, pocos piensan en las exigentes táreas que conlleva mantener funcionando la mayoría de las naves. Los chefs del Gremio de los Gourmands sirven comida a la tripulacion y los pasajeros, mientras que los capellanes y miembros del Gremio del Olvido ayudan a mantener a la gente con los pies en la tierra mientras navegan por el espacio durante meses en crujientes tubos de metal. La eliminacion de aguas residuales y otros desechos suele correr a cargo de miembros del Gremio de los Purgadores, que se han adaptado a la vida de a bordo.
                Santos Patronos: Olav el Ingeniero — Un valioso esclavo en una nave de guerra Decados tras la Caida, Olav detestába a sus captores pero amaba la nave en la que servia. Ingeniero hábil y fiel seguidor del Profeta, sirvió bien a sus amos en muchos conflictos, mientras rezaba por la libertad para sí mismo y sus companeros esclavos. Cuando su nave se topo con una nave vau aparentemente abandonada cerca de la puerta de salto de Cadiz, su capitan abordo el navio en busca de tecnología avanzada. Al hallar vau supervivientes, el capitan ordeno neciamente su ejecucion, una decision que fácilmente podria haber desembocado en guerra y (posiblemente) la extincion de la Casa Decados. Interdictando las ordenes de su capitan al dejarlo varado en una lanzadera, el acto de motin de Olav resulto, sin saberlo, oportuno, pues una nave de guerra vau llego justo a tiempo de presenciar todo el asunto. El consiguiente incidente diplomatico, conocido después como el Embrollo Vril-Ya, permitio la liberacion de Olav y sus companeros esclavos, así como de miles de otros, por insistencia de los vau. Es habitual encontrar santuarios improvisados a Olav en naves y estáciones espaciales. Po-Pi — Famoso por luchar hasta el final, esté marinero de los mares estelares trabajo en todas las formás de nave espacial, desde los más primitivos vagabundos hasta los mayores acorazados. Durante el conflicto Kurgan, la nave de mando Hazat en la que servia Po-Pi quedo gravemente danada. Poniendose un traje espacial, Po-Pi trabajo febrilmente en el exterior de la nave, poniendo en línea los sistemas y salvando así la nave, permitiendo la victoria sobre los Kurgan. Al regresar con sus cámaradas, Po-Pi murió de inmediato, pero se descubrio que su traje estába rasgado y que en realidad se habia quedado sin aire muchas horas antes. Aunque algunos atribuyen su supervivencia unicamente a haber bebido avanzado oxi-verde de Agricorp, el milagro del traje espacial rasgado aun se celebra, y el propio traje es un objeto venerado en Vera Cruz.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>jumpwebLore</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>techLore</group>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>shipboardOperations</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>dexterity</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>endurance</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>intuition</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>wits</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>gambler</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>linguistSpeak</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>linguistWriting</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>machineSpirit</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>mechanic</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <group>militaryRank</group>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>charm</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>interface</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>knavery</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>pilot</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>shoot</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>techRedemption</id>
                        <bonus>3</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>TECHNICAL</preference>
                <preference>TRADE</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
</callings>

