<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<occultism>
    <path>
        <id>farHand</id>
        <name>
            <en>Far Hand</en>
            <es>Mano Lejana</es>
        </name>
        <occultismType>psi</occultismType>
        <powers>
            <power>
                <id>liftingHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Lifting Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Alzadora</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>By focusing your will, you can create a simple field of directional force to pick up, push, or
                        pull objects.
                    </en>
                    <es>Concentras tu voluntad para crear un sencillo campo de fuerza direccional con el que recoger
                        objetos, empujarlos o tirar de ellos.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>1</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per turn extended duration</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por turno de duración extendida</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>An unattended object’s Resistance is 1 per 25 kg of weight. If someone is holding the object,
                        they can resist your psychokinetic pull as a reflexive secondary action; add that person’s
                        Strength to the Resistance. VP can be spent to overcome the object’s Resistance.
                    </en>
                    <es>Un objeto desatendido presenta una Resistencia de 1 por cada 25 kg de peso. Si alguien está
                        agarrando el objeto, puede resistir tu empuje psicoquinético con una acción secundaria refleja;
                        suma su Fuerza a la Resistencia. Puedes gastar PV para superar la Resistencia del objeto.
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You lift an object within your sight 1 meter into the air. You can push it in any direction a
                        distance of 1 meter per rank of Psi.\n
                        Each turn, you can keep this power going by spending 1 VP. While the power’s duration lasts,
                        you may use a secondary action to keep the object aloft and move it up to 1 meter per Psi rank.
                        When the duration ends, the object returns to the ground as if dropped from its height.
                    </en>
                    <es>Alzas 1 metro en el aire un objeto de tu campo visual. A continuación, puedes empujarlo en
                        cualquier dirección 1 metro por cada punto de Psi que tengas.\n
                        Cada turno, puedes mantener el poder activo gastando 1 PV. A lo largo de su duración, es posible
                        usar una acción secundaria para mantener el objeto flotando y moverlo hasta 1 metro por cada
                        punto de Psi. Una vez que la duración acabe, el objeto cae como si lo soltases desde esa altura.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>throwingHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Throwing Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Arrojadora</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You propel an object you have lifted with considerable force. You must first use Lifting Hand to
                        pick up the object; throwing it with this power is then a bonus primary action.
                    </en>
                    <es>Lanzas con una fuerza considerable un objeto que hayas alzado. Primero debes usar Mano Alzadora
                        para elevar el objeto y después una acción primaria adicional para lanzarlo.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>2</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneousAdditionalPrimaryAction</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP</en>
                    <es>1 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>perception</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Equals the target’s Body Resistance; if the target is an object, the GM determines its
                        Resistance.
                    </en>
                    <es>Equivalente a la Resistencia Corporal del objetivo; si el objetivo es un objeto, el DJ determina
                        la Resistencia.
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You fling your psychokinetically lifted object at a target (a person, thing, or location). The
                        GM determines the base damage delivered by the ob ject, based on its size, weight, sharpness,
                        etc. If it’s a weapon, use the weapon’s damage.\n
                        The target must be within 1 meter per Psi rating. This range can be increased by 1 meter per 1
                        VP you spend.\n
                        You cannot extend the duration of this power. If you want to throw the object again, you’ll need
                        to first use Lifting Hand again and then this power.
                    </en>
                    <es>Lanzas el objeto que has elevado psicoquinéticamente hacia un objetivo (persona, cosa o lugar).
                        El DJ determina el daño base que provoca el objeto según su tamaño, su peso, lo afilado que sea,
                        etc. Si es un arma, utiliza el daño del arma.\n
                        El objetivo debe estar como máximo a una distancia de 1 metro por punto de Psi. Puedes aumentar
                        esta dis tancia en 1 metro por cada PV que gastes. \n
                        Sin embargo, no puedes aumentar la duración del poder. Si quieres volver a lanzar el mismo
                        objeto, primero tendrás que usar de nuevo Mano Alzadora y después este poder.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>crushinHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Crushing Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Aplastante</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You can hold a target in place and exert crushing force.
                    </en>
                    <es>Mantienes a tu objetivo en su sitio y le aplicas una fuerza aplastante.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per turn extended duration</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por turno de duración extendida</es>
                </cost>
                <psiLevel>3</psiLevel>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>fights</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Against a person, the target’s armor does not provide Body Resistance, but they can use their
                        Strength as Resistance (e.g., a person with a Strength of 5 would get 5 Resistance). Against an
                        object, the GM determines the Resistance based on toughness.
                    </en>
                    <es>Contra una persona, la armadura del objetivo no proporciona Resistencia Corporal, pero la
                        persona puede usar su Fuerza como Resistencia (por ejemplo, una persona con Fuerza 5 ofrecería
                        Resistencia 5). Contra un objeto, el DJ determina la Resistencia basándose en su robustez.
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>Inflicts 3 base damage, and the target is Hindered until your psychokinetic hold is broken. Once
                        a Crushing Hand hold is victorious, you can maintain the duration by spending 1 VP each turn.
                        You can opt to inflict damage each successive turn as a primary action without needing to make
                        another roll; you spend VP to inflict this damage. During a Crushing Hand hold, you can consider
                        three sub-maneuvers: clinch, restrain, or escape.\n

                        Clinch: Instead of inflicting damage, you can opt to clinch your psychokinetic hold by making
                        another roll each turn as a primary action. This improves your hold — it grants you VP. If the
                        clinch roll fails, you still have hold of your target, but the target can make a reflexive roll
                        to escape (see below). If the clinch roll is a critical miss, the hold is broken.

                        Restrain: Instead of inflicting damage, you can try to restrain your victim. This can only be
                        done on turns after the turn in which the hold was established. You spend 2 VP to impose the
                        Immobilized state. On the following turn, you can spend 2 VP to try to render the target
                        Incapacitated (if they fail a reflexive secondary-action
                        Vigor + Will roll vs. your Psi as Resistance).\n

                        Escape: The character who is grappled can take a primary action to break free, rolling Fight +
                        Strength vs. Resistance equal to your Psi. If successful, they are free from the Crushing Hand
                        hold and can take their movement action. If the roll fails, they are still Hindered (or
                        Immobilized, if they were restrained). If you failed a clinch roll, the victim can make an
                        escape roll as a reflexive action.
                    </en>
                    <es>Inflige 3 puntos de daño base y el objetivo queda Obstaculizado hasta que interrumpas tu acción
                        psicoquinética. Una vez que consigas iniciar la Mano Aplastante, puedes mantener la duración
                        gastando 1 PV por turno. Puedes continuar provocando daño en cada turno sucesivo como acción
                        primaria sin necesidad de más tiradas, pero gastando PV. Durante el agarre de la Mano
                        Aplastante, puedes llevar a cabo tres submaniobras: afianzar, contener o escapar.\n

                        Afianzar: En vez de hacer daño, puedes optar por afianzar la presa psicoquinética, haciendo otra
                        tirada cada turno como acción primaria. Esto mejora tu agarre; es decir, te ofrece PV. En caso
                        de que falles la tirada de afianzar, tu objetivo todavía está bajo tu control, pero puede hacer
                        una tirada refleja para escapar (a continuación). Si la tirada de afianzar es un fallo crítico,
                        la presa queda interrumpida.

                        Contener: En vez de hacer daño, intentas contener a tu oponente. Solo puedes hacer esto en los
                        turnos posteriores al turno en el que has establecido la presa. Gasta 2 PV para imponer el
                        estado Inmovilizado. En el siguiente turno, puedes gastar 2 PV para dejar a tu objetivo
                        Incapacitado (si falla una acción secundaria refleja de
                        Vigor + Voluntad contra tu Psi como Resistencia).\n

                        Escapar: El personaje apresado debe usar una acción primaria para liberarse, haciendo una tirada
                        de Pelear + Fuerza contra una Resistencia igual a tu Psi. Si tiene éxito, se libera de la Mano
                        Aplastante y puede llevar a cabo su acción de movimiento. Si la tirada falla, seguirá
                        Obstaculizado (o Inmovilizado si estaba contenido). En caso de que falles la tirada de afianzar,
                        la víctima podrá hacer una tirada de escapar como acción refleja.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>duelingHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Dueling Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Duelista</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You can make a tool or weapon on your person leap into the air, perform an action, and then
                        either return to your person or hover, ready to act again in subsequent turns.
                    </en>
                    <es>Haces que una herramienta o arma que lleves encima se eleve en el aire, lleve a cabo una acción
                        y después, o bien vuelva a ti, o bien se quede flotando, lista para volver a actuar el próximo
                        turno.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>4</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per turn extended duration</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por turno de duración extendida</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>*</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>As per the task you perform with the item.</en>
                    <es>Dependiendo de la tarea que lleves a cabo con el objeto.</es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>The item can move up to 1 meter per Psi rating, plus 1 meter 1 VP spent.\n

                        If you’re using the psychokinetically controlled object as a weapon, treat it like a normal
                        attack, except that it’s at range.\n

                        After the action is complete, the item returns to where it came from (holster, belt, etc.),
                        unless you extend the duration (1 VP per turn), in which case the item hovers in place until you
                        direct it again. (Hovering is a secondary action; using it again to perform a task is a primary
                        action.)
                    </en>
                    <es>El objeto se puede mover 1 metro por cada punto de Psi, más 1 metro por PV gastado.\n

                        Si usas el objeto controlado psicoquinéticamente como arma, considéralo un ataque normal, salvo
                        que es a distancia.\n

                        Después de completar la acción, el objeto vuelve al lugar de donde vino
                        (funda de pistola, cinturón, etc.) a menos que amplíes la duración (1 PV por turno), en cuyo
                        caso el objeto se queda flotando en el sitio hasta que vuelvas a dirigirlo (flotar es una acción
                        secundaria y usarlo otra vez para llevar a cabo una tarea es una acción primaria).
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>focusedHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Focused Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Concentrada</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>Focusing your mind, you can perform great feats of strength, such as lifting an object of
                        incredible weight or raising multiple items into the air. You can also perform delicate tasks
                        from a distance.
                    </en>
                    <es>Si te concentras, puedes llevar a cabo hazañas de fuerza, como levantar un objeto de un peso
                        descomunal o elevar varios objetos en el aire. También puedes realizar tareas delicadas a
                        distancia.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>5</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per turn extended duration</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por turno de duración extendida</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>When lifting a single object, Resistance is 1 per 200 kg of weight. If someone is holding the
                        object, they can resist your psychokinetic pull as a reflexive secondary action; add that
                        person’s Strength to the Resistance. You can spend VP to overcome the object’s Resistance.\n

                        When lifting multiple objects, Resistance is 1 per 100 kg of weight.\n

                        When performing a skilled task, use the guidelines for the skill’s maneuvers in Chapter 3:
                        Traits, but generally, the Resistance is raised by one step (say, from Demanding to Tough).
                    </en>
                    <es>Cuando levantes un solo objeto, la Resistencia es 1 por cada 200 kg de peso. Si alguien está
                        agarrando el objeto, puede resistir tu empuje psicoquinético con una acción secundaria refleja;
                        suma su Fuerza a la Resistencia. Para superar la Resistencia del objeto puedes gastar PV.\n

                        Cuando levantes varios objetos, la Resistencia es 1 por cada 100 kg de peso.\n

                        Si llevas a cabo una tarea que requiera habilidad, guíate por las reglas de las maniobras en el
                        Capítulo 3: Atributos, aunque, por lo general, la Resistencia aumenta en uno (por ejemplo, de
                        Exigente a Ardua).
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You can lift one item, lift more items, or achieve a task. \n

                        Lift: You can either lift an object of immense weight, lift a multitude of items into the air,
                        or move everything not nailed down away from you. This operates like Lifting Hand with the
                        exceptions listed under Resistance (shown above), as well as the ability to lift more than one
                        item. You can also employ Throwing Hand with the objects you have lifted (as a bonus primary
                        action; as per the Throwing Hand rules). You can use Dueling Hand with your multiple objects,
                        but they must all perform the same action against the same target; otherwise, it costs you 2 VP
                        per additional action/target.\n

                        Task: You can perform a skill maneuver from a distance (within sight). Use the guidelines for
                        the skill from Chapter 3: Traits, but the GM will determine how well you can really perform
                        here. You might be able to type on a think machine’s keyboard from across the room, but that
                        doesn’t mean you can read the screen well enough to know if you’re getting the results you
                        intend. Combining this with a Sixth Sense power such as Far Self might lower the Resistance back
                        to normal.
                    </en>
                    <es>Puedes levantar un objeto, varios o llevar a cabo una tarea.

                        Levantar: Puedes levantar un objeto de enorme peso, elevar varios objetos en el aire o mover
                        todo lo que no esté sujeto al suelo para apartarlo de ti. Esto funciona como Mano Alzadora,
                        salvo por la capacidad de levantar más de un objeto y con las excepciones que aparecen en
                        Resistencia. También puedes usar la Mano Arrojadora con los objetos que has levantado (como
                        acción primaria adicional, tal como indican las reglas de la Mano Arrojadora). Para levantar
                        varios objetos puedes usar la Mano Duelista, pero todos deben realizar la misma acción contra el
                        mismo objetivo; de lo contrario, te costará 2 PV por acción/objetivo adicional.

                        Tarea: Puedes realizar una maniobra a distancia (siempre que esté a tu alcance visual). Utiliza
                        las reglas de habilidades del Capítulo 3: Atributos, aunque lo bien que la hagas dependerá de lo
                        que decida el DJ según las circunstancias. Quizás seas capaz de escribir con el teclado de una
                        máquina pensante desde la otra punta de la habitación, pero eso no quiere decir que puedas leer
                        la pantalla lo suficientemente bien como para saber si estás consiguiendo los resultados
                        deseados. Combinar este poder con un poder de Sexto Sentido, como Presencia Lejana, podría
                        reducir la Resistencia a un nivel normal.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>farWall</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Far Wall</en>
                    <es>Muro Lejano</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You create a force field barrier similar to one generated by energy shield technology.
                    </en>
                    <es>Creas un campo de fuerza parecido al que genera la tecnología de los escudos de energía.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>6</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per activation</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por activación.</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>will</characteristic>
                <skill>vigor</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Hard Resistance.</en>
                    <es>Resistencia Difícil.</es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>Psi rating, plus 1 sq. meter per 1 VP spent. Anyone behind the field gains its protection, as if
                        they were wearing a personal energy shield device.

                        The Far Wall behaves equivalent to an energy shield. Its lower threshold is equal to 3 + your
                        Urge rating, while its upper limit is 10 + your Psi rating. (For example, if your Urge is 2 and
                        your Psi is 6, your force field’s protection is 5/16.)

                        The Far Wall lasts for the remainder of the scene, but each “shield” activation costs you 1 VP.
                        If you can’t spend the VP, the power is still active, but it doesn’t have enough energy to
                        activate the shielding effect until you can spend VP.
                    </en>
                    <es>Creas un campo de fuerza de 1 m² por punto de Psi + 1 m² por cada PV que gastes. Cualquiera que
                        esté detrás del campo recibe su protección como si llevase encima un escudo de energía personal.

                        El Muro Lejano se comporta como un escudo de energía. Su umbral mínimo es 3 + tu puntuación de
                        Ansia, mientras que su umbral máximo es 10 + tu puntuación de Psi. Por ejemplo, si tu Ansia es 2
                        y tu Psi 6, la protección de tu campo de fuerza es 5/16).

                        El Muro Lejano dura el resto de la escena, pero cada activación del «escudo» te cuesta 1 PV. Si
                        no tienes PV, el poder seguirá activo, pero no tendrá suficiente energía como para activar el
                        efecto protector hasta que puedas gastar más PV.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>airStride</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Air Stride</en>
                    <es>Zancada Aérea</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>Focusing your directional forces on yourself, you can hover over the ground or take to the
                        air.
                    </en>
                    <es>Al concentrar las fuerzas direccionales en ti mismo, puedes flotar sobre el suelo o elevarte en
                        el aire.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>7</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Equals your Size rating (5 for humans) + 1 for every 100 kg of equipment/objects/creatures you
                        carry.
                    </en>
                    <es>Equivalente a tu tamaño (5 para humanos) + 1 por cada 100 kg de equipo/objetos/criaturas que
                        lleves.
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You hover up above the ground, and you can fly through the air for the remainder of the scene as
                        your movement action. Your base speed is 10 meters per turn. You can increase this by 5 meters
                        per turn per 2 VP you spend.
                    </en>
                    <es>Flotas sobre el suelo y puedes volar durante el resto la de la escena usando tu acción de
                        movimiento. Tu velocidad base es 10 metros por turno. Auméntala 5 metros por turno por cada 2 PV
                        que gastes.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>demolishingHand</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Demolishing Hand</en>
                    <es>Mano Demoledora</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>By compressing an energy field and releasing it at a single point, you can create a big hole in
                        something… or someone.
                    </en>
                    <es>Comprimir el campo de energía después de liberarlo en un único punto te permite crear un gran
                        agujero en algo... o alguien.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>8</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP</en>
                    <es>1 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>perception</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Equals target’s Body Resistance (ignores armor).
                    </en>
                    <es>Equivalente a la Resistencia Corporal del objetivo (ignora armadura).
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You compress and release a wave of force right next to a target, like uncoiling a spring. The
                        force ignores Body Resistance from physical armor; it’s considered a broad-impact strike against
                        energy shields (check for burnout). Base damage is equal to your Will rating and can be
                        increased by 1 per 2 VP spent.\n

                        Any target that suffers damage from this blast must make a reflexive secondary-action Endurance
                        + Vigor roll vs. Resistance equal to the amount of damage taken. Victory means they are Stunned
                        for their next turn. Failure means they are Unconscious for 1 turn per point of damage.
                    </en>
                    <es>Comprimes y liberas una oleada de fuerza junto a tu objetivo, como si soltases un resorte. La
                        fuerza ignora la Resistencia Corporal de la armadura física; se considera un golpe contundente
                        contra escudos de energía (comprueba si se agota). El daño base es equivalente a tu Voluntad y
                        se puede aumentar en 1 por cada 2 PV que gastes.\n

                        Cualquier objetivo que sufra daño de esta explosión debe llevar a cabo una acción secundaria
                        refleja de Constitución + Vigor contra una Resistencia equivalente a la cantidad de daño
                        sufrido. Una victoria implica quedar Aturdido durante su próximo turno, mientras que un fallo
                        implica quedar Inconsciente durante 1 turno por cada punto de daño.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>airDance</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Air Dance</en>
                    <es>Danza Aérea</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You may use Air Stride on others, even if they’re unwilling.
                    </en>
                    <es>Puedes usar la Zancada Aérea con otras personas, incluso aunque no quieran.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>9</psiLevel>
                <time>instantaneous</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>1 VP + 1 VP per additional target after the first (max limit = Psi)</en>
                    <es>1 PV + 1 PV por cada objetivo adicional (máximo = Psi)</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>wits</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Figure the Size ratings + 1 per 100 kg of equipment carried for each target and apply it as
                        Resistance; you can lift up those whose Resistance you overcome.
                    </en>
                    <es>Calcula el tamaño + 1 por cada 100 kg de equipo por cada objetivo y aplícalo como Resistencia;
                        puedes levantar a aquellos cuya Resistencia hayas superado.
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You bestow the Air Stride power on one or more willing targets, who are each in control of their
                        own flight (although either you or they must spend VP to increase base speed). Unwilling targets
                        can attempt a reflexive primary-action dodge maneuver (using Vigor skill); if they fail, you
                        control their flight as a secondary action.
                    </en>
                    <es>Confieres el poder Zancada Aérea a uno o varios objetivos voluntarios, y cada uno controla su
                        propio vuelo (aunque ellos o tú tendréis que gastar PV para aumentar la velocidad base). Los
                        objetivos forzados podrán intentar una maniobra de esquivar con una acción primaria refleja
                        (utilizando la habilidad Vigor); si fallan, controlarás su vuelo con una acción secundaria.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
        </powers>
        <elementalUse>
            <en>With Psi 1, you can use this power elementally (by spending 1 VP) to perform simple psychokinetic
                actions on items of negligible weight. You might turn an unlocked doorknob and push a door open, lift a
                pen, cause the drapes to flutter, etc.\n

                At Psi 5, you gain a bit more control. You can lift a pen and
                write a crude message, cause plants to sway in a particular direction as a means of directing someone
                that way, or even cause a negligible item to hover and fly for up to 1 turn per Psi rating.\n

                At Psi 9, you can lift objects up to 5 kg elementally.\n
            </en>
            <es>Con Psi 1, puedes utilizar este poder de forma elemental (gastando 1 PV) para realizar acciones
                psicoquinéticas sencillas sobre objetos con un peso insignificante. Por ejemplo, podrías girar el pomo
                de una puerta y abrirla, alzar una pluma, provocar el revoloteo de unas cortinas, etc.\n

                Con Psi 5, obtienes un poco más de control. Puedes alzar una pluma y escribir con ella un mensaje
                sencillo, hacer que las plantas se inclinen en una dirección para orientar a alguien, o conseguir que un
                objeto ligero flote y vuele durante 1 turno por cada punto de Psi.\n

                Con Psi 9, puedes levantar objetos de hasta 5 kg de forma elemental.\n
            </es>
        </elementalUse>
        <random>
            <classification>combat</classification>
        </random>
    </path>

    <path>
        <id>omen</id>
        <name>
            <en>Omen</en>
            <es>Augurio</es>
        </name>
        <occultismType>psi</occultismType>
        <powers>
            <power>
                <id>shadowsGoneBy</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Shadows Gone By</en>
                    <es>Sombras Que Fueron</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>Attuning yourself to an object, you may “read” it to get a vision of the past surrounding it.
                    </en>
                    <es>Al sintonizarte con un objeto, puedes «leerlo» para obtener una visión de su pasado.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>6</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en>2 VP</en>
                    <es>2 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>intuition</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Hard+ (see Impact)
                    </en>
                    <es>Difícil+ (mira Impacto).
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You call forth an event from the past surrounding an object you are touching. You can attempt to
                        see a particular time (“what happened 8 hours ago”) or a particular event (“when Dame Julia was
                        murdered”).\n

                        You experience the event as a flashback that lasts around 30 seconds with sight, sound, and the
                        general feelings of those around the object. The GM will establish the total Resistance based on
                        the distance in the past and the significance of the event. Seeing a year or two in the past
                        might be Hard; going back to the Second Republic could easily be considered Miraculous. The
                        significance of the event can also affect the Resistance: the less significant it is, the harder
                        it is to call forth. If the object was used to murder someone during the event, it wouldn’t
                        increase the Resistance, but if the object was only present during the murder, it could increase
                        Resistance by one step or more. Someone just passing by the object and not notably interacting
                        with it could increase Resistance by two or more steps.
                    </en>
                    <es>Revives un evento del pasado relacionado con un objeto que estés tocando. Puedes intentar ver un
                        momento concreto («lo que ocurrió hace ocho horas») o un evento concreto («cuando la dama Julia
                        fue asesinada»). Contemplas el evento como un flashback que dura unos 30 segundos e incluye
                        imagen, sonido y sentimientos generales de quienes estaban cerca del objeto. \n

                        El DJ determinará la Resistencia total según el tiempo que haya pasado y la importancia del
                        evento. Por ejemplo, rememorar un evento de hace un año o dos podría ser Difícil, mientras que
                        ver un suceso de la Segunda República se considera Milagroso. La importancia del evento también
                        puede afectar a la Resistencia: cuanto menos importante, más costará revivirlo. Si el objeto fue
                        utilizado para asesinar a alguien durante el evento, la Resistencia no aumenta, pero, si el
                        objeto solo estaba presente durante el asesinato, podría incrementarse en un nivel o más. Si
                        alguien pasa junto a un objeto sin interaccionar con él, es posible que la Resistencia aumente
                        en dos niveles o más.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>shadowsToCome</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Shadows to Come</en>
                    <es>Sombras por Venir</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>Turning your inner sight from the present, you may now gaze into the future and its possible
                        outcomes.
                    </en>
                    <es>Tu visión interna se abstrae del presente y mira hacia el futuro y las posibilidades por venir.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>7</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en>2 VP</en>
                    <es>2 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>intuition</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Hard+ (see Impact)
                    </en>
                    <es>Difícil+ (mira Impacto).
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You can see, hear, and feel a scene from the future surrounding a person, place, or object. This
                        can be a specific event or time (such as “the coronation of Bishop Vigaro de Aragorn” or “in
                        this courtyard at midnight three days hence”). The Resistance is decided by the GM based on the
                        distance into the future. An hour or two may only be Hard Resistance, while a week might be
                        Tough or worse. You see a potential future but a very likely one. The glimpse of the future
                        lasts for 30 seconds
                    </en>
                    <es>Ves, oyes y sientes una escena del futuro relacionada con una persona, lugar u objeto. Esta
                        escena puede ser un evento o momento concreto (como «la coronación del obispo Vigaro de Aragón»
                        o «en este patio a medianoche dentro de tres días»). El DJ decide la Resistencia según lo
                        distante que esté en el futuro. Una hora o dos podría ser Difícil, mientras que una semana sería
                        como mínimo Ardua. Durante 30 segundos ves un futuro potencial, aunque muy probable.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>voiceFromThePast</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Voice from the Past</en>
                    <es>Voz del Pasado</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>You can channel the personality of someone long dead to speak through you and impart
                        information.
                    </en>
                    <es>Puedes canalizar la personalidad de alguien muerto desde hace mucho para que ofrezca
                        información.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>8</psiLevel>
                <time>presentTense</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>2 VP</en>
                    <es>2 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>presence</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Demanding (Severe if the subject is unwilling)
                    </en>
                    <es>Exigente (Tenaz si la persona no quiere)
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You summon and channel a deceased entity to have it answer one question through your
                        voice. You may ask one additional question per 2 VP spent.

                        Some courts in the Known Worlds have allowed use of this power to take testimony from the dead
                        in murder cases. The Church maintains, however, that these are not ghosts; allegedly, this power
                        calls forth demons or the psychic’s own twisted mind.
                    </en>
                    <es>Invocas y canalizas una entidad fallecida para que responda a una pregunta con tu voz. Por cada
                        2 PV que gastes, responderá a una pregunta adicional.

                        Algunas cortes de los Mundos Conocidos han permitido usar este poder para que las personas
                        asesinadas puedan testificar. No obstante, la Iglesia sostiene que no son fantasmas, sino
                        demonios o la propia mente retorcida del psíquico.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id>oracle</id>
                <name>
                    <en>Oracle</en>
                    <es>Oráculo</es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>By entering a trance-like state, you can give cryptic foretellings of the future.
                    </en>
                    <es>Quedas en un estado de trance que te permite ofrecer predicciones crípticas.
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>9</psiLevel>
                <time>presentTense</time>
                <cost>
                    <en>3 VP</en>
                    <es>3 PV</es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic>presence</characteristic>
                <skill>focus</skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>Severe
                    </en>
                    <es>Tenaz
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>You may answer one question posed to you during your trance, and you will be given an answer. As
                        with the answers of the ancient Urth Delphic Oracle, the psychic’s answer is always in the form
                        of metaphors, riddles, or abstractions, and it must be interpreted. The GM is the voice of the
                        omen, and they should use the power to reveal a possible future for the troupe.
                    </en>
                    <es>Debes responder a una pregunta que te hagan durante tu trance con la respuesta que recibas. Como
                        ocurría con el antiguo oráculo de Delfos, en Urth, la respuesta del psíquico siempre está llena
                        de metáforas, enigmas o abstracciones, y debe ser interpretada. El DJ es la voz del augurio, y
                        debería usar el poder para revelar un futuro posible de la compañía.
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
        </powers>
        <random>
            <classification></classification>
        </random>
    </path>

    <path>
        <id></id>
        <name>
            <en></en>
            <es></es>
        </name>
        <occultismType>psi</occultismType>
        <powers>
            <power>
                <id></id>
                <name>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>1</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic></characteristic>
                <skill></skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id></id>
                <name>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>1</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic></characteristic>
                <skill></skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id></id>
                <name>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>1</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic></characteristic>
                <skill></skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
            <power>
                <id></id>
                <name>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </name>
                <description>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </description>
                <psiLevel>1</psiLevel>
                <time></time>
                <cost>
                    <en></en>
                    <es></es>
                </cost>
                <characteristic></characteristic>
                <skill></skill>
                <resistance>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </resistance>
                <impact>
                    <en>
                    </en>
                    <es>
                    </es>
                </impact>
            </power>
        </powers>
        <elementalUse>
            <en>
            </en>
            <es>
            </es>
        </elementalUse>
        <random>
            <classification></classification>
        </random>
    </path>
</occultism>