<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<callings>
    <calling>
        <id>collectionsAgent</id>
        <name>
            <en>Collections Agent</en>
            <es>Agente de Cobros</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>In the fullness of time every debt comes due, and those debts that are not paid in coin are paid in blood. Not quite foot soldiers and not quite bounty hunters, Collections Agents are tasked with ensuring debtors pay what they owe and lenders receive their due.
                When a payment is missed or a loan defaulted upon, Collections Agents are dispatched to correct the situation. Collections Agents use a combination of intimidation and force when plying their trade, securing wealth, possessions, and land from those who refuse to pay their debts. When Collections Agents encounter an unfortunate unable to pay and without property to repossess, they are expected to deliver a sound beating at best or drag the offender to the nearest debtor's prison at worst. Fit young Reeves often spend their apprenticeship working in collections teams, while those with a penchant for violence or a lack of self control remain in the profession as they advance in rank.
                Their patron saints are the Debtor's Martyr and Z'Dar the Grim.</en>
            <es>Con el paso del tiempo toda deuda vence, y las deudas que no se pagan en moneda se pagan en sangre. Ni del todo soldados de a pie ni del todo cazarrecompensas, los Agentes de Cobros tienen la misión de asegurarse de que los deudores paguen lo que deben y los prestamistas reciban lo suyo.
                Cuando se incumple un pago o se impaga un préstamo, se despacha a los Agentes de Cobros para corregir la situación. Los Agentes de Cobros emplean una combinación de intimidación y fuerza al ejercer su oficio, asegurando riqueza, posesiones y tierras de quienes se niegan a pagar sus deudas. Cuando un Agente de Cobros se topa con un desdichado incapaz de pagar y sin propiedades que embargar, se espera que le propine una buena paliza en el mejor de los casos o que arrastre al infractor a la prisión de deudores más cercana en el peor. Los jóvenes Magistrados en forma suelen pasar su aprendizaje trabajando en equipos de cobros, mientras que aquellos con inclinación por la violencia o falta de autocontrol permanecen en la profesión a medida que ascienden de rango.
                Sus santos patronos son el Mártir del Deudor y Z'Dar el Adusto.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>militaryWeapons</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>combatArmor</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>dexterity</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>strength</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>endurance</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>presence</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>aimWhereItHurts</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>armedToTheTeeth</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>bloodHound</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>diplomaticImmunity</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>intruder</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>resilient</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>ruthless</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>fight</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>intrusion</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>sneak</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>melee</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>shoot</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>vigor</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <restrictions>
            <upbringings>
                <upbringing>merchant</upbringing>
            </upbringings>
        </restrictions>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>COMBAT</preference>
                <preference>GUILD</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
    <calling>
        <id>fixer</id>
        <name>
            <en>Fixer</en>
            <es>Mediador</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Standing at the crux of what you need and who you need to know is the Fixer. An agent who opens the doors of commerce and politics, a Fixer is more than a go-between for the powerful and those seeking power. Fixers, with their web of contacts and network of resources, are facilitators without peer, always ready to get their client what they want, be it intelligence, illicit goods, or a face-to-face meeting with the grandees of the Known Worlds. Fixers are personable, quick witted, and work tirelessly to maintain and grow the network of influence that makes their profession possible. Most importantly, a Fixer is always available to pull the correct strings at a moment's notice and shrewd enough to know how best to pull them, be it with a bribe, a favor, flattery, or an implied threat.
                Their patron saints are Eloy the Lobbyist and Cha'iruhq the Acquisitor.</en>
            <es>En la encrucijada entre lo que necesitas y a quién necesitas conocer se encuentra el Mediador. Un agente que abre las puertas del comercio y la política, un Mediador es más que un intermediario para los poderosos y para quienes buscan poder. Los Mediadores, con su red de contactos y su entramado de recursos, son facilitadores sin igual, siempre dispuestos a conseguir a su cliente lo que desea, ya sea información, bienes ilícitos o una reunión cara a cara con los magnates de los Mundos Conocidos. Los Mediadores son afables, perspicaces y trabajan sin descanso para mantener y ampliar la red de influencia que hace posible su profesión. Y lo más importante, un Mediador siempre está disponible para mover los hilos adecuados en un instante y es lo bastante astuto como para saber cuál es la mejor forma de moverlos, ya sea con un soborno, un favor, la adulación o una amenaza velada.
                Sus santos patronos son Eloy el Cabildero y Cha'iruhq la Adquisidora.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>streetwise</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>factionLore</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>cathedralCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>courtCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>wits</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>will</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>presence</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>allAccessPass</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>friendsInHighPlaces</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>schmooze</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>underworldContacts</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>academia</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>arts</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>empathy</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>charm</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>knavery</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>observe</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>sneak</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <restrictions>
            <upbringings>
                <upbringing>merchant</upbringing>
            </upbringings>
        </restrictions>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>SOCIAL</preference>
                <preference>TRADE</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
    <calling>
        <id>factotum</id>
        <name>
            <en>Factotum</en>
            <es>Factótum</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Though the nature of the Merchant League all but demands each guilder specialize and excel in a narrow set of skills, there are those who would rather be a student of all trades than a master of one. Factotums are those who dabble in a wide array of studies and make a living sliding into and out of a broad array of professions. Researching cases in an advocate's office one day, crawling through the guts of a terraforming engine the next, preparing to transcribe texts in a Church library the week after, Factotums are broadly employed in the Merchant League fleet where their versatility and adaptable nature find them switching from one shipboard role to the next throughout the day. When a Factotum does secure long-term employment it is often as a jack-of-all-trades for a client who respects their versatility.
                Factotums come from a variety of backgrounds, though all are broadly educated. Most Factotums spend their apprenticeships serving aboard League escorts and freighters learning the rudiments of the trades of every commissioned merchant aboard, though commanding officers are careful to ensure a Factotum's education remains rudimentary lest closely guarded trade secrets are imparted and weaken a guild monopoly. Other factotums are former students of guild and seminary academies who never settled on a field of study, drifting from one foundational course to the next until their tuition or patron's patience ran out. In an era that values specialists, Factotums have carved out a unique niche for themselves that serves them and their clients well.
                Their patron saints are Chalim the Able and Gretak Raxikar.</en>
            <es>Aunque la naturaleza de la Liga Mercantil casi exige que cada gremial se especialice y destaque en un estrecho conjunto de habilidades, hay quienes prefieren ser estudiantes de todos los oficios antes que maestros de uno solo. Los Factótums son quienes se aventuran en una amplia variedad de estudios y se ganan la vida entrando y saliendo de un extenso abanico de profesiones. Investigando casos en el despacho de un abogado un día, arrastrándose por las entrañas de un motor de terraformación al siguiente, preparándose para transcribir textos en una biblioteca de la Iglesia a la semana siguiente, los Factótums son ampliamente empleados en la flota de la Liga Mercantil, donde su versatilidad y su naturaleza adaptable hacen que pasen de un cometido a bordo a otro a lo largo del día. Cuando un Factótum consigue un empleo de larga duración, suele ser como hombre orquesta para un cliente que respeta su versatilidad.
                Los Factótums proceden de orígenes muy diversos, aunque todos poseen una educación amplia. La mayoría de los Factótums pasan su aprendizaje sirviendo a bordo de escoltas y cargueros de la Liga, aprendiendo los rudimentos de los oficios de cada mercader con comisión a bordo, si bien los oficiales al mando se cuidan de que la formación de un Factótum siga siendo rudimentaria, no sea que se transmitan secretos comerciales celosamente guardados y se debilite un monopolio gremial. Otros factótums son antiguos estudiantes de academias gremiales y seminarios que nunca se decidieron por un campo de estudio, derivando de un curso introductorio al siguiente hasta que se les agotó la matrícula o la paciencia de su mecenas. En una era que valora a los especialistas, los Factótums se han labrado un nicho único que les sirve bien a ellos y a sus clientes.
                Sus santos patronos son Chalim el Capaz y Gretak Raxikar.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <group>meleeWeapons</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <group>rangedWeapon</group>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <group>knowledgeLore</group>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>shipboardOperations</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>strength</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>dexterity</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>endurance</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>wits</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>perception</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>will</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>intuition</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>beginnersLuck</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>gambler</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>gearhead</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>ingenious</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>learningFromMistakes</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>polymath</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>riskTaker</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>techSavvy</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>academia</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>charm</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>interface</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>pilot</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>intrusion</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>fight</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>melee</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>shoot</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>remedy</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>techRedemption</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <restrictions>
            <upbringings>
                <upbringing>merchant</upbringing>
                <upbringing>priest</upbringing>
                <upbringing>yeoman</upbringing>
            </upbringings>
        </restrictions>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>TECHNICAL</preference>
                <preference>KNOWLEDGE</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
    <calling>
        <id>negotiator</id>
        <name>
            <en>Negotiator</en>
            <es>Negociador</es>
        </name>
        <description>
            <en>Negotiators are more than fast talking traders of honeyed words – they're duelists who use turns of phrase, implied threats, and rhetorical logic where others use a sword. The right word from the lips of a Negotiator can prevent a war, free a hostage, or oversee a trade that leaves all parties involved feeling they got the better end of the deal. Merchants rely on Negotiators to hammer out favorable terms in the contracts they sign with their clients, while nobles rely on them to arrange for the transfer of hostages between rival houses and secure favorable dowries to cement political marriages. The Universal Church's office of the Syneculla makes extensive use of Negotiators to defend and expand the secular rights of the ordained. Every client counts on their Negotiator to look after their best interests, and to convince others that their best interests are for the greater benefit of all. The alternative, as any Negotiator will evenly tell you, is to invite chaos.
                Their patron saints are Delijaal the Peacemaker and Lomax of the Chit.</en>
            <es>Los Negociadores son más que comerciantes de labia veloz y palabras melosas: son duelistas que usan los giros de la frase, las amenazas veladas y la lógica retórica donde otros usan la espada. La palabra justa salida de los labios de un Negociador puede evitar una guerra, liberar a un rehén o supervisar un trato que deja a todas las partes implicadas con la sensación de haber salido ganando. Los mercaderes recurren a los Negociadores para perfilar términos favorables en los contratos que firman con sus clientes, mientras que los nobles confían en ellos para gestionar el intercambio de rehenes entre casas rivales y asegurar dotes ventajosas que cimenten matrimonios políticos. La oficina del Syneculla de la Iglesia Universal hace amplio uso de los Negociadores para defender y ampliar los derechos seculares de los ordenados. Todo cliente cuenta con su Negociador para que vele por sus mejores intereses y convenza a los demás de que esos intereses redundan en el mayor beneficio de todos. La alternativa, como te dirá sin inmutarse cualquier Negociador, es invitar al caos.
                Sus santos patronos son Delijaal el Pacificador y Lomax del Vale.</es>
        </description>
        <capabilities>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>cathedralCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                    <capability>
                        <id>courtCustoms</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
            <capabilitiesOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <capability>
                        <id>factionLore</id>
                    </capability>
                </options>
            </capabilitiesOption>
        </capabilities>
        <characteristics>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>presence</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>will</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
            <characteristicBonusOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>wits</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                    <characteristic>
                        <id>intuition</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </characteristic>
                </options>
            </characteristicBonusOptions>
        </characteristics>
        <perks>
            <perkOptions>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <perk>
                        <id>accord</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>bureaucracy</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>embargo</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>diplomaticImmunity</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>imperious</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>pettyCash</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>playingTheGame</id>
                    </perk>
                    <perk>
                        <id>respectable</id>
                    </perk>
                </options>
                <openPerks>true</openPerks>
            </perkOptions>
        </perks>
        <skills>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>academia</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>charm</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>empathy</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                    <skill>
                        <id>focus</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>impress</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>interface</id>
                        <bonus>1</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
            <skillBonusOption>
                <total>1</total>
                <options>
                    <skill>
                        <id>knavery</id>
                        <bonus>2</bonus>
                    </skill>
                </options>
            </skillBonusOption>
        </skills>
        <restrictions>
            <factions>
                <faction>reeves</faction>
            </factions>
        </restrictions>
        <random>
            <probabilityMultiplier>RARE</probabilityMultiplier>
            <recommendedPreferences>
                <preference>SOCIAL</preference>
                <preference>GUILD</preference>
            </recommendedPreferences>
        </random>
    </calling>
</callings>

